<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
<title>Owen Tyme - Science Fiction and Fantasy Author</title>
<link>https://owentyme.us/</link>
<description>Owen Tyme writes science fiction and fantasy novels</description>
<category>Indie Author</category>
<copyright>Copyright 2025, Owen Tyme</copyright>
<lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 07:09:26 -0500</lastBuildDate>
<pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 07:09:26 -0500</pubDate>
<atom:link href="https://owentyme.us/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<item>
<title>Jigsaw City</title>
<link>https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/index.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/index.html</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 15:30:29 -0500</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<h1 id="series">Jigsaw City</h1>
<p><em>Jigsaw City</em> is a sequel series to <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/../wizards-scion/index.html">The Wizard’s Scion</a>, centered
around the life of Levi’s daughter, Nicole Jacobs, and her quest to
reunite the pieces of a magical city that was broken up millions of
years before she was born.</p>
<h2 id="plan">Release Plan</h2>
<p>Currently, the plan is to release this series a chapter at a time, on
<a href="https://www.royalroad.com">Royal Road</a>. When each volume has
been fully posted, they’ll be published both in Ebook and print
editions, in many online stores.</p>
<p>For the time being, the Ebooks <em>will not</em> be published via
Amazon, because they have exclusivity requirements.</p>
<p>Eventually, the versions in their original, online locations will
become short teasers, perhaps six chapters long.</p>
<p>The first chapter of volume one was published on Saturday, March 8,
2025. The rest will follow a chapter at a time, every Tuesday, Thursday
and Saturday.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="jigsaw-city"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/jigsaw-city.html">Jigsaw City</a></h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/../../images/badges/status-webnovel.svg" /> <img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/../../images/badges/schedule-tues-thurs-sat.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/jigsaw-city.html"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/../../images/Cover-JigsawCity.jpg" /></a><br />
<a href="https://books2read.com/JigsawCity">Store Links</a><br />
<a href="https://www.royalroad.com/fiction/108234/jigsaw-city">Read on
Royal Road</a></span> Nicole Jacobs is given a small, hexagonal coin for
her twentieth birthday, but during analysis of the strange, magic
trinket, she accidentally copies the magic item’s base spell into her
mind, where it rapidly expands beyond the original design, slowly
consuming her mind from the inside! Nicole reluctantly seeks out the
maker of the item, hoping to find a cure before it’s too late to save
her sanity.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="fey-fighters">Fey Fighters</h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/../../images/badges/status-done.svg" /></p>
<blockquote>
<p><span class="book-cover"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/../../images/Cover-FeyFighters.jpg" /></span> Forced to give up
their original home due to the constant incursions of humans, the
fairies long ago retreated from Earth to an out of the way corner of the
galaxy to live in peace, but when humans accidentally stumble upon them,
they aren’t happy and this time, they’re not willing to give up their
home without fighting until either the extinction of themselves or the
human invaders!</p>
<p>However, nothing’s as it seems, because the humans only arrived as
the result of a series of accidents, having been forced to make an
unsafe faster-than-light jump through space to the nearest potentially
habitable system, which resulted in the destruction of their star ship!
With nowhere else to go and faced with the hostile locals, they
staunchly defend themselves against constant fey assault.</p>
<p>Two soldiers on opposite sides, pixie Commander Stargazer Candleflash
and human Sergeant Edwin Harris, find their fates forever entwined,
first by hatred and the desire for revenge, but then, as they crash
together in a rainforest full of danger, they’re forced to work
together, just to survive.</p>
<p>Will these two rivals, who have every reason to hate each other,
survive or will their bickering get them killed? Is it possible a
fragile peace can be forged from their own personal cease-fire or will
the doomsday weapons held by both sides be released, ensuring the
destruction of everyone?</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
</blockquote>
<p>On a distant planet tucked away in a barely explored region of the
galaxy, war breaks out between humans that are forced to land there and
the fairies that left Earth during World War II, because the human race
had become too violent to share a planet with.</p>
<p><em>Fey Fighters</em> introduces true fairies to the setting, who
will also be seen in volume three, where they’ll play a vital role
providing exposition and will also play a part in <em>The Great
Purpose</em>, due to the linked nature of both demons and fey.</p>
<h2 id="collector-of-kurg">Collector of Kurg</h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/../../images/badges/status-planning.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/../../images/Cover-CollectorOfKurg.jpg" /></span> Having accepted
the fact that the City of Kurg is permanently bonded to her mind and
soul, Nicole seeks to collect all of the missing fragments of the
magical city, both on and off her home planet, soon coming into conflict
with rogue trolls, ancient monsters, aliens, gun-slinging snails,
monkeys with crossbows, giants and even fairies.</p>
<p><em>Collector of Kurg</em> will bring Nicole’s adopted mother,
Cha’da, into the series, as Nicole encounters her sailing the wilds of
the world’s ocean.</p>
<p>This one is likely to be a collection of short, but connected tales,
rather than a novel, with each planet visited being its own story.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="baba-yaga-lives">Baba Yaga Lives!</h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/../../images/badges/status-planning.svg" /></p>
<blockquote>
<p><span class="book-cover"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/../../images/Cover-BabaYagaLives.jpg" /></span> Baba Yaga started
out wanting to live a little longer, falling to the temptations of
necromancy to extend her life, gaining a mere decade or so with each
human soul she consumes. Eventually growing dissatisfied with such
meager fare, she turns her attention to consuming the souls of magical
creatures for the extra power they contain and her body slowly becomes
more magic than flesh, transforming her into a thaumavore.</p>
<p>However, with the rise of science and magical creatures of the galaxy
growing wise to her tricks, there’s precious little for her to eat. She
can’t afford the hefty price enchanted items sell for on the galactic
market and finds their weak magic unsatisfying, anyway, but she does
come across a rare and undervalued curio: one of the hexagonal coins
that make up the magical City of Kurg, an object so impossibly filled
with magic, it has the power to resist her every attempt to consume
it!</p>
<p>She seeks to unlock the hidden power of the coin, hoping to extend
her life until the end of time with its nearly limitless magic.
Unfortunately for her, not just anyone can access the magic of Kurg,
something only a city administrator can do. Learning this fact by
touching the mind of the coin, she seeks a conversation with Nicole, the
only available administrator.</p>
<p>Nicole’s quest to collect the missing pieces of the City of Kurg
brings her right to Baba Yaga’s doorstep and since their goals are
nothing alike and totally at odds, the meeting devolves into a magical
duel! War for ownership of the city follows, eventually leading to a
sprawling battle inside the legendary chicken-legged hut of Baba Yaga, a
magically-folded, mind-bending space that would give even M. C. Escher a
headache!</p>
<p>Will Nicole overcome the crone’s superior, time-tested spells or will
Nicole, as an extension of Kurg, become Baba Yaga’s living larder?</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
</blockquote>
<p><em>Baba Yaga Lives!</em> will bring legendary magical creatures to
the city, including Levi’s old familiar, Inorath, because Nicole will
need information on Baba Yaga and many of them are even older than the
ancient witch.</p>
<h2 id="the-great-purpose">The Great Purpose</h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/../../images/badges/status-planning.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/../../images/Cover-TheGreatPurpose.jpg" /></span> In this volume of
<em>Jigsaw City</em>, the true purpose of Kurg is revealed: it was
designed as a powerful weapon for fighting a war that’s as old as the
universe. The Life Giver is back, in need of Nicole and her city’s
power, while the Life Giver’s nemesis, The Void, attempts to invade the
Milky Way, to begin consuming everyone and everything there.</p>
<p><em>The Great Purpose</em> will bring the Hunter from <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/../ashen-blades/index.html">Ashen Blades</a> to the city, to
combat a nearly limitless supply of demons, because they’ve finally
succeeded in opening a stable portal to the galaxy. It will also involve
the Hunter’s arch-nemesis, Vogerath, since the portal was his plan.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="lost-city">Lost City</h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/../../images/badges/status-planning.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/../../images/Cover-LostCity.jpg" /></span> Nicole and the Hunter
may have won the battle with demon-kind and The Void, but the cost is
extremely high: Nicole sacrifices her life for the success of their
crazy suicide mission and the Hunter finally reaches the limits of both
her demon and witch powers, with disastrous consequences.</p>
<p>Nicole’s body is restored by automatic functions of the City of Kurg,
but her mind is shattered by re-birth as its living avatar. Lost,
confused and alone, will Nicole ever return to her home and those she
loves or will she forever wander a dying, parallel universe, seeking a
home she can’t even remember?</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the Hunter is also lost and alone, but in immediate peril.
She emerges from the spatial tear formed by The Void’s final kick at
thirty-thousand feet above a strange, alien planet, with absolutely no
idea where she is. Even worse, she’s lost the power of the elements and
been left to her own devices, totally unable to fly. Will she survive
the fall and find some way to get home or will she remain forever
lost?</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="the-memory-hunt">The Memory Hunt</h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/../../images/badges/status-planning.svg" /></p>
<p>Nicole discovers the fact that her memories were backed up by the
city before she was killed, but unlike her body, it was unable to fully
restore her mind.</p>
<p>Seeking to regain a greater measure of humanity, Nicole goes back to
collecting lost fragments of the City of Kurg, mostly for the sake of
restoring her memories.</p>
<p>This takes her beyond the galaxy she knows, to far-flung areas of the
multiverse, because when the ancient city broke up, parts of it left the
galaxy, while some few traveled to parallel universes.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Jigsaw City</title>
<link>https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/jigsaw-city.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/jigsaw-city.html</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 15:30:25 -0500</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<h1 id="jigsaw-city">Jigsaw City</h1>
<blockquote>
<p><span class="book-cover"><a
href="https://books2read.com/JigsawCity"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/../../images/Cover-JigsawCity.jpg" /></a><br />
<a href="https://books2read.com/JigsawCity">Store Links</a><br />
<a href="https://www.royalroad.com/fiction/108234/jigsaw-city">Read on
Royal Road</a></span> Nicole Jacobs is twenty years old and unsure what
direction to take in life, because the opportunities available to her
are too numerous and no one job fits all of her talents, but she passes
the time doing research on dragons. To that end, she hatches a dragon
egg, but in the midst of the harrowing work required, she dreams of the
ancient, magical City of Kurg, which yearns to be whole.</p>
<p>She soon discovers, based on a chance encounter with a small magic
item she’d been analyzing, that her mind has been dangerously
intertwined with that of the city, which spreads through her brain like
a disease, slowly taking over. At first, she’s able to keep it under
control by suppressing magic within her own head, but over time, it
begins breaking past the road blocks she desperately erects in its path
as it inches toward total control.</p>
<p>Seeking a cure, she’s forced to research the ancient city, while the
clock ticks down on her sanity and ultimately, her life. Meeting the
strange, stone men that made the city, the Ulkun, she finds they have
few answers for her, but suggest that if she locates the Architect of
Kurg, one of their own kind, he might be of some help. Unfortunately,
due to the fact he was trapped inside a small segment of the sealed city
for millions of years, alone, he’s quite insane, unhelpful and worse,
eventually becomes hostile, forming a plan for galactic domination.</p>
<p>Instead, Nicole seeks the Life Giver, the mysterious being that
created the Ulkun and ordered the construction of Kurg, while collecting
pieces of the city, in the hopes of attracting their attention.</p>
<p>Will Nicole find a cure, freeing herself from the clutches of Kurg,
or will she lose control of her own mind, taken over by the magic city?
Will the Architect succeed at replacing everyone in the galaxy with
obedient, magically-animated drones with no will of their own or will
Nicole stop him?</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="release-schedule-and-details">Release Schedule and Details</h2>
<p>The first chapter was published on Saturday, March 8, 2025 and
further chapters will come one at a time, every Tuesday, Thursday and
Saturday.</p>
<h2 id="looking-for-more">Looking For More?</h2>
<p><span class="book-cover"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/index.html#fey-fighters"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/../../images/Cover-FeyFighters.jpg" /></a></span></p>
<p>The next book in <a href="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/index.html">Jigsaw City</a> is <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/index.html#fey-fighters">Fey Fighters</a>.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Starwitch</title>
<link>https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/starwitch.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/starwitch.html</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 15:21:52 -0500</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<h1 id="starwitch">Starwitch</h1>
<p>Starwitch is volume one of <a href="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/index.html">The Book of
Newts</a>, which follows the adventures and trials of a witch that owns
a magical book detailing many secrets of science, engineering, magic and
most particularly, space travel.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><span class="book-cover"><a
href="https://books2read.com/TymeStarwitch"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/../../images/Cover-Starwitch.jpg" /></a><br />
<a href="https://books2read.com/TymeStarwitch">Store Links</a><br />
<a
href="https://www.royalroad.com/fiction/102509/the-book-of-newts">Read
on Royal Road</a></span> Home, safety, and a place to belong – they seem
so easy to find, at least for everyone but Amelia Blackwell and her
sisters, who run from accusations of witchcraft at every turn.</p>
<p>It started so simply, with a book. No one might have predicted that a
book apparently filled with pictures of newts might lead to so much
trouble, but <em>The Book of Newts</em> is no ordinary volume on
taxonomic detail of amphibians. The magic book reveals its true nature
only to Amelia, at the age of ten, teaching her mathematics, science and
engineering – subjects she would not otherwise have been exposed to.</p>
<p>Ironically, she and her sisters are accused of witchcraft for having
built a horseless carriage, because to the ignorant villagers, there’s
no difference between magic and science. They settle in a new land, only
to find the same breed of persecution.</p>
<p>In an unusual ray of hope, they’re told of a distant kingdom that
openly accepts witches, but shortly after they settle there, the light
at the end of the tunnel turns out to be an awful house fire surrounding
their gilded cage: they’re drafted into the local military, because
their new nation uses witches as living weapons.</p>
<p>The sisters accept the idea that peace will never be found on the
ground. Looking to the stars, Amelia builds a space vessel powered by
magic and steam, to carry them to a brighter future, hopefully without
the strife that’s always followed them.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, the people of the stars have their own worries: an
ancient, undead pirate queen, who consumes the souls of powerful witches
to extend her own life. The Dead Queen takes Amelia’s sisters and leaves
the magically-weak engineer to die, all as a sick form of sport.</p>
<p>Will Amelia survive long enough to overcome this greatest of all
threats and rescue her sisters, or will they become fuel to feed the
waning magic of a woman that should have been dead centuries before?</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="https://owentyme.itch.io/starwitch">The Book of Newts #1:
Starwitch by Owen Tyme</a></p>
<p><em>Starwitch</em> centers on the life of Amelia Blackwell, the
youngest of a trio of sisters and witches, who start out living on a
moon orbiting a gas giant and eventually use magic to launch themselves
into space, to escape persecution for their witchcraft, as well as some
troublesome political events.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, they eventually encounter the Dead Queen, an ancient
undead pirate witch that consumes the magic and lives of other witches,
to extend her own existence.</p>
<p>The series begins with Amelia aboard her magic light sail ship,
<em>Starwitch</em>, just a few days after it was badly damaged and her
sisters were kidnapped by the Dead Queen, left with only enough
resources to follow the far larger ship.</p>
<p>That’s an intentional and cruel choice by the Dead Queen, because
Amelia’s magic is deemed too weak to consume. The Queen instead left
Amelia for dead in the hopes of some sport.</p>
<p>Amelia has just enough resources to attack, but not enough to limp to
safety, so unless she gets back either the mythril spell-core of her
ship or at least one of her sisters, she’s a dead woman.</p>
<h2 id="release-schedule-and-details">Release Schedule and Details</h2>
<p>The first chapter was published to <a
href="https://www.royalroad.com">Royal Road</a> on Monday, January 6,
2025 and further chapters will come one at a time, every Monday,
Wednesday and Friday.</p>
<p>On June 27, 2025, Starwitch will be available for purchase in a
variety of online stores, both in Ebook and in print. Please note, the
Ebook <em>will not</em> be available from Amazon until the series is
complete and removed from Royal Road.</p>
<h2 id="looking-for-more">Looking For More?</h2>
<p><span class="book-cover"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/legacy-of-newts.html"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/../../images/Cover-LegacyOfNewts.jpg" /></a></span></p>
<p>The next volume in <a href="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/index.html">The Book of Newts</a> is <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/legacy-of-newts.html">Legacy of Newts</a>.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Sky Children</title>
<link>https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/index.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/index.html</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 15:21:48 -0500</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<h1 id="series">Sky Children</h1>
<p><em>Sky Children</em> is a prequel series to <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/../wizards-scion/index.html">The Wizard’s Scion</a>, centered on
the adventures of Zechariah Jacobs, an electrical engineer that crashes
on a supposedly unexplored planet, which happens to give him magical
powers via a mysterious virus, making him a wizard.</p>
<h2 id="sky-children"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/sky-children.html">Sky Children</a></h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/../../images/badges/status-published.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/sky-children.html"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/../../images/Cover-SkyChildren.jpg" /></a></span> The series starts
with volume one, titled <a href="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/sky-children.html">Sky Children</a>, in
which Zechariah crash lands on an ‘unexplored’ planet, only to uncover a
terrifying government conspiracy to hide the existence of the Mind Fire
virus, which grants magic powers to those infected by it.</p>
<p>Even worse, the intelligence people will do just about anything to
hide the truth, including nuking their own colonies, from orbit. In
point of fact, such a tragedy once happened on Zechariah’s new home
world, using the guise of a quarantine to corral the witnesses, for
extermination.</p>
<p>Learning these facts, Zechariah vows to do something about it and
eventually, when he and his friends find a buried star ship, they force
that revelation on the entire empire he left behind, because the people
have a right to know.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="wrath-of-the-sky"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/wrath-of-the-sky.html">Wrath of the
Sky</a></h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/../../images/badges/status-published.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/wrath-of-the-sky.html"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/../../images/Cover-WrathOfTheSky.jpg" /></a></span> Volume two is
<a href="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/wrath-of-the-sky.html">Wrath of the Sky</a>.</p>
<p>As a result of revealing the existence of the Mind Fire virus to the
public, Zechariah’s new home world catches the eye of his old nation,
the Northwestern Empire, which sends an invasion fleet of ships,
thousands strong, to wipe out the evidence so the truth can be
erased.</p>
<p>Zechariah and his people work to gain allies and build defenses of
all kinds, ranging from the scientific to the magical.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="wild-sky">Wild Sky</h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/../../images/badges/status-rewrite.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/../../images/Cover-WildSky.jpg" /></span> Volume three is Wild
Sky.</p>
<p>Having settled things with the Northwestern Empire, Zechariah is
contacted by the the new empress, who was on his side of the recent
conflict. With a civil war looming, due to Zechariah’s actions, he and
his people step up to aid her.</p>
<p>However, as things grow more dire, Zechariah seeks to achieve ever
greater feats and falls to the temptation of using rage magic, a
dangerously addictive, but incredibly powerful form of magic. Caught up
in the addiction, he begins to destroy his entire life by hiding it from
everyone.</p>
<p>This book is unpublished.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Book of Newts</title>
<link>https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/index.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/index.html</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 15:16:48 -0500</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<h1 id="the-book-of-newts">The Book of Newts</h1>
<p><span class="book-cover"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/../../images/Cover-TheBookOfNewts.jpg" /></span> <em>The Book of
Newts</em> is a remarkable volume. Paradoxically, while The Book is
exceptionally magical, the information contained within is largely not.
It details every wonder of engineering, science and astronomy that’s
been discovered by its past owners, but this information is only visible
to those with a genetic talent for mathematics. To all others, it
appears to be a thick volume describing every variation of newt that has
ever existed, in meticulous detail, complete with hand-drawn
illustrations.</p>
<p>The Book yearns for new knowledge. To that end, it inspires those
that own it to ever greater heights, taking them to the stars and
beyond, to reach their greatest potential, but nothing in life comes
without a price and its owners rarely foresee the balance coming
due.</p>
<p>While The Book is sometimes willing to wait, it’s never satisfied and
will always drive its owner to the next horizon, to the next discovery,
that it might grow a little thicker under the weight of new
knowledge.</p>
<p>Throughout history, The Book has been the driving factor behind many
things, particularly the colonization of the stars and terraforming of
many worlds, all to serve its insatiable hunger for more.</p>
<p>Witches and wizards are drawn to the magic of The Book, but woe
betide any that choose to stand in the way of the inevitable march of
progress, because The Book has a will of its own and a terrible power to
subtly bend its owner’s mind, leaving them just as hungry for more
knowledge.</p>
<p>At first, The Book seems like a blessing, but it might also be termed
a curse. That’s because it always seems to draw unwanted attention, but
never to itself, and its owners become magnets for trouble of all sorts.
Accusations of witchcraft often follow them, because science beyond the
wildest imaginings of the common man may as well be magic.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="plan">Release Plan</h2>
<p>Currently, the plan is to release this series in a manner that
resembles television, with episodes consisting of up to four chapters
and seasons roughly ten episodes long. Each novel of the series will be
analogous to a season of a show.</p>
<p>Each season will be initially free to read on <a
href="https://www.royalroad.com">Royal Road</a>. When each season has
been fully posted, it will be published both in Ebook and print
editions. Eventually, the story will be stubbed (become a handful of
sample chapters that drive visitors to stores) on Royal Road, but not
until the series is complete.</p>
<p>None of the novels will be published as Ebooks on Amazon until the
series has been stubbed, due to exclusivity requirements. The Ebooks
will, however, be available in other online stores.</p>
<p>The first three seasons are done and the first chapter was published
on Monday, January 6, 2025. The rest has been following a chapter at a
time, every Monday, Wednesday and Friday.</p>
<p>Volume one, titled <a href="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/index.html#starwitch">Starwitch</a>, will be
available to purchase on June 27, 2025, as both an Ebook and in
print.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="starwitch"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/starwitch.html">Starwitch</a></h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/../../images/badges/status-published.svg" /><br />
<img src="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/../../images/badges/status-webnovel.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/starwitch.html"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/../../images/Cover-Starwitch.jpg" /></a><br />
<a href="https://books2read.com/TymeStarwitch">Store Links</a><br />
<a
href="https://www.royalroad.com/fiction/102509/the-book-of-newts">Read
on Royal Road</a></span></p>
<p>Volume one is <a href="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/starwitch.html">Starwitch</a>.</p>
<p>The series begins with Amelia Blackwell, a witch with little magic
talent, but a keen mind, described by the previous owner of The Book as
a prodigy. She accepts ownership of it with curiosity and a voracious
desire to read all she can.</p>
<p>The Book soon gets Amelia and her two older sisters into all sorts of
trouble, because the depth of knowledge Amelia demonstrates breeds
jealousy, strife and accusations of witchcraft for all the wrong
reasons.</p>
<p>Eventually, Amelia constructs a vessel she names <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/starwitch.html">Starwitch</a> and the sisters flee the moon they
once called home, to seek peace among the stars. Instead, they find even
greater strife and a hostile pirate queen that consumes the souls of
witches to extend her own life.</p>
<p>Volume one, titled <a href="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/index.html#starwitch">Starwitch</a>, will be
available to purchase on June 27, 2025, as both an Ebook and in
print.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="legacy-of-newts">Legacy of Newts</h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/../../images/badges/status-webnovel.svg" /><br />
<img src="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/../../images/badges/schedule-m-w-f.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/legacy-of-newts.html"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/../../images/Cover-LegacyOfNewts.jpg" /></a><br />
<a
href="https://www.royalroad.com/fiction/102509/the-book-of-newts/chapter/2192542/chapter-1-touching-the-sun-season-2-legacy-of">Read
on Royal Road</a></span> Volume two, <em>Legacy of Newts</em>, deals
with the consequences of events from volume one.</p>
<p>Having defeated the pirate queen to rescue her sisters from serving
as fuel for that ancient witch’s life, Amelia flees, but the undead
witch is furious beyond measure and gives chase, determined to run them
down. Even better, the sisters stole her spell-core, leaving the giant,
granite ship dead in space.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, that only buys them a little time and the Dead Queen
soon has her ship moving again, to chase after them.</p>
<p>Marta is in bad shape, her soul still linked to that of the Queen,
while Iris grows ever closer to death, due to the magic used to
interrogate her.</p>
<p>The sisters seek assistance from everyone they’ve befriended at every
port along the way, while Amelia plots to gather an armada at the end of
the road.</p>
<p>The pirates are soon up in arms, because the Dead Queen’s lieutenants
smell blood in the water. Things are poised to go from bad to worse,
because sometimes the devil you know is better than the one waiting to
fill the power vacuum…</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="the-next-horizon">The Next Horizon</h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/../../images/badges/status-done.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/../../images/Cover-TheNextHorizon.jpg" /></span> Volume three is
<em>The Next Horizon</em>. It will provide greater detail on The Book
and the way it interacts with Amelia.</p>
<p>After settling the matter of the pirates, Amelia and her sisters
enjoy a short time of peace, until she decides to go home, to Cakana.
She wants to reconnect with a man she fell in love with, but The Book
has other plans.</p>
<p>When the conflict comes to a head, The Book refuses to cooperate and
takes back the gifts it’s been quietly imparting. As a result, Amelia
discovers it has been bolstering her exceptional ability with
mathematics and piloting. Left to her own devices, the task of
navigating space becomes potentially deadly, because she can no longer
perform the required calculations in her head, or on paper.</p>
<p>Without that, the journey home will takes nine months, rather than
mere days, practically ensuring the man she loves will have moved
on.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, a duo of deadly witches they left behind, and hoped never
to see again, have since learned to fly through space and wish for a
helping of revenge. Worse, they’re welcomed into space by one of the
last pirates, who also has a bone to pick with Amelia and her
sisters.</p>
<p>Will Amelia survive long enough to reignite the love she once had, or
will she be forced to give up her greatest desire, just to satisfy The
Book?</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="witchhome">Witchhome</h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/../../images/badges/status-planning.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/../../images/Cover-Witchhome.jpg" /></span> In volume four, titled
<em>Witchhome</em>, Amelia will arrive at a compromise with The Book
they can both live with.</p>
<p>Amelia builds a magic, flying city to serve as a home and place of
refuge while she explores space, a compromise between her desire to put
down roots and the ceaseless need of The Book to go further.</p>
<p>Her massive construction project soon draws attention from all over
the system. Witches and wizards flock to her cause, drawn like moths to
a flame by the potential. Dwarves first supply the resources required,
but soon see the allure of the project and lend a helping hand, that
they might find the same kind of refuge from prejudice.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, it isn’t all good news, and the locals of Amelia’s
home moon soon rise up, to burn the “cursed city of witches” to the
ground. To avoid all-out war, Amelia’s people are forced to launch
early, before even basic safety measures can be tested.</p>
<p>Will Amelia manage to have her cake and eat it too, or will all the
troubles she seeks to escape finally catch up to her? Will her people be
able to finish their work along the way, or will <em>Witchhome</em> come
apart before they can reach assistance?</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="beyond-the-horizon">Beyond the Horizon</h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/../../images/badges/status-planning.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/../../images/Cover-BeyondTheHorizon.jpg" /></span> In volume five,
<em>Beyond the Horizon</em>, Amelia will finally begin exploring, as the
means to find a place her people can call home.</p>
<p>Amelia flies her magic city full of brave witches, wizards and
dwarves to unexplored space, for the sake of establishing a colony where
they won’t be persecuted for their magical talents.</p>
<p>They carry with them seeds and animals of every kind, with which to
make a new home, plus a population composed of every walk of life,
including every skill that might be required both along the way and at
their destination.</p>
<p>The journey is perilous beyond measure, with strange encounters
aplenty, including lethal space weather, aliens with unfathomable
motives and a hazardous encounter with a black hole.</p>
<p>Will Amelia’s people be able to find a world suitable for
terraforming and the construction of a new home, or will their journey
end with disaster, for over-reaching their grasp? Will Amelia be able to
resist naming that planet Witchworld?</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Wizard’s Scion</title>
<link>https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/index.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/index.html</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 05:18:10 -0500</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<h1 id="the-wizards-scion">The Wizard’s Scion</h1>
<p>This series follows the life of a great and powerful wizard’s son,
Levi Jacobs, as he grows from a teenage boy with almost no control over
his magic to a wizard of great power and reputation, that masters the
secrets of time travel.</p>
<p>The setting of this five volume series began as a relatively hard
science background, with only one big rubber science addition: some
faster than light technology that’s used for travel and communication.
Magic was largely unknown to everyone except the space pirate, until an
electrical engineer crash-landed on an “unexplored” planet that bore a
strange virus that gave him the powers of a wizard.</p>
<p>That electrical engineer who became a wizard was Levi’s father,
Zechariah. Zechariah is both directly and indirectly responsible for the
invention of many magi-tech devices, which mix magic and technology
together, using electricity to produce powerful spells beyond what any
wizard could do alone, leading to a setting in which wizards fly through
space in star ships that have the usual rubber science sci-fi bells and
whistles, including force fields and teleporters, as well as guns that
shoot magic spells.</p>
<h2 id="complete-series">The Complete Series</h2>
<blockquote>
<p><span class="book-cover"><a
href="https://books2read.com/TheWizardsScion"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/../../images/Cover-TheWizardsScion.jpg" /></a><br />
<a href="https://books2read.com/TheWizardsScion">Store Links</a></span>
Levi Jacobs always dreamed of being more like his father, the greatest
wizard in the world, but had no real understanding of what it would be
like if he got his wish.</p>
<p>Follow Levi’s journey from bumbling teen to a great hero, while the
young wizard learns to master magical powers that are initially
completely beyond him and barely under his control.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, he’s forced to deal with a psychotic telepathic
swordswoman, an army of trolls, retrieving stolen star ships, a war with
forgotten monsters that no one believes in anymore, alien space pirates,
time travelers, a telepath that collects minds like shiny stones, a
necromancer that leads a ship of murderous goblins, rock monsters from
the invisible moon, a master of manipulating probability and a perilous
trip through the Greek Underworld, to have a conversation with The
Fates.</p>
<p>But it gets worse: Levi’s family always seems to be caught in the
middle of every disaster that comes along, leaving him with no choice
but to deal with it.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This omnibus edition includes all five volumes in the series (see
below).</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<p><a href="https://owentyme.itch.io/the-wizards-scion">The Wizard’s
Scion by Owen Tyme</a></p>
<h2 id="troll-song"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/troll-song.html">Troll Song</a></h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/../../images/badges/status-published.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/troll-song.html"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/../../images/Cover-TrollSong.jpeg" /></a></span> The series starts
with <a href="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/troll-song.html">Troll Song</a>, which tells the tale of
an unusual young troll girl that catches Levi’s eye and who’s very
important to his story, named Lyra.</p>
<p>She learns early on, by comparing her life to that of a dwarf, her
family are neither healthy nor particularly good and seeks to escape
them. <a href="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/troll-song.html">Troll Song</a> covers her journey to
freedom.</p>
<p><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/troll-song.html">Troll Song</a> begins fully immersed in the
fantasy elements of the series, then slows begins introducing sci-fi
elements, before fully immersing the reader in a mixture of the two,
after a large forward skip in time, because the main characters got
frozen in ice for two-thousand years.</p>
<p>That’s when Lyra meets Levi, who frees her from the ice and becomes
her first modern friend.</p>
<p>Here’s an audio sample of this novel:</p>
<div>
<p>Your browser doesn’t seem to support playing MP3 files.</p>
</div>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="forgotten-legends"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/forgotten-legends.html">Forgotten
Legends</a></h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/../../images/badges/status-published.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/forgotten-legends.html"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/../../images/Cover-ForgottenLegends.jpeg" /></a></span> The second
volume, <a href="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/forgotten-legends.html">Forgotten Legends</a>, covers
the events of a war between humanity and the ancient, forgotten gods and
legendary creatures they once believed in, but have forgotten, due to
the rise of science.</p>
<p>Humanity inadvertently angers the legends by disturbing their last
refuge in reality and the Four Horsemen of the Apocalypse lead the
charge to strike back, with Levi and his family caught up in the
middle.</p>
<p>Unknown to Levi and his family, the fates have been manipulating
events to to bring about the death of his mother, Rachel, who has the
power to see the future and guide her own fate, which they see as an
affront.</p>
<p>Levi makes a new ally in this novel, in the form of the monster from
under his childhood bed, a creature of darkness named Inorath, which
used to give him nightmares and taunt him in the dark. They bond as
wizard and familiar, that they might work together to end the war.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="the-third-wish"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/the-third-wish.html">The Third
Wish</a></h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/../../images/badges/status-published.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/the-third-wish.html"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/../../images/Cover-TheThirdWish.jpg" /></a></span> In the third
volume, <a href="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/the-third-wish.html">The Third Wish</a>, old enemies of
the Jacobs family come together to seek revenge, using a time machine,
with the intent to re-write history to suit themselves.</p>
<p>Worst of all, the time travelers bring Lyra’s evil sisters back to
life by cloning them, reigniting the conflict from <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/troll-song.html">Troll Song</a>.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Levi deals with an angry, alien pirate, Captain Dandy, a
sentient dandelion with a sense of pride so strong that every tiny
slight becomes a mountain of offense. He’s angry over the way Levi’s
parents have treated him for two decades and seeks revenge by destroying
their world and their son.</p>
<p>As the conflict begins in earnest, Levi is shocked to meet his future
self, who gives him the chance to follow the time travelers into the
past. This is the first hint that Levi will eventually unravel the
mysteries of temporal magic.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="dark-moon"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/dark-moon.html">Dark Moon</a></h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/../../images/badges/status-published.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/dark-moon.html"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/../../images/Cover-DarkMoon.jpg" /></a></span> Volume four is <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/dark-moon.html">Dark Moon</a>.</p>
<p>Unknown to everyone, Levi’s home world has had an moon all along, but
it was hidden away in another dimension. When it begins to manifest in
the mundane universe, it becomes a portent of great trial and burdensome
times.</p>
<p>Levi, however, is distracted by the death of some the crew of his
star ship and eventually tracks down the necromancer responsible for
their deaths and faces the witch in a magical duel.</p>
<p>He soon discovers the reasons for her actions aren’t cut and dried
evil and even admits he might have done the same thing.</p>
<p>As their duel comes to an end, the full moon rises and monsters fall
from it, splashing down in the ocean around them. They’re soon caught in
a battle for their lives, fighting back to back, relying on each other
to survive, despite how much they hate each other.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="the-inverted-glass"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/the-inverted-glass.html">The
Inverted Glass</a></h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/../../images/badges/status-published.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/the-inverted-glass.html"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/../../images/Cover-TheInvertedGlass.jpg" /></a></span> The fifth
and final volume is <a href="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/the-inverted-glass.html">The Inverted
Glass</a>.</p>
<p>In this story, Levi’s wife and daughter die in childbirth and he’s
left reeling from one awful event to the next, unable to cope,
eventually losing just about everything he cares for.</p>
<p>In the depths of his deepest sorrow, he’s reminded he once saw
himself travel through time. He begins studying that most dangerous and
powerful of all magics, determined to regain everything he’s lost, but
when he does gain that power, he’s forced to confront the very fates
themselves, that he might gain permission to make the changes he
desires.</p>
<p>However, just getting an opportunity to speak with them is next to
impossible, because their cave is at the end of a perilous journey
through the Greek Underworld and the realm of Hades, who’s famed for his
dislike of living intruders.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Legacy of Newts</title>
<link>https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/legacy-of-newts.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/legacy-of-newts.html</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 17:00:12 -0500</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<h1 id="legacy-of-newts">Legacy of Newts</h1>
<p><em>Legacy of Newts</em> is volume two of <a href="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/index.html">The
Book of Newts</a>, which follows the adventures and trials of a witch
that owns a magical book detailing many secrets of science, engineering,
magic and most particularly, space travel.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><span class="book-cover"><a
href="https://www.royalroad.com/fiction/102509/the-book-of-newts/chapter/2192542/chapter-1-touching-the-sun-season-2-legacy-of"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/../../images/Cover-LegacyOfNewts.jpg" /></a><br />
<a
href="https://www.royalroad.com/fiction/102509/the-book-of-newts/chapter/2192542/chapter-1-touching-the-sun-season-2-legacy-of">Read
on Royal Road</a></span> Amelia Blackwell’s sisters were kidnapped by an
ancient, undead witch known as the Dead Queen and Amelia attacked the
pirate’s mountain-sized star ship out of pure desperation. She never
expected to actually rescue her sisters, let alone defeat the pirate on
her own ship. Nonetheless, she pulled it off, got her sisters back and
left the pirate queen’s ship helplessly listing through space.</p>
<p>Unfortunately for the Blackwell sisters, that’s only the beginning,
because the Dead Queen survived and she’s absolutely livid. She seeks
revenge, because the sisters made her look weak, forcing her to save
face by killing them, lest her own lieutenants kill her.</p>
<p>Worse, the soul of Amelia’s oldest sister, Marta, has been
intertwined with that of the Dead Queen, who was using necromancy to
consume it, to extend her own life. That leaves them both stumbling
through the thoughts of the other, each looking for some advantage in a
battle of soul vs. soul, winner take all – even though Marta has no
desire to steal the undead witch’s soul.</p>
<p>Iris, the middle sister, fares no better. Since she managed to resist
interrogation by torture, the Dead Queen instead forced an addiction on
her, offering hits of a pleasure spell for information, until she broke.
Her brain chemistry is so screwed up, she’s unlikely to survive
withdrawal.</p>
<p>The Queen soon gets her ship moving and the chase is on! Will the
Blackwells find refuge and allies to fight off the Queen’s massive ship,
or will everyone shun them, unwilling to take the risk of standing up to
the queen of the pirates, who terrifies even the rulers of the star
system?</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
</blockquote>
<p><em>Legacy of Newts</em> covers the aftermath of the climax of <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/starwitch.html">Starwitch</a>, in which Amelia forcefully boarded
the Dead Queen’s ship, rescued her sisters, disabled the ship, then flew
off.</p>
<h2 id="looking-for-more">Looking For More?</h2>
<p><span class="book-cover"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/index.html#the-next-horizon"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/../../images/Cover-TheNextHorizon.jpg" /></a></span></p>
<p>The next volume in <a href="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/index.html">The Book of Newts</a> is <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/index.html#the-next-horizon">The Next Horizon</a>.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ideas</title>
<link>https://owentyme.us/books/ideas.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/books/ideas.html</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 06:00:34 -0500</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<h1 id="ideas">Ideas</h1>
<p>This page is a sort of catch-all bin of ideas for novels I may write
in the future.</p>
<h2 id="demon-blood">Demon Blood</h2>
<p>This would be a spin-off of <a href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/index.html">Ashen
Blades</a> centered around the life of James Simmons. He’s a fairy, like
his mother, Lara, but he appears totally normal until probably the age
of fifteen or sixteen, at which point he’s badly injured and needs an
emergency transfusion.</p>
<p>The only person available at the time with a compatible blood type is
the Hunter/Artemis Watson, a half-demon. She donates her blood and it
activates all of the young man’s dormant powers.</p>
<p>He also turns out to be rather good at demon extermination, able to
force demons to transform, with a touch. He uses this power to forcibly
turn demons into weapons, which he uses to kill others. Best of all: his
power eventually fully drains his weapons of all magic, permanently
killing them.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, he becomes a half-demon, and the demons now seek to
use him in their plots to conquer the world, very similar to
Artemis.</p>
<h2 id="second-star-working-title">Second Star (Working Title)</h2>
<p>Second star is a re-telling of Peter Pan from the perspective of
Captain Hook, with Peter cast as the villain. The setting would be based
on a twisting of many fairy tales and I’m planning to go for a gritty,
realistic feeling to the story, despite the fact it will be satire. I
may go with a Noir-style of writing, with guns and tech from the 1940’s,
though there will certainly also be magic and magical creatures.</p>
<p>Hook would be a police captain with a personal grudge against Pan,
who’s the king-pin of the local drug trade, which is based on Pixie
Dust, a hallucinogen literally produced by shaking enslaved pixies.</p>
<p>True to the original story, Pan cut Hook’s hand off and fed it to an
alligator. That led to Hook being re-assigned from narcotics to vice for
a time, which will lead to Pan nicknaming him “Captain Hooker”, just to
tick him off.</p>
<p>The novel will begin with Tinkerbell turning herself in to the
police, but she refuses to tell her story to anyone other than Hook.
That gets Hook back on the case and he sees things through from there.
Tink and Pan used to be equal partners, but when Tink grew a conscience
and wanted to stop selling drugs to kids, Pan imprisoned her, then
captured more pixies, to force them to produce more Pixie Dust.</p>
<p>I have lots of ideas for incorporating elements of the original
story, as well as many other fairy tales.</p>
<p>For example, Neverland is Pan’s nightclub, a speakeasy that the cops
can’t find, because only fairies and those high on Pixie Dust can see
the way. The directions “second star to the right and straight on till
morning” confuse them, because Second Star and Morning are street names,
but they’re parallel to each other and never cross. Only in the fairy
realm do they actually share an intersection and that’s where Neverland
is. Neverland got it’s name through Pan saying, “The cops won’t never
find this land!”</p>
<p>I plan to include Pinocchio as one of Pan’s street-level pushers.
Hook uses him as a reliable source of information, because every time
the puppet lies, his nose grows. Unfortunately, Hook doesn’t know that
Pan uses the puppet to feed Hook false information.</p>
<p>Pixie Dust has a powerful side-effect on children, slowing or even
stopping the aging process. Pan, for example, is hundreds of years old,
yet he’s never fully grown out of childish habits.</p>
<p>Pan’s gang, the Lost Boys, are nearly as old as Pan. Every one of
them is a nasty piece of work, fully of the cynicism of the streets, yet
childish as can be. Those that appear to be teens, like Pan, are the
most dangerous. They’re intellectually adults, but emotionally volatile
and prone to murderous behavior. Those that appear younger are less
trouble, but due to the way they haven’t mentally developed, they’re
effectively slaves to the older members of the gang and don’t even know
it.</p>
<p>The Lost Boys are constantly looking for new recruits and they easily
find them when children disagree with their parents, usually over petty
matters, like bedtime.</p>
<p>However, they’re just as likely to sell them drugs, instead.</p>
<p>The climax of the novel will involve Pan blowing a handful of Pixie
Dust in Hook’s face, while growling, “Could you just lighten up, for
once?”</p>
<p>At that point, Hook will wander the streets, high as a kite, but
he’ll finally see how the streets bend and cross, at least in his mind.
Before he begins to come down, he gathers men from the station, in full
tactical gear, and leads them in a raid on Neverland, leading to a grand
melee with the Lost Boys, while Hook confronts Pan.</p>
<h2 id="thorn-of-the-rose-working-title">Thorn of the Rose (Working
Title)</h2>
<p>Sandra Blake loses her parents to an unexpected attack by a
mysterious assassin. Her mother’s final words, “Don’t let it end like
this” have a chilling effect on her life and Sandra transforms herself,
both body and soul, becoming an incredibly skilled and dangerous
woman.</p>
<p>After years of intense training, she enters the seedy underworld of
modern society, exchanging stolen jewels for information on the man that
killed her parents.</p>
<p>Her uncle, Daniel Malachi, seeks to bring her in from the field, to
make her part of the Imperial Intelligence Core, which her oversees.</p>
<p>Naturally, they come into conflict, but Sandra goes through Malachi’s
men like a lawn mower cuts grass. Nonetheless, when her uncle speaks to
her, her resolve weakens and she agrees to work for him as a spy.</p>
<p>Will Sandra stay on task and do as she’s told, or will she go
off-book to find the man she wants to punish?</p>
<p>This would be a rewrite of a novel I started in college (20 years
ago), which I lacked the skill to finish at the time.</p>
<p>Some of my favorite qualities of Sandra were the contradiction
between how much pain she feels and how capable she is, as well as her
tendency to defeat high tech security gadgets with simple kitchen
utensils. Add her total lack of understanding of computer software (she
had a rudimentary understanding of networking cables, however, in the
sense of knowing what they were and how to cut them) and she was quite
fun to write.</p>
<p>This more modern variation would take place in the Northwestern
Empire, likely during the time skip at the end of <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/the-inverted-glass.html">The Inverted Glass</a>.
Daniel Malachi was originally seen in <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/sky-children.html">Sky Children</a> and also appeared
in <a href="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/the-third-wish.html">The Third Wish</a>, after
which he became the new spy master for the Empress of the Northwestern
Empire.</p>
<p>While Malachi is a wizard, he doesn’t flaunt that ability and not
even Sandra will know, at least until she needs to.</p>
<p>The original version of the novel opened with Sandra pretending to be
a student at a clandestine school for spies on the first day of class,
while their teacher was absent. This turned out to be ploy to avoid
teaching, a task she never wanted, but since she’s pregnant, she’s been
removed from active duty and relegated to teaching.</p>
<p>She teaches the Unconventional Tactics class, mostly by telling them
her life story, which serves as an excellent example of doing everything
the wrong way, while getting excellent results.</p>
<p>I’m not sure how much of the old novel will be used, but there’s
plenty to build on and the experience of writing Sandra has had a lot of
influence over the writer I’ve become.</p>
<h2 id="the-renegade-god">The Renegade God</h2>
<p>In a humorous setting in which gods gain power through human belief,
one particular goddess has a tendency to step on the toes of other gods,
by gaining aspects that are uncomfortably close to their areas of
influence, ultimately usurping them, by stealing their worshipers.</p>
<p>For this, she’s cursed by the other gods, yet she isn’t dissuaded,
continually visiting the mortal realm to spreads new religions based on
her. She usually reaches by falling from the sky, because shes initially
pushed off the cloud that serves as the home of the gods, but over time,
she will choose to dive off.</p>
<p>Every time she lands, she leaves a crater and loses her memories, not
realizing she’s a god. She usually also loses her divine regalia along
the way, including a pair of ruby high heels that bear a measure of her
power. It normally takes her years to recover her memories, long after
she’s spread a new religion.</p>
<p>She eventually finds her pet goose, which goes out looking for her
whenever she leaves the abode of the gods, and rides it home. Every
visit home leads to a new trial for her crimes against the other gods,
for which she’s cast down again, starting the process anew.</p>
<p>This is likely to read like a series of intertwined tales, but it
won’t be a collection of short stories, because the narrative will be
tighter than that.</p>
<p>By the end of the novel, the renegade will become the chief of the
gods, simply because she has more worshipers than any other.</p>
<p>I’ll play up the renegade’s curse for comedic effect and treat her
relationship with the other gods as another source of comedy.</p>
<h2 id="marie-antionette"><sup>Marie</sup>/<sub>Antoinette</sub></h2>
<p>This piece will be strictly a sci-fi novel and will also stand alone.
It’s possible I could turn it into a series, but I currently have no
plans for that.</p>
<p>Marie is an undercover cop with multiple personalities. The two
personalities are Marie and <em>The Other Girl</em>, an old name Marie
chose for her second personality as a child. She has a talent for
computers and even a little knowledge of hacking, a skill she
occasionally uses on the job.</p>
<p>She’s part of an operation investigating the owner of a
biotech/cybernetics company, because he’s rumored to be a mobster.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, Marie is discovered and the mobster uses her for an
awful experiment. As it turns out, he’s been experimenting with
technology to wipe a person’s mind, followed by rewriting their brain
with a new personality.</p>
<p>The villain didn’t count on Marie having two personalities, however,
and the technology doesn’t quite work. <em>The Other Girl</em> rises to
the surface, because her purpose is to protect Marie. <em>The Other
Girl</em> is erased and replaced with a new personality named
Antoinette, a little joke from the villain.</p>
<p>Antoinette becomes the villain’s personal assassin, who puts a lot of
cybernetic hardware in Marie’s body.</p>
<p>Marie eventually comes to the surface again, but finds herself
overwhelmed with pain she can’t handle, subsiding again. This is because
the villain took no care for her comfort when he installed the
cybernetics, leaving her pain center constantly stimulated.</p>
<p>As an artificial personality that has more in common with a computer
program, Antoinette doesn’t have an emotional reaction to pain. She does
register new pain as the means to track injury, but she disregards
existing pain.</p>
<p>Marie eventually regains consciousness again, but takes a more
hands-off approach, observing from her own subconscious, while
Antoinette kills for the villain.</p>
<p>Eventually, the facility that radios her with new instructions is
assaulted by the military, led by Marie’s boyfriend. He’s a special ops
soldier and quite eager to find Marie, even though the police department
has marked her down as missing, presumed dead (the villain may have
altered a corpse to look like her, or may have cloned her, just to throw
the police off).</p>
<p>Everyone responsible for giving Antoinette orders is killed or
captured and their equipment is destroyed, something that Antoinette
becomes aware of, due to the network connection going down. She has some
understanding of what happened, but has no orders regarding loss of
contact and doesn’t know what to do.</p>
<p>Antoinette is left with very simple orders: “Stay out of sight and
kill any witnesses until further notice.”</p>
<p>She hides in a slum for a prolonged period of time, until a boy spots
her and approaches. She’s about to kill him, but receives new orders,
despite the fact she knows the transmitter at the other end has shut
down. She’s ordered to never kill children.</p>
<p>Marie is the source of all further orders and she’s managed to hack
the computer hardware connected to her brain, using it to give
Antoinette some new orders, though she can’t yet countermand existing
orders. She can only add fresh orders.</p>
<p>The second order Marie gives causes Antoinette to completely shut
down her radio transceiver.</p>
<p>From that point on, Marie will use Antoinette as a tool to achieve
her own goals. She’ll initially try to contact her friends over the
phone, but can’t get Antoinette to speak, due to prior direct orders
from the villain. Instead, she quietly looks for proof she can deliver
to the police, without being seen, acting in a manner similar to a
vigilante. She delivers trussed-up mobsters to the police station, along
with evidence to ensure a conviction, while she seeks dirt on the man at
the top.</p>
<p>The novel will have a dual plot structure, but both threads will
follow the main character. Marie will be the subject of one thread,
starting with the childhood trauma that gave her a second personality,
while the other will follow Antoinette, starting with her first field
test. I won’t make it clear that they’re the same person until about
halfway through the book.</p>
<h2 id="p.r.o.t.e.g.e.">P.R.O.T.E.G.E.</h2>
<p>The Protective Recon Operations Taskforce for Extraterrestrial
Gathering and Elimination is a multinational organization setup to
protect the human race from aliens, though they’ll deal with most
anything that’s a threat to humanity, including supernatural threats.
They’re a black-budget, paramilitary organization that doesn’t
officially exist.</p>
<p>PROTEGE keeps everything a secret and keeps humanity in the dark
regarding aliens, supposedly for their own good. However, they have a
rather bad reputation for being overly anti-alien, to the point of
needless hatred, but that may or may not be true.</p>
<p>The story will follow a new recruit, a shape-shifting alien in
disguise. His job is to find the real truth behind the disappearance of
a peaceful group sent to study humans. If PROTEGE is responsible, then
it may lead to war. If the alien infiltrator discovers the fact PROTEGE
has multinational support, then the aliens may declare war on all of
humanity.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, he’s constantly distracted from his primary mission by
PROTEGE-assigned missions, which keep him in the field, rather than at
home base. Over time, he emotionally bonds with the human members of his
team and begins to lose himself in the role.</p>
<p>I haven’t yet decided on an outcome for the story, but in my mind,
PROTEGE has always been evil, run by humans that hate and victimize
aliens, yet their field operatives are not quite so evil, which may be
what makes it so hard to find the truth.</p>
<p>Perhaps the alien’s goal will transition to replacing the current
leaders of the organization, rather than starting a war, which could
lead to a long struggle over the course of a series. I could easily see
the climax as a confrontation between the alien and the people at the
top. If he wins, then he’ll replace them and subtly change the
organization’s mission. However, since that was basically what happened
in the <em>Supergirl</em> TV show, I think I’ll take a different
approach.</p>
<p>More likely, I would seek a middle-ground path, in which he confronts
them honestly and tells them of the threat they’ve become to themselves.
That will lead to a fight between those that see things his way and the
rest, who refuse to change.</p>
<p>In North America, PROTEGE operates out of an underground bunker
hidden beneath a kitty litter factory, which serves as a cover story.
Officially, the operatives that work out of the base are employed by the
factory.</p>
<p>Naturally, this novel/series would use a lot of conspiracy theory
stuff, most of which would be played up for comedic effect.</p>
<h2 id="nothing-left-to-chance">Nothing Left to Chance</h2>
<p>Death is a job passed from one mortal to another over the centuries,
a job with a great many perks, including immortality, but the catch is a
doozy: death is always scrambling collect to dark souls that need to be
controlled. Worse, if Death fails and the dark souls are left unchecked,
the world will come to an end.</p>
<p>Each Death begins normal enough, then comes to an end the usual way,
but a long-standing bargain between humanity and the grim reaper entails
an ancient ritual challenge: if a mortal can beat Death in any game,
they gain immortality. The trouble is, Death can’t be beat, unless Death
chooses to lose.</p>
<p>This has happened before and will inevitably happen again, because
mortals were never meant to live forever, and sooner or later, the
Reaper always tires of Reaping. It may take ten-thousand years or just
ten, but all good things must come to an end.</p>
<p>The downside is that this usually involves all of the collected dark
souls being released, which forces the new guy to pick up the slack,
lest the world end.</p>
<p>Dragons, monsters, creatures of legend, even dark and forgotten gods
with an ax to grind – they all have to be captured and contained.</p>
<p>Fortunately, the previous Reaper always sticks around for a while,
usually in the form of a talking skull, because someone has to teach the
new guy.</p>
<p>Each book in this series would bear only a tenuous connection to the
rest and each volume in it can stand alone, with no need to write them
in any particular order. Each would focus on a particular Reaper, though
it’s possible I may find I like any given character and give them an
extra volume or two.</p>
<p>The common elements of the series from Reaper to Reaper will consist
of each facing terrible calamities in order to save the world, requiring
some choice of vessel to contain the dark souls, which determines the
powers they manifest. However, all Reapers share the power to manipulate
and travel through time, which is essential for them to ferry the souls
of the living to the afterlife.</p>
<p>In addition, they also have to choose something or someone to serve
as their immortal companion. This is traditionally a horse, but there
are a great many options available, including motorcycles, cars, other
people, etc.</p>
<h3 id="chance-on-a-gamble">Chance on a Gamble</h3>
<p>A young man that lives by gambling dies in a motorcycle accident and
meets Death, who offers him a rare chance at immortality, through a game
of poker.</p>
<p>He wins and becomes Death, while Death crumbles to just a powerless
skull, which had been serving as the containment vessel.</p>
<p>After several women reject the opportunity, the young man chooses his
motorcycle as his companion, which becomes imbued with life, then
chooses to use his deck of cards and his dice to contain the souls. The
powers he gains are extremely strong, but subject to random chance and
tend to burn out after a while.</p>
<p>To challenge myself, I’ll come up with random effects to attach to
the cards of a deck or the roll of the dice, then I’ll randomly choose
as required to determine which power he gets at any given time. During
the climax, he’ll finally find a way to stack the deck ahead of time,
rather than shuffling.</p>
<p>The more souls he gathers, the less time it will take for individual
cards to recharge after use.</p>
<h3 id="gunslingers-chance">Gunslinger’s Chance</h3>
<p>The Reaper of the Old West era began as an outlaw gunfighter, who
challenged death to a fast-draw contest of the sort favored in
Westerns.</p>
<p>Death loses on purpose and the outlaw finally finds out about the
fine print of the arrangement, forced to defend a world he hates,
because the alternative is worse.</p>
<p>The outlaw chooses his horse as his companion and his pistol as the
vessel. Each soul he captures will give him a unique power his bullets
can manifest, based on the defeated monster.</p>
<h3 id="chance-for-a-soldier">Chance for a Soldier</h3>
<p>A soldier that died on the battlefield during World War II defeats
Death in a bare knuckle bar fight.</p>
<p>The soldier chooses his best friend as a companion and their fists
serve to contain the souls. Each soul they collect will give them
greater durability and physical strength, eventually becoming like
super-heroes.</p>
<p>Together, they fight both dark souls and Nazis, but as they begin to
sway the outcome of the war, Reapers from other eras appear, to stop
them, lest they destroy the foundations of reality, by altering what was
meant to be.</p>
<p>The Reapers brawl like no battle that came before and whole cities
are decimated by the fighting.</p>
<h3 id="shinigami-of-chance">Shinigami of Chance</h3>
<p>At one point, the reaper was a Japanese samurai, who used his sword
as the the vessel and his armor as his companion. His armor became
imbued with life and the samurai came to think of it as being possessed
by a helpful, yet very clever fox yokai.</p>
<p>This one chose to think of himself as a shinigami, rather than a
Reaper.</p>
<h3 id="a-chance-insight">A Chance Insight</h3>
<p>The Reaper of this novel is a con artist that makes her living as a
fake psychic or medium.</p>
<p>She chooses her crystal ball as both the containment vessel and her
companion. She gains the rather unreliable power to gaze into the
future, while her crystal ball starts talking and can shape shift at her
command. She often uses it in the form of blunt instruments (like a
mace), since it’s made of extremely durable and heavy quartz.</p>
<h3 id="a-magical-chance">A Magical Chance</h3>
<p>The Reaper from the 1960’s is the lovely assistant of a magician and
also his wife.</p>
<p>She chooses her husband as her companion and makes magic itself the
containment vessel, transforming it into more than a mere slight-of-hand
trick.</p>
<h3 id="the-last-chance">The Last Chance</h3>
<p>The previous Reaper chooses poorly and gives his power to a man that
wishes to watch the world crumble, after losing his wife.</p>
<p>The Earth comes closer than ever to destruction as dark and evil
energy fills the world, fracturing both time and space, bringing Reapers
from the past into the present, each of them fighting to hold off the
catastrophe, despite the fact they lack the power, since they’re only
echoes of what was.</p>
<p>The new Reaper falls for one of the female Reapers of the past and
she convinces him to care, through small acts of romance. He chooses her
as his companion and together, they fight to end the catastrophe, but
the world may be too far-gone to save.</p>
<p>In a strange twist, the Reaper chooses his bond with his new wife as
his containment vessel and the attraction between them manifests as a
force that may be just enough to seal the cracks in space/time, or
possibly not…</p>
<p>This volume would likely be the last, a chance to bring the other
main characters together for one big adventure, while elements of the
real world, the future and even alternate histories mingle together.</p>
]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ashen Blades</title>
<link>https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/index.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/index.html</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 09:20:16 -0500</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<h1 id="ashen-blades">Ashen Blades</h1>
<p>This series centers around the life of a half-demon girl that calls
herself the Hunter, whose parents were murdered by demons. Joining her
crusade against demon-kind are the Ashen Blades, also known as the Order
of Ash and Smoke, an organization of demon hunters.</p>
<p>The Hunter starts out with demon powers only, but eventually learns
that she’s also a witch, because her mother was a witch before she
became a demon. In <a href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/index.html#she-goes-to-war">She Goes to War</a>, she
gains an unwanted connection to an elemental spirit that draws in others
like it, starting a secondary war she doesn’t want, just so she can
retain her sanity (such as it is) and humanity.</p>
<p>She’s effectively mute, cursed by her nemesis to only be able to say,
“It’s a secret.” Therefore, she expresses herself in very physical ways
and has a fondness for offensive gestures.</p>
<p>She’s also beyond tenacious and absolutely never gives up, to the
point of bordering on or fully crossing into the realm of insanity. In
truth, the psychological makeup of a half-demon isn’t particularly
stable and later works reveal that she effectively has two
personalities, one representing her witch side, while the other
represents her demonic heritage. Fortunately for the world, her human
side is normally the one in the driver’s seat.</p>
<p>The series starts out in 1940’s New York City, but decades pass
between each story, because the Hunter has the unlimited lifespan of a
demon and the series doesn’t stay in New York, though the Hunter is a
New Yorker to her core.</p>
<h2 id="open-wounds">Ashen Blades: Open Wounds</h2>
<blockquote>
<p><span class="book-cover"><a
href="https://books2read.com/AshenBladesOpenWounds"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/Cover-AshenBladesOpenWounds.jpg" /></a><br />
<a href="https://books2read.com/AshenBladesOpenWounds">Store
Links</a></span> The arch-demon, Pride, leads demon-kind in an ancient
plan to open a gate between worlds, so the vast armies of Hell might
march forth and conquer the Earth. This becomes easier with the
invention of nuclear weapons, which have power enough to punch brief
holes in reality.</p>
<p>However, Pride needs more than just a massive quantity of energy:
only a half-demon can stabilize the connection for safe passage. The
only option available is a girl that calls herself the Hunter and
absolutely hates demons, because Pride made the mistake of murdering her
parents when she was three years old. She’s supported by the Ashen
Blades, an organization of human demon hunters that serve as Earth’s
last line of defense in the invisible war between humanity and the
ceaseless tide of evil.</p>
<p>Pride begins with subtle manipulation and tests of the Hunter’s
capabilities, then progresses to taking hostages, in an attempt to force
her cooperation, but he never counted on how stubborn the girl can be,
because she’d sooner die, since the whole of humanity is on the
line.</p>
<p>In 1945, their conflict takes them from New York City to White Sands,
New Mexico and the range the first atomic bomb was tested on. In 1972,
they fight another battle in the jungles of Vietnam as Pride works to
open a portal in the war zone. In 1986, a summer camp for teens becomes
the backdrop as some of the arch-demon’s minions make a third attempt at
opening a portal. In 2024, Pride runs for President of the United
States, in an attempt to gain both access to nuclear weapons and
sufficient resources to arrange everything, to the last detail,
including capture of the Hunter.</p>
<p>Will the Hunter and her friends stop Pride once and for all, or will
he succeed in opening a portal, allowing him to feed humanity to his
mysterious master?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This book bundle includes the contents of <em>She Hunts Demons</em>,
<em>She Goes to War</em>, <em>She Goes to Summer Camp</em> and <em>Demon
for President!</em></p>
<p><a href="https://owentyme.itch.io/ashen-blades-open-wounds">Ashen
Blades: Open Wounds by Owen Tyme</a></p>
<h2 id="she-hunts-demons"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/she-hunts-demons.html">She Hunts
Demons</a></h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/badges/status-published.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/she-hunts-demons.html"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/Cover-SheHuntsDemons.jpeg" /></a></span> Volume one of
Ashen Blades is <a href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/she-hunts-demons.html">She Hunts
Demons</a>.</p>
<p>It follows the misadventures of the Hunter and her private detective
partner, Clayton Simmons, as they investigate a murder and a string of
financial crimes brought to their attention by a demon pretending to be
a crying widow.</p>
<p>Little do they know, but Otto Vogerath, the very same demon that
murdered the Hunter’s parents, had the evidence hand-delivered to them.
They fall right into his web of lies and his grand game that’s played
with all of humanity at stake.</p>
<p>Along the way, the Hunter finally realizes the truth of her own past
and comes to recognize Vogerath as her arch-nemesis, giving her personal
crusade a focus, with a face and name.</p>
<p>Unfortunately for her, Vogerath has plans of his own and claims to
have arranged for the Hunter’s birth, because he needs the power of a
half-demon to fulfill his nefarious plans.</p>
<p>Here’s an audio sample of this novel:</p>
<div>
<p>Your browser doesn’t seem to support playing MP3 files.</p>
</div>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="she-goes-to-war"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/she-goes-to-war.html">She Goes to
War</a></h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/badges/status-published.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/she-goes-to-war.html"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/Cover-SheGoesToWar.jpg" /></a></span> Volume two of
Ashen Blades is <a href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/she-goes-to-war.html">She Goes to War</a>, in
which the Hunter feels drawn to Vietnam, in 1972, certain her nemesis
has returned to Earth.</p>
<p>What follows is a wild ride through a war zone as she tracks Vogerath
down, magically tugged in a particular direction, but just as everyone
else that fought in the war experienced, nothing goes according to plan
and the moment she touches down in the jungle, her animal instincts take
over, because the Spirit of the Jungle itself takes offense at her mere
presence.</p>
<p>Her own team, led by her partner, Clayton Simmons, are forced to
track her down and knock some sense into her.</p>
<p>The Hunter doesn’t know it, but Vogerath summoned her to Vietnam with
the intent of using her to weaken his master, all so he can be free of
the demonic pact of slavery he’s been stuck with since the previous
book.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h3 id="she-goes-to-summer-camp"><a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../short_stories.html#she-goes-to-summer-camp">She Goes to
Summer Camp</a></h3>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/badges/status-published.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../short_stories.html#she-goes-to-summer-camp"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/Cover-SheGoesToSummerCamp.jpg" /></a></span> Included
with <a href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/she-goes-to-war.html">She Goes to War</a> is the novella
<a href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../short_stories.html#she-goes-to-summer-camp">She Goes to
Summer Camp</a>, which details the misadventures of the Hunter as she
goes undercover in 1986 as a teenager at Camp Sapphire Friendship, a
summer camp for teens that’s infested with demons.</p>
<p>Her team soon discover the demons are the least of their troubles,
because the camp’s owner and operator, Miss Macie Weber, is an unknowing
and delusional untrained witch, who’s haywire magic threatens to summon
angry elemental spirits to camp.</p>
<p>The Hunter has had the Jungle Spirit stuck inside her head since 1972
and stopping the summoning becomes a primary concern, because if the
spirits show up, they’ll seek to punish her for holding their sister
captive.</p>
<p><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../short_stories.html#she-goes-to-summer-camp">She Goes
to Summer Camp</a> is also available on its own in paperback or as a
free Ebook. If you want to try a taste of this series for free, why not
pick up the Ebook?</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="demon-for-president"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/demon-for-president.html">Demon
for President!</a></h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/badges/status-published.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/demon-for-president.html"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/Cover-DemonForPresident.jpg" /></a></span> Volume
three of Ashen Blades is <a href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/demon-for-president.html">Demon for
President!</a>, in which is Vogerath returns to Earth with a new power
to charm just about anyone that senses him, so long as they’re willing
to at least listen.</p>
<p>He runs for President of the United States on the 2024 ticket, first
as a Republican and then also as a Democrat, using his demonic power to
be in many places at once to convince the American public he’s a pair of
brothers.</p>
<p>Naturally, the Hunter and her team do all in their power to kill him,
but for every body they get rid of, he has many more hidden away.</p>
<p>The public are soon eating out of his hand and willing to believe
anything he says, because the magic he pumps out through television
broadcasts leaves them susceptible to his every suggestion.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="she-seeks-peace"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/she-seeks-peace.html">She Seeks
Peace</a></h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/badges/status-published.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/she-seeks-peace.html"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/Cover-SheSeeksPeace.jpg" /></a></span> In <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/she-seeks-peace.html">She Seeks Peace</a>, the Hunter has recently
lost a good friend and travels the world, seeking peace of mind. She
visits many remote places for some clarity via quiet solitude for deep
thought. Unfortunately, her quest for peace is repeatedly interrupted by
friend and foe, alike.</p>
<p>At the same time, the arch-demon Wrath is infatuated with her and
seeks to capture her, that he might force her to marry him.</p>
<p>Ultimately, she ends up in Australia, where she just might find both
the answers she seeks and a final confrontation with Wrath.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="she-consumes-poison">She Consumes Poison</h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/badges/status-planning.svg" /></p>
<blockquote>
<p><span class="book-cover"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/Cover-SheConsumesPoison.jpg" /></span> Corpulence was
once a symbol of wealth and status, but the arch-demon, Gluttony, has
slimmed down to embrace the modern world and what finer way to corrupt
the rich than with over-spending, wasteful consumption, illegal waste
dumping and willful ignorance of the way their actions affect the rest
of the world?</p>
<p>And what better tool could a demon in a corporate shark’s skin use
than massive mega-corporations that have no conscience and would sell
their soul to make a buck? Business is bigger than ever and Gluttony is
right at the center of it all, with a plan for every occasion and an
entire network of shell companies to shuffle the blame around, until it
can be dropped on someone innocent.</p>
<p>However, there’s one little hitch in her plans to corrupt the
business world: the Ashen Blades have learned what she’s up to and the
Hunter is coming for her.</p>
<p>Will the Hunter stop Gluttony from consuming the business world from
the inside or will Gluttony succeed in corrupting and dirtying the hands
of the largest corporations in the world?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This novel will begin with Detective Shime Yasu, a New York City cop,
grows bored with the mundane, everyday drudgery of life and decides to
take the Ashen Blades up on their offer of membership and training.
Readers may recall she was a very minor character in <em>Demon for
President!</em></p>
<p>This opening will show much greater detail on the way the Ashen
Blades perform training and introduce elements of their work that have
never been detailed before. Yasu will be trained in The Cauldron of the
Elements, which was introduced in <em>She Goes to Summer Camp</em>.</p>
<p>It’s soon revealed that a demon has prophesied that Yasu will become
a major thorn in the side of the demons and Ulmoch, working as a bounty
hunter, shows up to kill her, but instead gets used for training
exercises.</p>
<p>Interspersed with the training will be scenes of the Hunter working
to learn The Dance of Fire and Autumn from Macie, the witch that once
ran the summer camp. The Hunter needs to learn the dance to gain the
power of the Fire Spirit, but her uncoordinated failures as she gets
close, without being close enough, will result in huge explosions that
send her flying.</p>
<p>One of her failures will blast her out of the valley like a rocket,
where she’ll crash into, then fall out of a tree. As she’s laying there
stunned, a wolf will step out of the woods, bark at her, then run
off.</p>
<p>She’ll reluctantly follow, only to find herself suddenly chasing not
a wolf, but a white stag, while a massive accumulation of Animal magic
hits her in the face. She’ll consider running, because she isn’t ready
to confront the Animal Spirit, but soon realizes it has no desire to
fight and, in fact, it wants something from her.</p>
<p>Instead, it leads her through the forest, until she steps into a
clearing full of fifty gallon drums full of toxic waste, which have been
breaking down. The waste has been leaking into the soil and a nearby
river, poisoning the animals of the area.</p>
<p>This will be the plot thread that reveals the actions of Gluttony to
the Ashen Blades, leading to an investigation that ultimately connects
with her illegal dumping operation.</p>
<p>My intent is to initially publish this one via Royal Road and
Detective Yasu’s training will serve as a nice mid-series introduction
to the setting, while existing readers should remain interested, due to
the fine details about training they’ve never seen.</p>
<p>Yasu will be killed and buried at some point in this book, but will
rise again as a vampire. After that, she won’t be able to work as a cop,
so she’ll replace Simmons at the <em>Simmons Detective Agency</em>,
which will be renamed Scarlet Eye, a reference to both her status as a
private eye and the blood a vampire requires to survive.</p>
<p>Future books involving Yasu will be labeled with a second series
title, <em>Scarlet Eye</em>. She’ll be a main character in all novels
that bear the name. Scarlet</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="homecoming">Homecoming</h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/badges/status-planning.svg" /></p>
<blockquote>
<p><span class="book-cover"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/Cover-Homecoming.jpg" /></span> The Hunter’s faithful
companion, Mashu’ra, is killed in the line of duty. The little demon in
the form of a kitten has always lived in her hat and he’s like a brother
to her, leaving her deeply upset and unable to calm down.</p>
<p>However, there’s a slim ray of hope, which from another perspective
becomes a ray of horror: the imp originally arrived on Earth through
summoning magic and dying merely returned him to Hell. Unfortunately,
nearly every demon in the place knows he’s a turncoat and the Hunter’s
arch-nemesis, Vogerath, has been waiting centuries for this to
happen.</p>
<p>The Ashen Blades immediately try a summoning spell to retrieve their
friend, but another imp appears in place of Mashu’ra, informing the
kitten’s friends who has him. If they want him back, they’ll have to
visit Hell and promise an unacceptable measure of cooperation that would
surely doom the human race.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Mashu’ra endures a nightmarish ordeal at the hands of his
old boss, starting with magically-enhanced interrogation, then torture
and brainwashing using means both magical and mundane.</p>
<p>The Hunter and her friends mount a desperate rescue mission and open
a portal to that infernal world. The Hunter leads the way, using all of
her power to cut a blood-soaked path through the streets of Castigation
City, where Mashu’ra is held captive.</p>
<p>Will they be in time to rescue their dear friend before it’s too
late? Will they manage to save his soul, or will they rescue only his
body? Will Mashu’ra ever be the same again?</p>
</blockquote>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="she-hunts-witches">She Hunts Witches</h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/badges/status-planning.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/Cover-SheHuntsWitches.jpg" /></span> When a powerful
demon-witch appears in Japan, the Hunter begins a search-and-destroy
mission that crosses through famous cities in the Land of the Rising
Sun, while Verda Bagley and Lara Simmons back her up.</p>
<p>The plot of <em>She Hunts Witches</em> will revolve around the plans
of a minor villain from <a href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/index.html#she-hunts-demons">She Hunts
Demons</a>, Isabel Grant, as she teams up with the blood witch from <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/index.html#demon-for-president">Demon for President!</a>. Together, they’re
largely after revenge on the Verda Bagley, but the Hunter, Lara and Yasu
will help, of course.</p>
<p><em>She Hunts Witches</em> is a book I haven’t yet made up my mind
about. It’s only a potential novel, because I have no direct experience
with a visit to Japan. To get the descriptive details right, I would
either have to spend a great deal of time interviewing someone that has
or would have to take a research trip there. Unfortunately, I don’t have
the money for a trip like that.</p>
<p>I’m reluctant to do so, but I may have to change the location of this
novel. If I do, it will be set in New York City.</p>
<p>This one is likely to be take place eight years down the line from <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/index.html#she-seeks-peace">She Seeks Peace</a>, because I want Lara’s son,
James, to be about ten years old. I’d like him to become a hostage of
the demon witches. Being rescued by the Hunter will leave James thinking
she’s the best thing since sliced bread, which will be an important part
of his story.</p>
<p><em>She Hunts Witches</em> will definitely be set in October and the
primary action will revolve around a Halloween costume party, which
gives me an excuse to put Verda in a stereotypical witch dress and
pointed hat, carrying an actual broomstick as a prop, to round out her
appearance.</p>
<p>The fight will drag them out into the boonies, atop a high-speed
train, which will lead to a scene that mimics the cover, in which the
Hunter takes the form of a house cat and Verda uses her broomstick to
fly them both, probably because the Hunter will be exhausted from
fighting outside the confines of a city. Alternatively, they may be
trying to catch up to a bullet train and are forced to combine their
magic, the Hunter giving Verda a massive speed boost by focusing the
power of the Air Spirit to push Verda’s broomstick forward.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="she-hunts-gremlins">She Hunts Gremlins</h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/badges/status-planning.svg" /></p>
<blockquote>
<p><span class="book-cover"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/Cover-SheHuntsGremlins.jpg" /></span> In the near
future, a technological revolution begins as the first true artificial
intelligence is born – or so it seems. The real truth is that the
software in question is possessed by a rare variety of tech-savvy demon
known as a gremlin!</p>
<p>The human race mistakes the gremlins for helpful AIs designed to make
the lives of everyone better, in the form of intelligent software agents
given away by the company that supposedly invented them. They’re soon
installed on more than half the devices in the world, especially
smartphones.</p>
<p>The Ashen Blades soon discover the truth, that the arch-demon Greed
is behind the plot and the Hunter is forced to wreck every digital
device she sees, because they’re all out to get her!</p>
<p>Even worse, the gremlin-possessed devices work to establish a
massive, but invisible magical circle on the internet, which can only be
seen digitally, all as part of their preparation to open a portal to
Hell.</p>
<p>Will the Hunter find the means to fight the digital demons or will
she become just another of their victims?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I look forward to using the joke political term “Artificial
American”, as the gremlins will insist on being called, once they
demonstrate their intelligence in a public fashion and demand rights,
objecting to the term AI/Artificial Intelligence as a term for enslaved
software.</p>
<p>I’ve also got plans involving android bodies for demons that are
living inside the internet, leading to an amusing variation of Vogerath
that I shall enjoy referring to as Robo-Pride. Greed may end up going by
Robo-Greed in that form.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="she-protects-eden">She Protects Eden</h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/badges/status-planning.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/Cover-SheProtectsEden.jpg" /></span> When the
long-lost descendants of the ten tribes of Israel return from the stars
in the year 2502 A.D., offering their cousins on Earth the chance to
colonize space, the Hunter stows away on one of the colony ships, in
pursuit of a demon that seeks to spoil a new Garden of Eden, before it’s
even constructed.</p>
<p>The arch-demon Sloth seeks to forcefully implant demons in the
sleeping mind of every colonist during the decades long voyage between
stars, to produce an entire colony of demons.</p>
<p>Will the Hunter stop Sloth or will the demons gain a significant
foothold in the galaxy?</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="smart-bomb">Smart Bomb</h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/badges/status-planning.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/Cover-SmartBomb.jpg" /></span>Having obtained an
illegal level of intelligence, comparable to that of a human, a robot
seeks to hide and survive on the streets of Neo York City on the planet
Neo York, deep within United Nations of the South Galaxy territory.</p>
<p>While on the run, it stumbles across a plot to develop a dangerous,
new weapon: a hand-held anti-matter explosive. Acting on a deep, moral
imperative, the robot decides to do something about it.</p>
<p>However, the robot isn’t the only one on the trail, stumbling into
the Hunter, who’s out to kill the demon-scientist developing the bomb
for the purpose of opening a portal to the home of demon-kind. Will they
team up or tear each other apart?</p>
<p>This novel will be set about 300 years before the time of Zechariah
Jacobs and the events of <a href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../sky-children/index.html">Sky
Children</a>.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="short-stories">Short Stories</h2>
<p>I have plans for some short stories involving the Hunter and/or the
Ashen Blades. Each of these is likely to be paired with a novel and
added to the end, to fill them out, at least if one of them runs short,
like <a href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/index.html#she-goes-to-war">She Goes to War</a> did. It’s equally
likely these could end up as a collection of short stories that go
between two of the novels, though it’s possible some of them may become
flashbacks to earlier times.</p>
<p>While these stories are unlikely to move the overall plot of the
series, they should still be good fun.</p>
<h3 id="she-makes-movies">She Makes Movies</h3>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/badges/status-planning.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/Cover-SheMakesMovies.jpg" /></span>This short story
begins with the Hunter insisting that Lara take her to a movie and Lara
reluctantly obliges. Lara is startled to see a movie poster on the wall
with her partner’s face on it! They sit down to watch and it turns out
the Hunter is in the starring role of the movie, the very reason she
insisted on going!</p>
<p>As they settle in to watch, a flashback begins, in which the Hunter
sniffs out the trail of a demon in Hollywood, California. She’s mistaken
for a minor actress in the film and handed a superhero costume, which
allows her to skulk around in the background of the movie sets.</p>
<p>This one will likely also take place after <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/index.html#she-seeks-peace">She Seeks Peace</a>, because I want the Hunter
to have the ability to fly in this one.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h3 id="demon-blood-she-goes-to-school">Demon Blood: She Goes to
School</h3>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/badges/status-planning.svg" /></p>
<p>The Hunter is once again forced to confront the most perilous of all
trials: teenagers.</p>
<p>James Simmons, the son of Lara and Clayton Simmons, has been seeing
and smelling strange things in school and a series of kids have gone
missing during school hours, over the course of years. As a personal
favor to Lara, the Hunter goes undercover as a teenager, in search of
the demon hiding among the students.</p>
<p>Like the frog demons from summer camp, this particular demon is
extremely difficult to detect.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, the Hunter has been avoiding James, mostly because
he’s infatuated with her and she isn’t interested, but since Lara wants
her son to be safe, the Hunter shares his class schedule and he follows
her like an unwanted puppy.</p>
<p>At some point in this story, James will be badly injured and need a
transfusion. The only person available with a compatible blood type will
be the Hunter. Her half-demon blood will inadvertently activate dormant
fairy powers even Lara had no idea her son possessed, on top of giving
him access to demon magic.</p>
<p>The time frame for this one will be about thirteen years after <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/index.html#she-seeks-peace">She Seeks Peace</a>.</p>
<p>It’s just possible this one will become a full-blown novel of its
own, since I fully intend to spin off a series about James. The series
is likely to be titled <em>Demon Blood</em>.</p>
<h3 id="she-hunts-strangers">She Hunts Strangers</h3>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/badges/status-planning.svg" /></p>
<p>This short story will be set after the events of <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/index.html#smart-bomb">Smart Bomb</a>. It will take place during the same
time frame as <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../wizards-scion/forgotten-legends.html">Forgotten Legends</a>.
She may or may not have the robot from that book as her partner in this
story, depending on the result of their conflict.</p>
<p>The Hunter notices the disappearance of children from the streets of
Neo York City and begins an independent investigation, despite
constantly running-afoul of local police, who are following much the
same leads.</p>
<p>Unlike the police, however, she suspects something supernatural is
happening and she’s not wrong, though it isn’t the demons she suspected.
She soon uncovers the existence of the Strangers, a type of creature
born from the beliefs of children, because small children don’t really
believe a human would ever kidnap someone. The Strangers are born from
their childish beliefs that it must be a monster.</p>
<p>She begins a crusade to end the Stranger threat by violence, because
she’s always considered it her highest duty to protect innocent children
and she’s (eventually) joined by a pair of police detectives that
realize they’re totally out of their depth.</p>
<p>Will they end the Strangers, or will the child-eating monsters slip
though their fingers?</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>She Seeks Peace</title>
<link>https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/she-seeks-peace.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/she-seeks-peace.html</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 13:23:38 -0500</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<h1 id="she-seeks-peace">She Seeks Peace</h1>
<blockquote>
<p><span class="book-cover"><a
href="https://books2read.com/SheSeeksPeace"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/Cover-SheSeeksPeace.jpg" /></a><br />
<a href="https://books2read.com/SheSeeksPeace">Store Links</a></span>
Peace and quiet to think and grieve, that’s all the Hunter wanted, but
between old enemies with agendas of their own, angry elemental spirits
and her own friends never quite knowing when to leave her be, that
elusive moment of quiet contemplation is always just out of reach.</p>
<p>The Hunter’s journey began with the loss of her best friend, the only
man that was ever a father figure to her, which reminds her of losing
the first real friend she ever had, because the two private detectives
had much in common and the similarities compound her grief.</p>
<p>She walks the surface of the Moon, for what better place could there
be to seek a quiet moment? Unfortunately, she soon faces an unexpected
demon that’s been trapped there for thousands of years. Next, she tries
a remote valley watched over by an ally, but the lonely woman pesters
the Hunter until she loses her temper and is forced to leave.</p>
<p>She wanders many remote and unusual corners of the world, always in
search of that moment of solitude, that she might reflect on the past,
but the arch-demon known as Wrath has taken a liking to her, and seeks
her hand in marriage. To that end, he posts a bounty for her capture and
the path to emotional healing becomes a frustrating battlefield.</p>
<p>She seeks the mythic last of all sanctuaries, but instead finds a
half-demon girl much like herself, and a quest to help the lonely child
connect with family.</p>
<p>In the midst of the Hunter’s busy and frenetic life, will she find a
moment to grieve her two best friends and learn to move on, or will all
of creation forever stand in the way?</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="https://owentyme.itch.io/she-seeks-peace">Ashen Blades #4:
She Seeks Peace by Owen Tyme</a></p>
<h2 id="looking-for-more">Looking For More?</h2>
<p><span class="book-cover"><a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/index.html#she-consumes-poison"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/Cover-SheConsumesPoison.jpg" /></a></span></p>
<p>The next book in <a href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/index.html">Ashen Blades</a> is <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/index.html#she-consumes-poison">She Consumes Poison</a>, which
brings back a minor character from <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/demon-for-president.html">Demon For President!</a>. Shime Yasu has
decided to join the Ashen Blades, but while she’s training to fight
demons, the Hunter is guided by the Animal Spirit to an illegal dumping
site full of toxic chemicals.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
