<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
<title>Owen Tyme - Science Fiction and Fantasy Author</title>
<link>https://owentyme.us/</link>
<description>Owen Tyme writes science fiction and fantasy novels</description>
<category>Indie Author</category>
<copyright>Copyright 2025, Owen Tyme</copyright>
<lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 20:23:20 -0600</lastBuildDate>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 20:23:20 -0600</pubDate>
<atom:link href="https://owentyme.us/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<item>
<title>Ashen Blades</title>
<link>https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/index.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/index.html</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 20:22:47 -0600</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<h1 id="ashen-blades">Ashen Blades</h1>
<p>This series centers around the life of a half-demon girl that calls
herself the Hunter, whose parents were murdered by demons. Joining her
crusade against demon-kind are the Ashen Blades, also known as the Order
of Ash and Smoke, an organization of demon hunters.</p>
<p>The Hunter starts out with demon powers only, but eventually learns
that she’s also a witch, because her mother was a witch before she
became a demon. In <a href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/index.html#she-goes-to-war">She Goes to War</a>, she
gains an unwanted connection to an elemental spirit that draws in others
like it, starting a secondary war she doesn’t want, just so she can
retain her sanity (such as it is) and humanity.</p>
<p>She’s effectively mute, cursed by her nemesis to only be able to say,
“It’s a secret.” Therefore, she expresses herself in very physical ways
and has a fondness for offensive gestures.</p>
<p>She’s also beyond tenacious and absolutely never gives up, to the
point of bordering on or fully crossing into the realm of insanity. In
truth, the psychological makeup of a half-demon isn’t particularly
stable and later works reveal that she effectively has two
personalities, one representing her witch side, while the other
represents her demonic heritage. Fortunately for the world, her human
side is normally the one in the driver’s seat.</p>
<p>The series starts out in 1940’s New York City, but decades pass
between each story, because the Hunter has the unlimited lifespan of a
demon and the series doesn’t stay in New York, though the Hunter is a
New Yorker to her core.</p>
<h2 id="she-hunts-demons"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/she-hunts-demons.html">She Hunts
Demons</a></h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/badges/status-published.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/she-hunts-demons.html"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/Cover-SheHuntsDemons.jpeg" /></a></span> Volume one of
Ashen Blades is <a href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/she-hunts-demons.html">She Hunts
Demons</a>.</p>
<p>It follows the misadventures of the Hunter and her private detective
partner, Clayton Simmons, as they investigate a murder and a string of
financial crimes brought to their attention by a demon pretending to be
a crying widow.</p>
<p>Little do they know, but Otto Vogerath, the very same demon that
murdered the Hunter’s parents, had the evidence hand-delivered to them.
They fall right into his web of lies and his grand game that’s played
with all of humanity at stake.</p>
<p>Along the way, the Hunter finally realizes the truth of her own past
and comes to recognize Vogerath as her arch-nemesis, giving her personal
crusade a focus, with a face and name.</p>
<p>Unfortunately for her, Vogerath has plans of his own and claims to
have arranged for the Hunter’s birth, because he needs the power of a
half-demon to fulfill his nefarious plans.</p>
<p>Here’s an audio sample of this novel:</p>
<div>
<p>Your browser doesn’t seem to support playing MP3 files.</p>
</div>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="she-goes-to-war"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/she-goes-to-war.html">She Goes to
War</a></h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/badges/status-published.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/she-goes-to-war.html"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/Cover-SheGoesToWar.jpg" /></a></span> Volume two of
Ashen Blades is <a href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/she-goes-to-war.html">She Goes to War</a>, in
which the Hunter feels drawn to Vietnam, in 1972, certain her nemesis
has returned to Earth.</p>
<p>What follows is a wild ride through a war zone as she tracks Vogerath
down, magically tugged in a particular direction, but just as everyone
else that fought in the war experienced, nothing goes according to plan
and the moment she touches down in the jungle, her animal instincts take
over, because the Spirit of the Jungle itself takes offense at her mere
presence.</p>
<p>Her own team, led by her partner, Clayton Simmons, are forced to
track her down and knock some sense into her.</p>
<p>The Hunter doesn’t know it, but Vogerath summoned her to Vietnam with
the intent of using her to weaken his master, all so he can be free of
the demonic pact of slavery he’s been stuck with since the previous
book.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h3 id="she-goes-to-summer-camp"><a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../short_stories.html#she-goes-to-summer-camp">She Goes to
Summer Camp</a></h3>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/badges/status-published.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../short_stories.html#she-goes-to-summer-camp"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/Cover-SheGoesToSummerCamp.jpg" /></a></span> Included
with <a href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/she-goes-to-war.html">She Goes to War</a> is the novella
<a href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../short_stories.html#she-goes-to-summer-camp">She Goes to
Summer Camp</a>, which details the misadventures of the Hunter as she
goes undercover in 1986 as a teenager at Camp Sapphire Friendship, a
summer camp for teens that’s infested with demons.</p>
<p>Her team soon discover the demons are the least of their troubles,
because the camp’s owner and operator, Miss Macie Weber, is an unknowing
and delusional untrained witch, who’s haywire magic threatens to summon
angry elemental spirits to camp.</p>
<p>The Hunter has had the Jungle Spirit stuck inside her head since 1972
and stopping the summoning becomes a primary concern, because if the
spirits show up, they’ll seek to punish her for holding their sister
captive.</p>
<p><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../short_stories.html#she-goes-to-summer-camp">She Goes
to Summer Camp</a> is also available on its own in paperback or as a
free Ebook. If you want to try a taste of this series for free, why not
pick up the Ebook?</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="demon-for-president"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/demon-for-president.html">Demon
for President!</a></h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/badges/status-published.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/demon-for-president.html"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/Cover-DemonForPresident.jpg" /></a></span> Volume
three of Ashen Blades is <a href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/demon-for-president.html">Demon for
President!</a>, in which is Vogerath returns to Earth with a new power
to charm just about anyone that senses him, so long as they’re willing
to at least listen.</p>
<p>He runs for President of the United States on the 2024 ticket, first
as a Republican and then also as a Democrat, using his demonic power to
be in many places at once to convince the American public he’s a pair of
brothers.</p>
<p>Naturally, the Hunter and her team do all in their power to kill him,
but for every body they get rid of, he has many more hidden away.</p>
<p>The public are soon eating out of his hand and willing to believe
anything he says, because the magic he pumps out through television
broadcasts leaves them susceptible to his every suggestion.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="she-seeks-peace"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/she-seeks-peace.html">She Seeks
Peace</a></h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/badges/status-published.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/she-seeks-peace.html"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/Cover-SheSeeksPeace.jpg" /></a></span> In <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/she-seeks-peace.html">She Seeks Peace</a>, the Hunter has recently
lost a good friend and travels the world, seeking peace of mind. She
visits many remote places for some clarity via quiet solitude for deep
thought. Unfortunately, her quest for peace is repeatedly interrupted by
friend and foe, alike.</p>
<p>At the same time, the arch-demon Wrath is infatuated with her and
seeks to capture her, that he might force her to marry him.</p>
<p>Ultimately, she ends up in Australia, where she just might find both
the answers she seeks and a final confrontation with Wrath.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="she-hunts-gluttony">She Hunts Gluttony (Working Title)</h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/badges/status-planning.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/Cover-SheHuntsGluttony.jpg" /></span> Corpulence was
once a symbol of wealth and status, but the arch-demon, Gluttony, has
slimmed down to embrace the modern world and what finer way to corrupt
the rich than with over-spending, wasteful consumption, illegal waste
dumping and willful ignorance of the way their actions affect the rest
of the world?</p>
<p>And what better tool could a demon in a corporate shark’s skin use
than massive mega-corporations that have no conscience and would sell
their soul to make a buck? Business is bigger than ever and Gluttony is
right at the center of it all, with a plan for every occasion and an
entire network of shell companies to shuffle the blame around, until it
can be dropped on someone innocent.</p>
<p>However, there’s one little hitch in her plans to corrupt the
business world: the Ashen Blades have just been tipped off about what
she’s doing and the Hunter is coming for her.</p>
<p>Will the Hunter stop Gluttony from consuming the business world from
the inside or will Gluttony succeed in corrupting and dirtying the hands
of the largest corporations in the world?</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="she-hunts-gremlins">She Hunts Gremlins</h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/badges/status-planning.svg" /></p>
<blockquote>
<p><span class="book-cover"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/Cover-SheHuntsGremlins.jpg" /></span></p>
<p>In the near future, a technological revolution begins as the first
true artificial intelligence is born – or so it seems. The real truth is
that the software in question is possessed by a rare variety of
tech-savvy demon known as a gremlin!</p>
<p>The human race mistakes the gremlins for helpful AIs designed to make
the lives of everyone better, in the form of intelligent software agents
given away by the company that supposedly invented them. They’re soon
installed on more than half the devices in the world, especially
smartphones.</p>
<p>The Ashen Blades soon discover the truth, that the arch-demon Greed
is behind the plot and the Hunter is forced to wreck every digital
device she sees, because they’re all out to get her!</p>
<p>Even worse, the gremlin-possessed devices work to establish a
massive, but invisible magical circle on the internet, which can only be
seen digitally, all as part of their preparation to open a portal to
Hell.</p>
<p>Will the Hunter find the means to fight the digital demons or will
she become just another of their victims?</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="she-hunts-witches">She Hunts Witches</h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/badges/status-planning.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/Cover-SheHuntsWitches.jpg" /></span> When a powerful
demon-witch appears in Japan, the Hunter begins a search-and-destroy
mission that crosses through famous cities in the Land of the Rising
Sun, while Verda Bagley and Lara Simmons back her up.</p>
<p>The plot of <em>She Hunts Witches</em> will revolve around the plans
of a minor villain from <a href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/index.html#she-hunts-demons">She Hunts Demons</a>
as she teams up with the blood witch from <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/index.html#demon-for-president">Demon for President!</a>. Together, they’re
largely after revenge on the Hunter and her friends.</p>
<p><em>She Hunts Witches</em> is a book I haven’t yet made up my mind
about. It’s only a potential novel, because I have no direct experience
with a visit to Japan. To get the descriptive details right, I would
either have to spend a great deal of time interviewing someone that has
or would have to take a research trip there. Unfortunately, I don’t have
the money for a trip like that.</p>
<p>I’m reluctant to do so, but I may have to change the location of this
novel.</p>
<p>This one is likely to be set eight years down the line from <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/index.html#she-seeks-peace">She Seeks Peace</a>, because I want Lara’s son,
James, to be about ten years old. I’d like him to become a hostage of
the demon witches. Being rescued by the Hunter will leave James thinking
the she’s the best thing since sliced bread.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="she-protects-eden">She Protects Eden</h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/badges/status-planning.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/Cover-SheProtectsEden.jpg" /></span> When the
long-lost descendants of the ten tribes of Israel return from the stars
in the year 2502 A.D., offering their cousins on Earth the chance to
colonize space, the Hunter stows away on one of the colony ships, in
pursuit of a demon that seeks to spoil a new Garden of Eden, before it’s
even constructed.</p>
<p>The arch-demon Sloth seeks to forcefully implant demons in the
sleeping mind of every colonist during the decades long voyage between
stars, to produce an entire colony of demons.</p>
<p>Will the Hunter stop Sloth or will the demons gain a significant
foothold in the galaxy?</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="smart-bomb">Smart Bomb</h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/badges/status-planning.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/Cover-SmartBomb.jpg" /></span>Having obtained an
illegal level of intelligence, comparable to that of a human, a robot
seeks to hide and survive on the streets of Neo York City on the planet
Neo York, deep within United Nations of the South Galaxy territory.</p>
<p>While on the run, it stumbles across a plot to develop a dangerous,
new weapon: a hand-held anti-matter explosive. Acting on a deep, moral
imperative, the robot decides to do something about it.</p>
<p>However, the robot isn’t the only one on the trail, stumbling into
the Hunter, who’s out to kill the demon-scientist developing the bomb
for the purpose of opening a portal to the home of demon-kind. Will they
team up or tear each other apart?</p>
<p>This novel will be set about 300 years before the time of Zechariah
Jacobs and the events of <a href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../sky-children/index.html">Sky
Children</a>.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="short-stories">Short Stories</h2>
<p>I have plans for some short stories involving the Hunter and/or the
Ashen Blades. Each of these is likely to be paired with a novel and
added to the end, to fill them out, at least if one of them runs short,
like <a href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/index.html#she-goes-to-war">She Goes to War</a> did. It’s equally
likely these could end up as a collection of short stories that go
between two of the novels, though it’s possible some of them may become
flashbacks to earlier times.</p>
<p>While these stories are unlikely to move the overall plot of the
series, they should still be good fun.</p>
<h3 id="the-new-recruit">The New Recruit</h3>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/badges/status-planning.svg" /></p>
<p>In this short story, Detective Shime Yasu, a New York City cop, grows
bored with the mundane, everyday drudgery of life and decides to take
the Ashen Blades up on their offer of membership and training.</p>
<p>She locates the card she was given, calls the number and makes
contact. She’s assigned Lara Simmons as her trainer and that necessarily
also involves the Hunter lending a hand, since the two of them are
partners.</p>
<p>On the first day of training, it turns out that every one of the
trainees brought weapons from home, based on superstition and
misconception, including the detective.</p>
<p>To disabuse the trainees of their incorrect notions, the Hunter
captures the infamous squirrel-demon, Ulmoch, and every one of the
strange and amusing items the trainees brought is tested on him, to
demonstrates what does and doesn’t work.</p>
<p>This has to take place after <a href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/index.html#she-seeks-peace">She Seeks
Peace</a>, since it’s based on the detective from <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/index.html#demon-for-president">Demon for President!</a> and there was no
time skip between those two novels.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h3 id="she-makes-movies">She Makes Movies</h3>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/badges/status-planning.svg" /></p>
<p>This short story begins with the Hunter insisting that Lara take her
to a movie and Lara reluctantly obliges. Lara is startled to see a movie
poster on the wall with her partner’s face on it! They sit down to watch
and it turns out the Hunter is in the starring role of the movie, the
very reason she insisted on going!</p>
<p>As they settle in to watch, a flashback begins, in which the Hunter
sniffs out the trail of a demon in Hollywood, California. She’s mistaken
for a minor actress in the film and handed a superhero costume, which
allows her to skulk around in the background of the movie sets.</p>
<p>This one will likely also take place after <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/index.html#she-seeks-peace">She Seeks Peace</a>, because I want the Hunter
to have the ability to fly in this one.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h3 id="demon-blood-she-goes-to-school">Demon Blood: She Goes to
School</h3>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/badges/status-planning.svg" /></p>
<p>The Hunter is once again forced to confront the most perilous of all
trials: teenagers.</p>
<p>James Simmons, the son of Lara and Clayton Simmons, has been seeing
and smelling strange things in school and a series of kids have gone
missing during school hours, over the course of years. As a personal
favor to Lara, the Hunter goes undercover as a teenager, in search of
the demon hiding among the students.</p>
<p>Like the frog demons from summer camp, this particular demon is
extremely difficult to detect.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, the Hunter has been avoiding James, mostly because
he’s infatuated with her and she isn’t interested, but since Lara wants
her son to be safe, the Hunter shares his class schedule and he follows
her like an unwanted puppy.</p>
<p>At some point in this story, James will be badly injured and need a
transfusion. The only person available with a compatible blood type will
be the Hunter. Her half-demon blood will inadvertently activate dormant
fairy powers even Lara had no idea her son possessed, on top of giving
him access to demon magic.</p>
<p>The time frame for this one will be about thirteen years after <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/index.html#she-seeks-peace">She Seeks Peace</a>.</p>
<p>It’s just possible this one will become a full-blown novel of its
own, since I fully intend to spin off a series about James. The series
is likely to be titled <em>Demon Blood</em>.</p>
<h3 id="she-hunts-strangers">She Hunts Strangers</h3>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../../images/badges/status-planning.svg" /></p>
<p>This short story will be set after the events of <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/index.html#smart-bomb">Smart Bomb</a>. It will take place during the same
time frame as <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/../wizards-scion/forgotten-legends.html">Forgotten Legends</a>.
She may or may not have the robot from that book as her partner in this
story, depending on the result of their conflict.</p>
<p>The Hunter notices the disappearance of children from the streets of
Neo York City and begins an independent investigation, despite
constantly running-afoul of local police, who are following much the
same leads.</p>
<p>Unlike the police, however, she suspects something supernatural is
happening and she’s not wrong, though it isn’t the demons she suspected.
She soon uncovers the existence of the Strangers, a type of creature
born from the beliefs of children, because small children don’t really
believe a human would ever kidnap someone. The Strangers are born from
their childish beliefs that it must be a monster.</p>
<p>She begins a crusade to end the Stranger threat by violence, because
she’s always considered it her highest duty to protect innocent children
and she’s (eventually) joined by a pair of police detectives that
realize they’re totally out of their depth.</p>
<p>Will they end the Strangers, or will the child-eating monsters slip
though their fingers?</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Sweet Surrender</title>
<link>https://owentyme.us/shorts/short-of-tyme/sweet-surrender.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/shorts/short-of-tyme/sweet-surrender.html</guid>
<pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 08:01:32 -0600</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>In this trio of linked tales, learn what happens when the unstoppable
force meets the immovable object.</p>
<p>In the first tale, a priestess to the god of empathy never wanted to
involve herself in politics, but when her king seeks riches from the
kingdom at the expense of the common man, she’s forced to put herself
directly in the path of the King’s armies, who are under strict orders
to turn her away, even if it means killing her. Unfortunately for them,
they didn’t count on the pain they inflict on her reflecting back!</p>
<p>In the second tale, nobles discuss Aaron Kozinski, an amazing guard
that never fails in his duty, no matter how bleak the situation, all in
exchange for a little money, that he might eat and pay rent. He stands
guard in horrendous weather and even repels assassins, preventing them
from coming anywhere near his employer, all without complaint.</p>
<p>In the concluding tale, the two are manipulated into conflict by a
mysterious man that hopes they’ll destroy each other.</p>
<p>Will the priestess learn enough about Aaron to ease his pain or will
she be overwhelmed by his hopelessly broken heart?</p>
</blockquote>
<div id="prose" class="prose">
<h1 id="sweet-surrender">Sweet Surrender</h1>
<h2 id="short-of-tyme-4">Short of Tyme #4</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://owentyme.us/shorts/short-of-tyme/sweet-surrender.html#tale-1-unstoppable" id="toc-tale-1-unstoppable">Tale 1
Unstoppable</a></li>
<li><a href="https://owentyme.us/shorts/short-of-tyme/sweet-surrender.html#tale-2-immovable" id="toc-tale-2-immovable">Tale 2
Immovable</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://owentyme.us/shorts/short-of-tyme/sweet-surrender.html#chapter-1-noble-inquiry"
id="toc-chapter-1-noble-inquiry">Chapter 1 Noble Inquiry</a></li>
<li><a href="https://owentyme.us/shorts/short-of-tyme/sweet-surrender.html#chapter-2-fires-of-hearth-and-home"
id="toc-chapter-2-fires-of-hearth-and-home">Chapter 2 Fires of Hearth
and Home</a></li>
<li><a href="https://owentyme.us/shorts/short-of-tyme/sweet-surrender.html#chapter-3-attention-to-duty"
id="toc-chapter-3-attention-to-duty">Chapter 3 Attention to
Duty</a></li>
<li><a href="https://owentyme.us/shorts/short-of-tyme/sweet-surrender.html#chapter-4-ash-blood-pass"
id="toc-chapter-4-ash-blood-pass">Chapter 4 Ash-Blood Pass</a></li>
<li><a href="https://owentyme.us/shorts/short-of-tyme/sweet-surrender.html#chapter-5-noble-demand"
id="toc-chapter-5-noble-demand">Chapter 5 Noble Demand</a></li>
</ul></li>
<li><a href="https://owentyme.us/shorts/short-of-tyme/sweet-surrender.html#tale-3-collision" id="toc-tale-3-collision">Tale 3
Collision</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://owentyme.us/shorts/short-of-tyme/sweet-surrender.html#chapter-1-gainful-employment"
id="toc-chapter-1-gainful-employment">Chapter 1 Gainful
Employment</a></li>
<li><a href="https://owentyme.us/shorts/short-of-tyme/sweet-surrender.html#chapter-2-the-would-be-kidnapper"
id="toc-chapter-2-the-would-be-kidnapper">Chapter 2 The Would-Be
Kidnapper</a></li>
<li><a href="https://owentyme.us/shorts/short-of-tyme/sweet-surrender.html#chapter-3-bar-breaker"
id="toc-chapter-3-bar-breaker">Chapter 3 Bar Breaker</a></li>
<li><a href="https://owentyme.us/shorts/short-of-tyme/sweet-surrender.html#chapter-4-a-lovely-meeting"
id="toc-chapter-4-a-lovely-meeting">Chapter 4 A Lovely Meeting</a></li>
<li><a href="https://owentyme.us/shorts/short-of-tyme/sweet-surrender.html#chapter-5-the-price-of-empathy"
id="toc-chapter-5-the-price-of-empathy">Chapter 5 The Price of
Empathy</a></li>
<li><a href="https://owentyme.us/shorts/short-of-tyme/sweet-surrender.html#chapter-6-the-undelivered-letter"
id="toc-chapter-6-the-undelivered-letter">Chapter 6 The Undelivered
Letter</a></li>
<li><a href="https://owentyme.us/shorts/short-of-tyme/sweet-surrender.html#chapter-7-sweet-surrender"
id="toc-chapter-7-sweet-surrender">Chapter 7 Sweet Surrender</a></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>
<h1 id="tale-1-unstoppable">Tale 1 Unstoppable</h1>
<p>The priestess strode confidently up the hillside, alone. She was
dressed in a simple, white, hooded robe that reached to her ankles. The
color and simplicity of her robes marked her station as a priestess. Her
short, blond hair had been tucked into her hood.</p>
<p>“Ready!”</p>
<p>The archers raised their bows. She continued, unperturbed, her face
locked in a grim expression of determination.</p>
<p>“Aim!”</p>
<p>They took aim. She pressed forward, ignoring them.</p>
<p>“Fire!”</p>
<p>Dozens of arrows were loosed, nearly every one of them striking the
priestess!</p>
<hr />
<p>The small hovel, suitable for a family of four, was housing twice
that many. Most of the family, consisting of four children and their
parents, greeted the priestess at the front door. She gave them a small
bag of flour; it was all she could spare for the poor family, with so
many of her flock in a similar situation.</p>
<p>She was directed to a back room of the hovel where one of the only
two beds in the house was occupied by an elderly couple, the
grandparents of the children. They were emaciated from the ravages of
hunger and near to death. They'd stopped eating to spare the lives of
their grandchildren.</p>
<p>She knelt next to them and clasped their hands, speaking words of
comfort. She reached into her heart and drew upon her connection to her
god, bringing the pain and suffering of her flock into herself, giving
them a few painless hours with which to say goodbye to their family.</p>
<p>She held their hands the entire time, trembling with pain, until
their last breaths.</p>
<hr />
<p>Grunting in pain as the arrows clattered to the ground around her,
the priestess fell to her knees. At the same time she dropped each
archer that struck his mark fell, bleeding from an unexpected wound, but
the priestess was <em>not</em> bleeding!</p>
<p>“Doesn't even compare.” She muttered, mostly to herself.</p>
<p>The few archers that missed panicked and ran, while one cried out, in
terror, “She's a witch!”</p>
<p>Standing, she made her way to the side of the most grievously wounded
archer, tore strips of cloth from her robe and bound his wounds, then
did likewise for a few others. The rest were too far gone to save.</p>
<p>She stood once more, faced the remaining soldiers and continued up
the hillside. One stood to block her path, his finely-made and daily
honed sword pointed in her face, his grip and confidence hinting at his
expertise.</p>
<p>“Turn back!” he ordered.</p>
<p>She stepped around his sword, ignoring him. He quickly blocked her
way and pointed the blade in her face, again!</p>
<p>Nervously, he called, “I-I'm warning you, I <em>will</em> cut you
down!”</p>
<p>“Don't stand in my way.” She gave him an unimpressed look, “I'm
warning <em>you</em>, you'll only hurt yourself!”</p>
<p>She didn’t resist as the soldier charged, delivering a mighty swing
that connected solidly with the side of her neck, full force!</p>
<hr />
<p>The priestess hurried into the woods, alongside the local doctor, who
was little more than an old sawbones. The woodcutters had sent for both
her and the doctor.</p>
<p>When they arrived, she saw one of her flock, a poor man that spent
more time in the woods than he should have, because he wanted to help
his less fortunate neighbors survive the coming winter. They couldn't
afford his services, but he provided them anyway.</p>
<p>The evidence of the terrible incident with the ax was everywhere,
staining the fall leaves a deeper shade.</p>
<p>The doctor examined the man, shaking his head; too much time had
passed and the woodcutters didn't known how to save such a badly damaged
arm, simply tying a tourniquet to staunch the bleeding.</p>
<p>“I'll have to amputate.” The expected words were delivered by the
doctor, “I'm out of anesthetic, so we'll have to do this the hard
way.”</p>
<p>Everyone but the priestess cringed.</p>
<p>The priestess shook her head and reached out for the woodcutter's
undamaged hand. She concentrated and focused on taking the pain on
herself. As she did so, the man's breathing returned to normal and she
nodded to the doctor.</p>
<p>She held the woodcutter's hand as the surgery was completed,
trembling and sweating, but not crying out, stubbornly clenching the
woodcutter's hand the entire time. The surgery went well, aside from the
priestess accidentally breaking a bone in the man's other hand, from
squeezing too tight.</p>
<hr />
<p>The fierceness of the blow caught her off-guard, causing her to lose
her balance and roll downhill for roughly ten feet, until she grabbed
hold of a tree root.</p>
<p>The soldier's face bore a look of shock and pain as his head fell
free, followed shortly by his body, which began to convulse!</p>
<p>The priestess, covered head to toe in sweat, fallen leaves, dirt and
loose grass, stood on her feet, somewhat unsteadily, rubbing her neck.
The remainder of her hood dangled loose, revealing her head of short,
blond hair.</p>
<p>“That hurt.” She muttered in a somewhat befuddled state as she pulled
her hood back on.</p>
<p>After a few moments to gather her wits, she looked around. All of the
soldiers had fled, except for one. She continued up the hill.</p>
<p>The last man standing was clearly frightened, but stood his ground,
directly in her path. He was older, with a graying mustache and beard.
His sword was sheathed and his shield was lying discarded to one side.
The insignia on his breastplate marked his rank as captain of the
guard.</p>
<p>“Get out of my way!” she commanded.</p>
<p>“I'm duty-bound, ma’am. I can't let you pass.”</p>
<p>“You will.” She predicted.</p>
<p>She moved to step around him and the man put his hands on her
shoulders, leaning forward and shoved with everything he had! The
priestess, unprepared for such an indirect use of force, fell back and
tumbled down the hill, uncontrolled!</p>
<hr />
<p>Having carefully positioned himself for it, the force of the reverse
shove dropped the soldier on his back and knocked the wind out of him.
He expected to feel each impact as the priestess rolled down the hill,
but was surprised when he didn't.</p>
<p>He got back to his feet and brushed himself off, feeling certain he’d
found a chink in his opponent’s god-given armor: side effects of simple
shoves were all he needed to win.</p>
<hr />
<p>The priestess stopped her fall, roughly half-way down. She was
covered in bruises, cuts and scrapes, her robe now mostly a tattered
mess, but she was still able to get to her feet. Clearly, her last
opponent was smarter than the rest.</p>
<p>She strode up the hill to stand before him, once more, but stopped
short by twenty feet.</p>
<p>“I know how to stop you now!” He threatened.</p>
<p>“No.” She shook her head, “You can knock me down, but I always get
up.”</p>
<p>“I salute you.” He nodded, with respect, “Your tolerance for pain is
incredible.”</p>
<p>She nodded to him, in turn, “Years of training. Years of enduring the
pain of my flock.” She paused for a brief moment before she continued,
with emotion in her voice, “The flock your king has wounded.”</p>
<p>The soldier looked ashamed, “I'm bound to obey his commands. You
cannot pass.”</p>
<p>“That's unfortunate. I don't want to hurt you.”</p>
<p>This time, she charged, running up the hill in a sudden burst of
speed! She didn't aim to move by him, but aimed directly at him! He
braced for the impact!</p>
<p>The collision wasn't anything you'd put in a book on martial arts,
except as an example of what not to do. It shouldn't have worked against
a highly-trained soldier.</p>
<p>She left the guard captain lying there, clutching the back of his
head and cursing.</p>
<p>She finished her ascent of the steep hill and approached the
drawbridge of the castle. It was up.</p>
<p>“Lower the bridge or I'll do to you want I did to the others!” She
bellowed, bluffing!</p>
<p>There was a hurried argument and then the bridge lowered. Two
soldiers passed her on either side, nodding respectfully and then ran as
fast as they dared down the hill!</p>
<hr />
<p>As she entered the castle, the captain of the guard stopped
pretending to be hurt. He hoped for a moment he was doing the best thing
for his king. He thought on the priestess' behavior and smiled to
himself, content he did right. He strode into the castle a few minutes
later, heading for his office, to write a letter of resignation.</p>
<hr />
<p>The king screamed, “Guards! Remove this woman from my throne
room!”</p>
<p>She paused for dramatic effect and looked around, waiting for anyone
to show up. Some servants stepped into the room, but no guards.</p>
<p>She explained, “I'd be quite willing to guess you have no guards
left. Most of your archers have arrow wounds. Unfortunately, a fair
number of them were so badly wounded there was nothing I could do. Also,
one of your foot soldiers lost his head when he foolishly tried to cut
mine off. Your guard captain probably has a concussion, but I doubt
he'll remain in your service after today. The rest deserted.”</p>
<p>“Then I’ll strike you down myself!” The king announced, arrogantly,
drawing his sword with his right hand.</p>
<p>“I would think before acting, if I were you.” She warned, “How do you
think I got past your guards?”</p>
<p>The king's eyes widened and his lower lip trembled slightly, but he
stepped forward and demanded, “What sorcery did you use on my men,
witch?”</p>
<p>She held out her right hand and suggested, “Use that sword to give me
a small cut on my hand. I think this will aid understanding.”</p>
<p>Confused, but also curious, the king forcefully jabbed the palm of
her hand with the tip of his fine blade and immediately dropped it, his
freshly injured sword hand trembling in pain as it bled, looking as
though a sword had gone clean through it!</p>
<p>The priestess sighed, tore another strip of cloth from her ragged
robe, knelt beside him and started bandaging his hand.</p>
<p>She chided him, “I said a <em>small</em> cut.”</p>
<p>He sat on the floor and allowed her to work, clearly dumbfounded by
her actions.</p>
<p>“Do you know why I'm here?” She asked, once she’d finished, still
kneeling beside him.</p>
<p>He shook his head, thoroughly confused.</p>
<p>“You've caused the death of many of my flock, mostly through heavy
taxes, but also through heavy-handed laws. I feel the pain of each of
them, that I may know their needs and work to care for them.”</p>
<p>She slapped him, as hard as she could, leaving a red imprint of her
hand on his face! He didn't resist.</p>
<p>“You sit here, on your throne, handing down orders that hurt my
flock, that kill my flock as surely as a sword through the heart!”</p>
<p>She slapped him on the other cheek, just as hard!</p>
<p>Her second slap brought a memory to mind, from three years before.
She wasn't sure if it was her god's doing or simply the memory being
stirred up by seeing the king again.</p>
<hr />
<p>The priestess ran to the castle and the first servant she met
wordlessly took her straight to the queen's private chambers.</p>
<p>The queen was lying in her bed, dying. Childbirth had gone wrong in
many ways and the midwife had called in the doctors, for it was that
bad. The little baby princess was already dead, having never taken a
breath.</p>
<p>The king was there, at her side, holding her hand.</p>
<p>The priestess took the tiny woman's other hand and held it, willing
the pain from the dying body into herself.</p>
<p>The king and queen had a precious, heartfelt goodbye with the queen's
pain out of the way.</p>
<hr />
<p>The priestess shed a tear, stepped back, bowed and commanded, “Mend
your ways, my king, while you still can.”</p>
<p>He stared at her in disbelief and shock.</p>
<p>Her facial expression softened and became compassionate, “You are
also a member of my flock. I know your pain. Filling the castle treasury
won't make up for the loss of your wife and daughter. Get to know your
people and serve them, as a good king should. Charity will mend your
heart better than greed.”</p>
<p>With that, she turned and quietly left, leaving the king with his
suddenly swirling thoughts and a jumble of conflicted feelings.</p>
<h1 id="tale-2-immovable">Tale 2 Immovable</h1>
<h2 id="chapter-1-noble-inquiry">Chapter 1 Noble Inquiry</h2>
<p>“Your letters of recommendation are impressive.” Lord Scaplin
remarked as he skimmed through the job applicant's papers.</p>
<p>“I suppose.”</p>
<p>The applicant was plainly dressed, appearing much like a typical
peasant, except for the fact he was quite muscular and very fit.
According to the papers he'd brought, he was actually a minor noble. He
was staring at a point a few inches above the nobleman's head and hadn't
blinked for the entire duration of the meeting.</p>
<p>“By everything in here, you're clearly qualified to be my guard
captain. You could easily do that job for the king!”</p>
<p>“Didn't want the job.” The fellow admitted.</p>
<p>The nobleman flipped through the letters again, finding one signed by
the king.</p>
<p>“Oh. He offered you the position, I see that now.”</p>
<p>The nobleman looked very confused. He stared at the applicant for
some time, working through the inconsistencies.</p>
<p>He couldn't puzzle it out, so he asked, “Why in the world are you
applying for a position as a common gate guard? You're clearly
overqualified.”</p>
<p>The man sighed, speaking as though he hardly cared about the result
of the meeting, “Do you want me for the job or not? I've got three other
interviews scheduled for today. You're just the first.”</p>
<p>The nobleman looked exasperated, having never dealt with such a
reversal in an interview, so he looked through the papers some more, “I
see your last employer was Lord Braden. Wasn't he killed by a robber in
the night, just last week?”</p>
<p>“Yes.”</p>
<p>“Where were you when this happened?”</p>
<p>“Wasn't my shift.”</p>
<p>The noble found the most recent letter, written by Lord Braden's
guard captain, praising the man's capability, wishing he'd been on duty
during the incident in question.</p>
<p>“Oh. I see. His guard captain wrote a letter, as well.” Lord Scaplin
muttered, after flipping though the papers, again.</p>
<p>“Yes.”</p>
<p>The noble sighed and asked again, “Why do you want to be a gate
guard?”</p>
<p>“Need a job.” The applicant spoke without emotion, “Have to eat and
pay rent.”</p>
<p>Lord Scaplin stared at the man for several long moments, who still
hadn't blinked. It was starting to make the noble's eyes water in
sympathy.</p>
<p><em>I'd be insane not to hire him, with these recommendations!</em>
He took a few moments to weigh his options, <em>He even comes at a
bargain price, but why does he want such a lowly job?</em></p>
<p>The noble made up his mind, “Consider yourself hired. When can you
begin?”</p>
<p>He handed back the letters of recommendation, keeping just the
resume.</p>
<p>The man folded them carefully into his jacket pocket, “I'm not busy
at the moment.”</p>
<p>Lord Scaplin sputtered at the proclamation and reverted to a
childhood stuttering habit briefly, before getting a hold of himself,
“T-Then report to my guard captain for your assignment.”</p>
<p>The man stood like a soldier and saluted, making the movements with
classic, textbook perfection as he stood to attention, speaking his
response in a fashion that would make the most insane drill sergeant
tearfully proud, “Yes, my lord!”</p>
<p>Having finished his salute, he marched out of the room.</p>
<hr />
<p>Lord Scaplin watched the new guard with unusual interest over the
next few weeks.</p>
<p>He did his duty to perfection, standing next to the front gate
through each day. He stood so motionless that the children in the
village thought the owner of the mansion awfully cheap for having bought
a statue of a guard, instead of hiring one!</p>
<p>Over the course of these weeks, it started to bother the nobleman,
like a nagging itch he couldn’t reach.</p>
<p>He approached his guard one afternoon and asked, “Are you satisfied
in your work?”</p>
<p>The man saluted, “It feeds me and pays my rent, sir.”</p>
<p>“And that's enough for you?”</p>
<p>“Yes, sir.”</p>
<p>This did not answer the noble's questions. It only brought more to
mind.</p>
<p>He decided on a new approach, “Are you happy?”</p>
<p>“No, sir.”</p>
<p>“Please elaborate on that.”</p>
<p>The man gave him a perplexed look and asked, “Is anyone, sir?”</p>
<p>“Very well, then tell me why you're here?”</p>
<p>“The pay, sir.” The guard spoke patiently, “It feeds me and pays my
rent.”</p>
<p>Lord Scaplin stared at the man for several minutes and then walked
inside, feeling frustrated.</p>
<hr />
<p>Lord Scaplin was in the home of an old friend, a minor noble by the
name of Jerome Attcombe. They were sharing drinks and talking about old
times at a school they'd attended together. It was just small talk,
however, and not the reason for the visit.</p>
<p>Eventually, Jerome asked, “So, now that we've gotten the polite
conversation out of the way, why are you here? You don't normally come
unless the king has an assignment for me.”</p>
<p>Lord Scaplin sighed in frustration, “It’s my newest guard. He used to
work for you.”</p>
<p>“I think I know who you're talking about.” Jerome laughed out loud,
“Collects recommendation letters from nobles like flies on a corpse,
right?”</p>
<p>“Y-Yes.”</p>
<p>“Fellow does his job perfectly in every detail, right?”</p>
<p>“Yes.”</p>
<p>“And you can't stand it, because he's qualified enough to be your
guard captain, but just wants to be a gate guard?”</p>
<p>“Yes!” Lord Scaplin nearly shouted.</p>
<p>Jerome laughed again, “Don't worry about him. Just be glad you've got
him. He's the best guard you'll ever have.”</p>
<p>Lord Scaplin fell back in his chair, frustrated, “Don't you know
anything about him?”</p>
<p>Jerome nodded, “You must have skipped reading his military service
record.”</p>
<p>“What was in it?”</p>
<p>Jerome looked out the window, a sad expression on his face, “You
remember that little skirmish we had just five years ago?”</p>
<p>“Our neighbor to the north invaded and the king sent his personal
regiment.”</p>
<p>“Your new guard was the leader of that regiment.”</p>
<p>“What happened to him out there?”</p>
<p>“Nothing in particular. It’s what happened while he was away...”</p>
<h2 id="chapter-2-fires-of-hearth-and-home">Chapter 2 Fires of Hearth
and Home</h2>
<p>Royal Regiment Commander, Aaron Kozinski, was happy to be home. He'd
missed his wife and daughter while he'd been away. He was proud to have
served his king so well in the past few weeks, but it was good to be
going home. He and his men were marching into the royal city, having
successfully repelled the invaders.</p>
<p>He looked across the city at the setting sun, seeing too much smoke!
Despite how tired they were from a long day's march, he ordered an
increase to their pace and directed his into the city, toward the
closest fire! They soon had the fire out and then he split his men into
multiple groups, each with a task of organizing and supporting fire
brigades.</p>
<p>He looked at the plumes of smoke again, trying to determine which was
the biggest. That's when he noticed one of the smallest, coming from his
own neighborhood!</p>
<p>He organized the last of his men, ordering them toward the biggest
fires. Then, quite unusually for him, he left them to work, running as
hard as he could for his own home, praying he was wrong!</p>
<p>He got there and found the smoke rising from the area of his home! He
ran on, accelerating down his own street, seeing the distant, grand home
his king had given him, smoke rising from one side!</p>
<p>He found the peasants of the area running a bucket brigade through
his front door.</p>
<p>One of them recognized him and removed his hat, solemnly, “Sorry. We
did our best.”</p>
<p>He demanded, not as a noble, not as the Royal Regiment Commander, but
as a husband and father, every inch of him filled with trepidation, “Is
my family safe?”</p>
<p>Several more peasants removed their hats, looking down. Some of the
women began to cry.</p>
<p>“We're sorry. We...didn't get here in time.”</p>
<p>Not wanting to believe it, Aaron rushed into his home, pushing aside
peasants carrying buckets! He ran for the wing of the house with the
family bedrooms, the same side that burned. He pushed people out of the
way until he found his wife, now barely recognizable. He cradled her in
his arms, begging her to wake.</p>
<hr />
<p>Jerome finished the sad story, “According to the investigation, an
arsonist set fire to the homes of several nobles. His home happened to
be one of them.</p>
<p>“The man resigned the next day, unwilling to explain his reasons. Out
of respect and a sense of responsibility, the king gave him a glowing
letter of recommendation.</p>
<p>“From what I'm told, the incident still weighs heavily on the king's
mind. He blames himself for diverting his personal regiment away from
their normal duty of patrolling the city.”</p>
<p>Lord Scaplin nodded, “If the man had been home, his family would have
been safe. I can understand why he resigned.”</p>
<p>“Having read all of this, I thought him a broken shell of a man.”
Jerome finished, “I initially gave him the job out of pity, to help him
get back on his feet. I was as wrong as I could be. He does his job to
absolute perfection, then goes home to a rented room, just to sleep.
Most of his pay goes to widows and orphans of his old regiment, aside
from what he spends on food and rent.”</p>
<p>“How do you know that?”</p>
<p>“I hired an investigator to follow him for a few weeks, because it
started to bother me, just like you.”</p>
<p>Lord Scaplin was silent for a long while, finished his drink and
asked, “You trust the man?”</p>
<p>“Absolutely.”</p>
<p>Jerome poured his friend another glass of brandy and started another
tale.</p>
<h2 id="chapter-3-attention-to-duty">Chapter 3 Attention to Duty</h2>
<p>Aaron stood to attention in the pouring rain, staring forward. In
deference to the weather, he was wearing a heavy oilskin cloak, which
had been issued along with his armor and uniform. The other guards
retreated indoors, to warm themselves by the fire of the gatehouse. He'd
volunteered to stand guard, because their job required at least one of
them to be at the gate, ready to greet visitors or trouble-makers at all
hours, regardless of the weather.</p>
<p>The rain poured down the hood of his cloak as he stared straight
ahead, into the darkness.</p>
<p>Using instincts he'd honed patrolling the streets of the city, Aaron
caught just the smallest reflection of light out of place in the rain as
an object flew through the air, targeted at his neck! His sword was up
in a flash, blocking a tiny dart, which clattered to the
cobblestones!</p>
<p>His eyes quickly scanned the rooftops, looking for the source! Two
more darts flew in rapid succession, one deflected by his sword and the
other by his shield!</p>
<p>He caught a small movement as two individuals dressed in black
stealthily dropped from a roof, into the shadows of an alley.</p>
<p>He'd long known that assassins should know better than to wear pure
black. It always made a darker impression in the pit of a shadow, but
there were always plenty of talented amateurs that didn't know better.
Black, however, did work against most guards. Still, they should have
been wearing dark green or a nearly-black red.</p>
<p>He watched as one of them raised a bow. He examined the angle and
stood motionless as an arrow stuck the wall beside him. The other
assassin raised a bow and fired, aiming directly at him! Aaron raised
his shield, deflecting it expertly.</p>
<p>He called into the pouring rain, “Guards! To attention!”</p>
<p>His voice was nearly lost in the pouring rain, even to him. Leaving
his post to warn the others would likely allow them to sneak past him,
beyond the wall, so her stayed put.</p>
<p>Aaron twisted his neck a few times, while keeping his eyes on target,
limbering up. He followed by stretching his limbs, as well. As he did
so, another arrow was fired. He deftly leaned forward and the arrow
passed over him!</p>
<p>Wanting to get the conflict over with, Aaron stepped directly in
front of the gate and gestured with the middle finger of his sword hand
for his assailants to meet him head-on, finishing by leaving it raised
and still, taunting them.</p>
<p>One of the dark figures rushed forward, foolishly. This one was
clearly young, brash and overconfident, armed with a sword just long
enough to not be considered a knife. He was wearing black leather armor
and his head was wrapped in black cloth.</p>
<p>Just as the young man was about to attack, Aaron stepped into the
assault, parrying with his own sword! The young man was off-balance,
having tried to put too much force into the attack. His face was met by
Aaron's shield, ringing fairly loudly, despite the rain! The man fell
back, limp, out cold.</p>
<p>Aaron stepped back to his chosen position and stared directly at the
other assailant. He started ramming the hilt of his sword into his
shield, to make as much noise as possible. It didn't carry very far in
the pouring rain.</p>
<p>He deflected two more arrows with his shield, before the other one
stepped out of hiding, calmly starting across the street.</p>
<p>The assassin was dressed similar to his companion, but his eyes were
visible through a slit in the cloth. They looked each other in the eye.
Clearly, Aaron was looking into the eyes of a killer, one with a great
deal of experience. Having taken the assassin's measure, he was sure it
a man, rather than a woman. It made a difference; women lacked a common
vulnerability of men.</p>
<p>When they were twenty feet apart, the assassin called, barely heard
over the rain, “Leave and I won't kill you! Stay and your life is
forfeit!”</p>
<p>Aaron shrugged and call back, “You've got that backwards!”</p>
<p>The assassin threw three knives with each hand as he rushed in, each
expertly aimed for a vital organ! Aaron blocked two with his shield, two
with deft parries and then moved sideways for the last two!</p>
<p>As he closed the distance, the assassin drew a sword and a long
knife! He stood with his legs apart, for good balance.</p>
<p>Aaron deflected or parried all of the assassin's attacks and launched
into a deceptive series of attacks, taking the offensive, but always
seeming to come up short. With each attack, the assassin leaned just out
of reach. Aaron had him right where he wanted him, expecting only
attacks with his sword or shield.</p>
<p>Aaron telegraphed an attack with his sword, making it look like an
over-eager strike. The assassin leaned back and Aaron's armored foot
connected with the man's groin!</p>
<p>There was a groan of agony as the assassin collapsed. Aaron wasted no
time and quickly finished his dangerous opponent with a downward sword
thrust.</p>
<p>After carefully scanning the area for more opponents, he cleaned and
sheathed his sword. He grabbed the unconscious assassin. He carried them
to the guard room with one hand, kicked the door open and then roughly
dropped his prisoner at the feet of his stunned colleagues!</p>
<p>“Send a runner to the house. Alert all guards. We've got
trouble.”</p>
<p>He went back to his post.</p>
<hr />
<p>Jerome finished his story, “There were several more attacks that
night. Fortunately, thanks to Aaron, the rest of my guards were very
alert and ready for them. The unconscious assassin was handed over to
the royal regiment for interrogation. Turns out an old business rival
hired a clan of assassins, the Ashen Blades, to kill me. The regiment
literally knocked his door down, the next day, with a battering ram. He
was executed for his crime not long after.”</p>
<p>“Why did Aaron quit, if you were so satisfied with his work?” Lord
Scaplin asked.</p>
<p>“I did what anyone would have, after a night like that: I promoted
him! He quit the next day. My advice is to give him a raise instead of
promoting him, if you're ever in that position. He chose the job himself
and he must have his reasons, but he might accept higher pay as a reward
for good service. I'm honestly not even sure if he would care,
though.”</p>
<p>Lord Scaplin thanked his friend for the drinks and the stories, even
though they raised even more questions, while providing only precious
few answers.</p>
<hr />
<p>It wasn't long before Lord Scaplin called on Lady Audrey Bellany,
another of Aaron's previous employers.</p>
<p>After a few pleasantries, she asked, “To what do I owe the pleasure
of your company? It can't be that you've come courting, seeing as you're
married.”</p>
<p>“I recently hired a new guard. I'm trying to learn more about
him.”</p>
<p>“Mr. Kozinski, I presume.” She smirked at him.</p>
<p>“He's an enigma, I must admit.”</p>
<p>“You're lucky to have him. I pity the man for the loss of his family
and I admire his dedication to duty.”</p>
<p>Lord Scaplin asked, “Do you know why he insists on taking such lowly
jobs?”</p>
<p>“No, but it’s clearly related to the loss of his family. I did ask
him once, but he simply said, ‘A man needs to eat.’ I didn't believe
him, but I didn't want to press the point, either.”</p>
<p>“Can you at least tell me why he left your service?”</p>
<p>“The short version is that he did so for my safety and the safety of
everyone around him.”</p>
<p>“And the long version?”</p>
<p>She sighed, “That’s a story in and of itself...”</p>
<h2 id="chapter-4-ash-blood-pass">Chapter 4 Ash-Blood Pass</h2>
<p>Aaron stood beside the back gate on a summer afternoon, not moving,
staring straight ahead. The guard on the other side was sitting on the
ground and smoking, a habit that got him banned from working at the
front door and on probation. His shield was leaning against the
wall.</p>
<p>“Hey, statue, you want a smoke?” The slovenly guard asked.</p>
<p>Aaron didn't respond, simply continuing his vigil. After a lengthy
silence, he tossed his shield in the path of a projectile, saving his
comrade from death by crossbow!</p>
<p>Aaron dove right behind the shield, quickly scooped it up and brought
it to the proper position, the blocked bolt sticking out of it!</p>
<p>The slovenly guard screamed, the roll-up falling from his mouth. He
scrambled to pick up his shield and get his sword in hand as Aaron
blocked two more shots, both aimed at the lazy guard!</p>
<p>“Alert the others!” Aaron commanded.</p>
<p>The man was halfway to the house before he realized he was following
the order of someone he out-ranked! Still, it was the right thing to do,
both for their lady and his own safety! Another shot barely missed him
as he made his way to the house!</p>
<hr />
<p>Aaron took position at the center of the open gate.</p>
<p>He eyed the assailant, someone dressed in black perched on the
balcony of a nearby house, holding a crossbow. They were reloading to
make another shot.</p>
<p>Aaron knew the home. It belonged to a noble. The room itself belonged
to the man's young daughter. Clearly, it had been invaded to get a good
position to shoot from.</p>
<p>Two more shots in rapid succession revealed he was dealing with a
double crossbow, rather than two attackers. He easily blocked them.</p>
<p>Several guards arrived behind him, ready to back him up.</p>
<p>“Stay behind the walls!” He commanded with such absolute authority
that all the other guards, including the captain, obeyed without
thinking.</p>
<p>His timely words saved them from being hit as two more shots were
fired, missing one of them by inches! After a another pause to reload,
two more shots flew in, aimed at Aaron's feet! He leaped backward at
just the right moment!</p>
<p>He waited and stared the attacker right in the eye as they reloaded
and aimed. Aaron read their intent and blocked the next two with his
shield, both targeted at his head!</p>
<p>“You won't get me that way!” Aaron taunted, “Why don't you face me
like a man?”</p>
<p>The hollow laugh that came in response was unexpected, to say the
least. It was the laugh of a young woman.</p>
<p>“Man or woman, you won't take me down from a distance!”</p>
<p>The black-clad woman leaped down from the balcony, discarding her
crossbow in the same fluid movement, landing in the grass of the other
house’s yard as lightly as a cat.</p>
<p>Aaron barked, “Two guards, go and check on that house!”</p>
<p>One of the guards behind the wall responded to his order fairly
automatically, “Yes, sir!”</p>
<p>There was a bit of arguing and then the guard captain said, “I'll
take that under advisement, Mr. Kozinski!”</p>
<p>After some more muttering, two guards stepped past him and made their
way across the street. By this point, the assassin was into the
street.</p>
<p>Her attention was fixed on Aaron as she pulled off her mask,
revealing short, brown hair. She was attractive, but her expression was
of pure hatred, trying to burn holes through Aaron with her eyes
alone.</p>
<p>“Why are you here?” Aaron demanded.</p>
<p>“You killed my father! Until you're dead, the Ashen Blades will
target everyone around you, <em>especially</em> your employers!”</p>
<p>The woman rushed forward with a drawn sword, all caution thrown to
the wind and no attempt at defense even made. Aaron shook his head
slightly, braced himself for the attack and neatly positioned his sword
to skewer her as she approached, using her own momentum to drive the
blade through her chest. Through the bone-jarring impact, he kept his
footing. He withdrew his sword, dropping her to the ground.</p>
<p>She coughed a few times as she died, blood pouring from the wound and
her mouth. He wiped his sword clean on her clothes and sheathed it,
returning to his post.</p>
<p>The two guards returned and reported, “Everyone in the house is
dead!”</p>
<p>Aaron stared straight ahead. Two more attacks were aimed in his
direction that day, but neither was particularly effective. Each came
from a different house, each turning out to have been invaded, just to
get a good position to snipe from.</p>
<hr />
<p>The next morning Aaron showed up early, just to resign. Within the
hour, he paid the town crier to spread word he was leaving the city,
headed for Hallyson's Pass, a notoriously narrow path through the
mountains, impassible by cart or horse, but easy enough for a man on
foot.</p>
<p>He carried only a pack of provisions and camping supplies, a sword
and shield. He wore old regimental armor, a suit of plate mail.</p>
<p>After a day of indecision, Lady Bellany asked her guard captain to
organize and send a group of volunteers into the pass, to support
Aaron.</p>
<hr />
<p>The six volunteers, led by Lady Bellany's captain of the guard, were
each wearing their regular work attire: chain mail, sword and shield.
The captain had the double crossbow from the recent assassination
attempt strapped on his back. It was an evil device, with a cocking
mechanism that dramatically increased the strength that could be
applied, allowing even a small person to penetrate heavy armor.</p>
<p>The hike into the mountains took the better part of three days. Most
of Hallyson's Pass was little more than a deep, narrow canyon that wound
around at strange angles. However, there were wider areas, big enough to
use for camp sites. Every once in a while a small side canyon branched
off the main path, but most ended in a dead end. They got lost a few
times, having to backtrack to the main path.</p>
<p>The walls looked almost like someone painted them with a variety of
natural pigments, making horizontal lines at various heights, but that
was just layers of natural stone. Most of the canyon was a mixture of
reds and browns, with a nearly black line every so often. The lightest
colors were almost like cream. As the wind swept through, it brought the
smell of water, dirt and sand.</p>
<p>There was a little trickle of water flowing along the path; the
canyon had been carved by that stream, which turned into a deadly
torrent during storms.</p>
<p>On the third day, they began hearing sounds of fighting, echoing
through the canyon. It was impossible to tell how far away it was, but
almost as one man, the guards quickened their pace!</p>
<p>By mid-morning, they found the small stream tinged with blood,
becoming darker the farther they went.</p>
<p>Throughout the day they heard fighting, off and on. Each time, they
increased their pace, hoping to find Aaron around the next corner.</p>
<p>When noon came, they ate on the run, not wanting to stop for
lunch.</p>
<p>As they were eating and turning a corner, they came across a man
dressed in black, lying dead next to the stream at a natural pinch-point
in the canyon. While the dead man was contributing to the blood in the
stream, he was clearly not the only source, as the water was already red
by the time it reached him.</p>
<p>Within ten minutes they found another body, similarly dressed, with a
small section of the canyon wall collapsed on him. The area had clearly
been fairly narrow until the collapse.</p>
<p>The next group of bodies was three men, crammed into another choke
point, as though they'd died attempting to cross it. These had to be
removed before the guards could continue.</p>
<p>This pattern persisted. With each defensible location was a small
pile of bodies. They stopped counting after about twenty corpses, but
there were dozens more.</p>
<p>By late afternoon, they heard fighting again, so they sped onward,
running as fast as safety allowed in the narrow canyon! This time, the
fighting sounded much closer!</p>
<p>As the first of them turned a corner, there was a group of six
black-clad men, attempting to get into a side canyon! At their feet were
several more, dead. Aaron was just beyond the entrance, forcing them to
come at him one at a time.</p>
<p>Aaron's sword thrust through the gut of his current opponent,
protruding out the left side of the man's torso! With a swift kick, he
dislodged his blade just in time to be ready for his next opponent!</p>
<p>The captain readied his crossbow, took aim and launched a bolt into
one of Aaron's tormentors, going through his bicep and between his ribs,
puncturing a lung! He quickly aimed at another and fired, putting the
bolt in the man's temple, killing him nearly instantly!</p>
<p>As he dropped the bow and drew his sword, he called to his men,
“Attack!”</p>
<p>The ensuing battle was short and bloody, but the guards came out on
top. Aaron finished two of them himself, while the remaining two gave
the guards some serious trouble. The assassins were each skilled
fighters, but were soon outflanked and fighting back to back,
overwhelmed. With three opponents each, skill just wasn't enough to save
them!</p>
<p>Each of the guards was wounded, but when the captain surveyed his
men, he was happy to see none of the wounds were serious.</p>
<p>Limping a bit from a bad bruise to his leg, the captain made his way
toward Aaron and was quite surprised to find himself hastily parrying an
expertly-aimed attack, going straight for his jugular!</p>
<p>As he stumbled over a corpse, tripping and falling back, he saw the
look in Aaron's eyes. He was long past exhaustion and likely didn't even
know what was going on, running on pure combat instinct and
adrenaline!</p>
<p>As Aaron aimed a deadly strike his way, his mind worked like
lightning!</p>
<p>He raised his shield and shouted, “Kozinski! Present arms!”</p>
<p>The blade stopped just half an inch from the captain's eye!</p>
<p>Despite how exhausted he was, Aaron responded to the voice of proper
authority. He clearly obeyed without thought, presenting his weapons as
though on parade and his posture became perfectly straight. Even now,
his form was picture-perfect. The scene was rather spoiled by the fact
that the man, his armor and his weapons were all covered in blood, dirt
and sand, the reek of death and sweat wafting from him.</p>
<p>One of the men behind the captain commented, “He is human?”</p>
<p>The source of this comment was quickly shushed and smacked.</p>
<p>The captain stood, brushed himself off and ordered, “Stand at ease,
Mr. Kozinski!”</p>
<p>Aaron finally snapped out of it, looking around himself as though
he'd lost track of where he was and what was going on. He lost his
balance and started to fall to one side.</p>
<p>The captain rushed forward, catching him, “I've got you. You're
safe.”</p>
<p>Aaron was already unconscious.</p>
<hr />
<p>Aaron woke to the magnificent sound and smell of sizzling bacon. His
stomach rumbled, the most emotional response any of the guards had ever
seen from the man.</p>
<p>The sun was directly over the canyon, noon being the only time of day
that allowed direct light. They were in the small side canyon in which
Aaron had made his stand, but the guards had moved the bodies downwind,
to improve the smell of the area.</p>
<p>Without a word, he was quickly fed strip after strip of bacon, then
some cheese and finally about half a loaf of bread. This was
interspersed with several long pulls from a water skin.</p>
<p>With his hunger satisfied, he asked, “How long was I out?”</p>
<p>“Eighteen hours.” The captain said with some concern, “How long were
you fighting before we showed up?”</p>
<p>“They came at me in the dark, hit and run. I fought them at choke
points. When I got here, I knew I could hold the line. They kept at it
for at least six hours after that, rotating so each could rest. Thanks
for the help. Any of them left?”</p>
<p>“Not that we can tell. We've been vigilant.”</p>
<p>Aaron looked himself over. His armor had been removed and cleaned. He
was bandaged in a few places where the joints of the armor allowed
weapons to graze him, but on the whole, he was in better shape than the
guards, one of which was dealing with a nasty stab wound in his leg.</p>
<p>Aaron stood, walked over to the man with the stab wound and took a
good look. He wouldn't be walking any time soon, but he knew a few
things that would prevent the inevitable infection. He soon found his
pack and pulled out some first-aid supplies and a small bottle of
brandy.</p>
<p>Thinking it was for him to drink, the guard held out a hand for the
bottle.</p>
<p>First cleaning a needle and thread with the alcohol, Aaron said,
“This is going to hurt.”</p>
<p>He poured some of it into the wound. The guard cried out in pain as
Aaron worked to sew the wound shut. When he was done, he applied a fresh
bandage.</p>
<p>He handed the bottle to the man and advised, “Clean it with this,
daily. It’s not for drinking.”</p>
<p>The captain wondered aloud, “Where did you learn to do that?”</p>
<p>As Aaron sat down to rest for a bit more, he replied, “Had a really
good sawbones in my regiment, once. Said the best way to save a wounded
limb was to keep things clean. Said brandy was about the best thing for
cleaning a wound with. After I saw him save a few good men from losing a
limb, I had him train all my men.”</p>
<p>“What regiment?”</p>
<p>Aaron shook his head, “Just look at my armor.”</p>
<hr />
<p>The captain examined the armor closely and recognized the marks of a
royal guardsman. He felt extremely foolish for not having realized it
sooner, but the last time he'd paid attention to the armor, it had been
soaked in blood.</p>
<p>Turning back to Aaron, he demanded, “Why in the world were you
serving as a gate guard?”</p>
<p>Aaron sighed, “Man's gotta eat.”</p>
<p>“True, but why aren't you doing something more important?”</p>
<p>Aaron redirected, “Why aren't you? You're good at your job and you
care for your men. You could be in my old regiment if you wanted.”</p>
<p>“I didn't think the king would hire a commoner for his personal
regiment.”</p>
<p>Aaron nodded, “Used to be the case, yes, but not in recent years.
When we get back, I'll write you a letter. You can take it to the king's
steward.”</p>
<hr />
<p>The captain was so dumbfounded, he’d forgot his question, just as
Aaron intended.</p>
<p>After another day of rest, the group headed back the way they'd come,
with Aaron in the lead. Vultures were all over the canyon as they
walked, working overtime to clean up the mess.</p>
<hr />
<p>Lady Bellany finished, “After that, the Ashen Blades were no more and
Hallyson's Pass was renamed Ash-Blood Pass. Personally, I consider the
new name to be remarkably poor taste, but it was quite some time before
the bones washed out completely.</p>
<p>“It wasn't long before my guard captain was invited to join the
king's regiment. Seems Aaron took a liking to the man and recommended
him to the king. I wholeheartedly agreed with that assessment, but was
sad to lose such a capable captain.”</p>
<p>Lord Scaplin sighed, “The more questions I ask about Aaron Kozinski,
the more I learn of his impeccable character, but no one seems to know
what motivates him.”</p>
<p>“Why does it matter to you so much? Isn't it enough to know you can
trust him?”</p>
<p>“How can I trust a man that refuses to tell me why he works for
peanuts at the lowliest job he can find? I need to know!”</p>
<p>The Lady smiled and chuckled a little, “Don't let it bother you. The
king himself vouched for his character, as you well know. Just be
grateful you've got him.”</p>
<p>He sighed again, “You're right, of course. You're absolutely
right.”</p>
<h2 id="chapter-5-noble-demand">Chapter 5 Noble Demand</h2>
<p>The meeting came to a close and he headed home, resolving to take her
advice. As his coach passed through the front gate, with Aaron at his
post in his usual motionless pose, the puzzle began to nag him again. He
couldn't just let it lie.</p>
<p>Once the coach was parked, he stepped out and headed straight to the
gate.</p>
<p>Aaron saluted.</p>
<p>Lord Scaplin demanded, quite flustered, “Why? Why are you content to
work as a gate guard?”</p>
<p>Aaron gave his usual response, “It feeds me and pays my rent,
sir.”</p>
<p>“I don't believe you! You could be doing something important! Why
this, in particular?”</p>
<p>Aaron shrugged, “Why not?”</p>
<p>Lord Scaplin stared hard at the man for close to two minutes and a
new approach occurred to him, “I order you to tell me the truth about
why you're working as a gate guard!”</p>
<p>Aaron's normally expressionless face twisted into a wince, as if he’d
been slapped. He didn't respond for a long moment.</p>
<p>Lord Scaplin demanded, “Well? What have you to say for yourself?”</p>
<p>Aaron's face returned to normal, “I refuse to answer. Sir, I'm afraid
that I must inform you of my intention to resign.”</p>
<p>More quietly and calmly, Lord Scaplin asked, “On what grounds?”</p>
<p>“Invasion of my privacy, sir.”</p>
<p>Lord Scaplin's jaw dropped, but he soon closed it, “I apologize and I
understand.”</p>
<p>With a final salute, Aaron left his post and heading for the guard
captain's office, to turn in his uniform and equipment.</p>
<p>Lord Scaplin felt extremely foolish for his actions, but in a strange
way, also relieved. The puzzle of Aaron Kozinski was no longer his
problem. Before Aaron left, he gave him a letter of recommendation to
add to his collection, for he truly had great respect for the man. No
previous guard had behaved so well during long hours at their post.</p>
<h1 id="tale-3-collision">Tale 3 Collision</h1>
<h2 id="chapter-1-gainful-employment">Chapter 1 Gainful Employment</h2>
<p>As Aaron walked home that day, he was approached by a small man
dressed in fine clothes. He had naturally curled brown hair.</p>
<p>“Good afternoon!” The young man called to him.</p>
<p>Aaron nodded.</p>
<p>“Since you're walking the street instead of guarding Lord Scaplin's
front gate, would I be right in guessing you've quit left his
employ?”</p>
<p>Aaron nodded, “Yes.”</p>
<p>“Are you looking for a new gate to guard?”</p>
<p>“I suppose.”</p>
<p>“Why don't you guard my front door? I've heard nothing but good
things about you! I've been green with envy that Lord Scaplin managed to
hire you!”</p>
<p>“I'll consider it. Your name, please?”</p>
<p>The man bowed, “Marcus Rawlings. I run a very <em>exclusive</em>
gentleman's club and could use a good man for the door.”</p>
<p>Aaron talked it over with him, listening for any downside. The pay
was good, he'd be doing some reasonably important work, protecting the
club's clients, mostly nobles, and most important of all, his
responsibility was simply to guard the door.</p>
<p>“I’ll take the job.” Aaron informed his new employer, who eagerly led
him away, to see the door he would be guarding.</p>
<h2 id="chapter-2-the-would-be-kidnapper">Chapter 2 The Would-Be
Kidnapper</h2>
<p>The priestess leaned over a man lying on his belly, as she changed a
bandage on a his back. The wound was from a particularly nasty scythe
accident and had left him unable to work, due to both the injury and the
resulting fever. The infection was gone and the wound was finally
healing nicely. She was grateful she wouldn't have to call on the doctor
again. There would still be some pretty bad scarring, but he was out of
the woods, after months of care.</p>
<p>She stood, straightened her spine and declared, “I'm done for today.
You're healing well, I'm glad to say. Get some more rest.”</p>
<p>He thanked her.</p>
<p>She stepped out of the sick room where she cared for those with no
one else to care for them. The main hall of the modest temple was small,
with just a few pews for services.</p>
<p>She reflected on the king's change of heart so many years before,
when she'd chastised him for his greed. Within a few years he actually
came to her, in person, to thank her. It was incredible to see the
growth in the man as he looked to his people's needs and did his best to
care for them, in an almost fatherly fashion, treating his people as
though they were the child he’d lost.</p>
<p>Eventually, the king offered to fund the construction of a grand
temple. The priestess thanked him, asked for just enough to build a
small temple and insisted he use the rest of the money to serve the
poor.</p>
<p>It was a happy day for the kingdom when he remarried. The priestess
had officiated, in the very temple she was stood in.</p>
<p>She rubbed her aching back. Stooping so long to take care of that man
on a daily basis was beginning to give her trouble with her own body.
Still, she didn't want to complain; others had it worse.</p>
<p>She crossed the hall and entered her private quarters. There was a
full-size standing mirror there, a gift from the king. She glanced at
her reflection briefly. She was getting older, her blonde hair beginning
to lose all color. She still wore it short, though. Long hair was a
bother when she was working, so she'd always kept it short.</p>
<p>Her plain, white robe was one of the simple, practical ones she
always wore while working. It was both something to wear and a source of
emergency bandages. She wore an extra-long one just for that reason. She
had better robes, but they were for ceremonial occasions and she didn't
like wearing them, anyway.</p>
<p>She mused to herself that she needed an apprentice, to take her place
when she died, but she figured there was plenty of time for that to be
arranged.</p>
<p>Just as she was about to sit down and read a book on medicinal herbs,
the outer doors of the temple opened.</p>
<p>Someone cried out, “Sister! We need you!”</p>
<p>She could hear the fear pouring out of the young woman's voice.</p>
<p>“What is it?” The priestess shouted as she quickly made her way back
into the hall!</p>
<p>“Strangers in the village, stealing children!”</p>
<p>The priestess ran down the hall and accelerated past the upset young
woman! The two of them raced to the village as fast as possible!</p>
<p>Unfortunately, the priestess had to stop for a breather, halfway
there. In retrospect, she wished she'd accepted the king's offer of a
horse and stable for the temple. At the time, she'd been a bit younger
and with no aches in her back. Now, it seemed a reasonable
suggestion.</p>
<p>When they arrived, she found a group of masked men beating one of the
village men! Behind them was a cart full of children from the
village!</p>
<p>She rushed forward, diving in the path of a kick, aiming to take the
blow in the crotch! The attacker fell back, clutching his family jewels
in pain!</p>
<p>The priestess grimaced, but got to her feet, standing between the man
and his attackers.</p>
<p>One of them swung a mace at her and she put her face in its path. The
mace-wielder fell back with a badly-bleeding shattered nose!</p>
<p>Next was a short sword, jabbed in her direction! She blocked with her
bare hand, leaving the man bleeding from his sword hand!</p>
<p>She stood her ground and shrugged off the momentary pain of their
wounds. Having seen three men attack her, only to injure themselves, the
others gave her a wide berth.</p>
<p>“Just what in the world is going on here?” She demanded.</p>
<p>One of the men at the back of the cart, not having seen the
commotion, raised a crossbow and fired. The priestess was hit in the
gut, but the bolt simply bounced off. The crossbow wielder dropped his
weapon and screamed in pain!</p>
<p>She dropped to her knees, having failed to notice the man fire. When
she recovered, she got back on her feet and slapped her way through the
crowd of kidnappers toward the cart! As each of them attacked, they fell
back, suffering the wounds they would have inflicted on her! She barely
twitched with the pain of each strike.</p>
<p>She pushed several of the masked men aside and shouted to the
children, “Get back to your parents! I'll keep them busy!”</p>
<p>The children leaped from the cart and bolted in all directions as
soon as they were safely away! The priestess smiled in grim
satisfaction.</p>
<p>She ran into the group of kidnappers, wildly kicking, punching and
screaming defiance! The masked men were soon a mass of confusion and
chaos! They tried to stop her, but to no avail!</p>
<p>The distraction was complete. Armed villagers began showing up on the
edges of the scene, carrying scythes, sickles, pitchforks and other
tools that could easily be used as weapons.</p>
<p>When she finally stopped fighting and stepped out of the melee, they
were surrounded by angry villagers!</p>
<p>“Thank you, sister.” The mayor said as she stepped beside him.</p>
<p>The kidnappers were soon rounded up and their wounds tended. They
were herded, at the point of farm implements, to a barn that would serve
as a make-shift prison for the day or two it would take to get some
law-men to take them away. The mask was pulled from each as their hands
were bound.</p>
<p>However, just before he was disarmed and unmasked, one of the men
managed to slip away, running much faster than anyone could follow! As
the men of the village tried to tackle him, he stabbed two of them with
the pair of matched daggers he wielded!</p>
<p>The priestess watched as he crested a small hill and looked back,
straight at her. He removed his mask, giving everyone a good look at his
features. He was young, with naturally curly brown hair.</p>
<p>Without taking his eyes off her, he bowed as a taunt and then ran.
When the men following him reached the top of the hill, he was long
gone. Beyond the hill was a thick forest, where it would be easy to
escape. The men searched until late evening, but to no avail.</p>
<p>After everything was over, the priestess held a meeting, where
everyone shared what they could remember of what the man looked like. By
the end of the day, she had two copies of a good drawing of the man.</p>
<p>Questioning revealed the men were mercenaries and the man that
escaped was their employer. None knew why the man wanted a wagon full of
children.</p>
<p>When the law men came, one copy of the drawing was given to them, but
the priestess knew that would do no good. It was rare for such an
incident to result in an arrest, unless they were caught red-handed.
There just weren't enough law men to go around.</p>
<h2 id="chapter-3-bar-breaker">Chapter 3 Bar Breaker</h2>
<p>It had been years since the priestess entered the royal city. The
last visit had been to meet and bless the royal couple's first-born.</p>
<p>She didn't like the city. It was too big, but these days there were
other priests of her religion to look after the larger flock. She
preferred her small, rural flock, where it was still possible to learn
and remember everyone's name.</p>
<p>She knew she'd likely be gone for quite some time, so she left her
patient in the hands of the women of the village. With any luck, that
would lead to the poor man finding a wife.</p>
<p>She started her investigation by visiting a local law man, one of
those that came to the village for the mercenaries, gaining a promise to
hold the suspect for an inquiry if she brought him in and an apology
that he couldn't do more. After a long discussion of where to begin her
search for the ring-leader, she made her way to the seedier section of
the city. She showed the drawing to the ruffians on the street, with
little success.</p>
<p>Around mid-afternoon on the third day, a huge man, just shy of seven
feet tall, carrying a rather large club, approached her and declared,
loudly, “You the lady been askin' 'bout the boss? He be angry you
askin'!”</p>
<p>She grinned, “Maybe I am, maybe I'm not.” She held up the drawing and
asked, “Is this the boss?”</p>
<p>The brute squinted at the drawing and stupidly smiled, “Yeah, dat's
him!”</p>
<p>“Thank you.” She laughed in his face, “Where can I find him?”</p>
<p>The brute looked confused for a moment as he took the time to
perform, what was for him, the very difficult task of thinking.</p>
<p>He arrived at a shaky conclusion, “Hey! You trick me!”</p>
<p>The brute's club was swung overhead, in both hands! She calmly
reached up and blocked the incredible blow with her right forearm. She
felt the pain of the break as she heard the brute's bones crack!</p>
<p>He roared in pain, his badly-damaged arm dropping to his side, parts
of it moving at unnatural angles. He still held the club in the other
hand and raised it for another strike!</p>
<p>Not wishing to see the man lose the use of his other arm, she dodged
and shouted, “Do you want another broken arm?”</p>
<p>It did no good as the man screamed in blind rage and attacked again.
She blocked with the other arm, wincing from the pain as she saw the
man's arm collapse! The club tumbled away, rolling into the gutter.</p>
<p>There were a number of people on the street that took notice of the
biggest bully around, seemingly beaten by a small woman. Two dirty
street children, a boy and a girl, picked up the club and ran away down
an alley. She wasn't sure of the significance of this, but her attention
was focused on the man before her, who wouldn't even be able to feed
himself.</p>
<p>He dropped to the pavement, wailing like an extremely large, injured
toddler!</p>
<p>She knelt beside him and put a hand on his shoulder. She willed most
of the pain into herself, leaving just enough that the foolish man
wouldn't hurt himself further.</p>
<p>She spoke soothing words and helped him to stand, keeping a hand on
him at all times, to take the pain.</p>
<p>From one of the astonished on-lookers, she demanded, “Where's the
nearest doctor?”</p>
<p>At this point, she realized everyone on the street was staring.
Several of them pointed just down the street, where there was actually a
small, wooden sign of a saw crossed over a bone. She'd never actually
seen a doctor advertise themselves as a sawbones. That was usually an
insult laid on them by others.</p>
<p>She walked the blubbering man into the clinic.</p>
<p>Someone male screamed, “Bar Breaker, you know you're not welcome
here!”</p>
<p>The priestess moved around to the front of the large man and
explained as she maneuvered him to an open bed, “I'm sorry. You just
happened to be the nearest doctor and this foolish man just broke both
his arms attacking me.”</p>
<p>She finally got a good look at the doctor and the room.</p>
<p>He was middle-aged, his hair starting to gray and wearing a
short-sleeved white shirt, a black tie and a black apron. He looked more
like a mortician than a doctor.</p>
<p>The room had four sick beds and a small desk at the back. Behind the
desk was a small surgical room beyond an archway and a set of stairs
that probably led to the doctor's bedroom. There was a very chemical
smell in the room.</p>
<p>He sighed, “Very well. Will someone be paying for his treatment or is
this supposed to be free?”</p>
<p>With her other hand, the priestess removed a few gold from her
coin-purse and tossed them to the man, “Will that do for a start?”</p>
<p>He grumbled a bit, but got to work, setting and splinting the huge
man's broken forearms; one gold would have been far more than required,
but she’d been impatient and wanted the doctor to stop complaining.</p>
<p>As he worked, the doctor volunteered, “Everyone around here calls me
Doc, but I'd prefer to be called Dr. Petrov.”</p>
<p>She shrugged, “I'm afraid I gave up my name in the service of my god,
long ago. You can call me 'sister', but it’s more an honorific than a
name.”</p>
<p>With a hint of recognition in his eyes and a glance at the way she
was keeping a hand on Bar Breaker, he commented, “You're one of those
empathy priests, aren't you?”</p>
<p>She nodded, “The fool hit me with a club, twice. That wasn't a wise
thing to do. Could have been worse, though. Someone tried to cut my head
off, once.”</p>
<p>The doctor blanched, “Those who don't learn from their mistakes
sometimes don't get the chance to repeat them.”</p>
<p>As Dr. Petrov completed his work, he injected the large man and then
said, “You can let go in a moment. He'll be out for hours. When he comes
to, I'll give him something for the pain.”</p>
<p>Within a minute, the huge man was snoring quite loudly, sounding
something like an industrial accident in progress. The doctor lifted his
patient's head, turned it to one side and tucked a pillow under it,
somewhat reducing the volume of the snore.</p>
<p>He headed toward his desk, gestured for her to sit in one of the
chairs in front of it and sat down behind it. As she tried to get
comfortable on the worn-out seat, he handed back the coins she'd given
him.</p>
<p>He answered her quizzical expression by explaining, “I've thought it
over. Keep your money. It’s more than worth it to see Bar Breaker off
the street for a while, since he causes so many injuries.”</p>
<p>She nodded, “Hopefully, he'll learn something from this.”</p>
<p>“Probably not,” he chuckled, “but at least he won't be hurting anyone
for a few months. So, what brings you to our little slice of
heaven?”</p>
<p>She produced the now-battered drawing of the man she was searching
for from a pocket and smoothed it out on the desk, “I'm looking for this
man. Bar Breaker called him 'the boss.' He hired mercenaries to kidnap
children from my village.”</p>
<p>The doctor looked the picture over and scratched his stubbly chin, “I
know I've seen him around, but I can't quite place where.”</p>
<p>She sighed, “I was hoping to question our large friend, but I'm not
sure he would be willing to help. He attacked when I asked where I could
find the man.”</p>
<p>The doctor smiled, “People around here aren't usually helpful to
outsiders, even if they could be, but I think everyone on the street
knows you just took down Bar Breaker. He's feared on the streets as a
malicious thug for hire. There should be more than enough good-will for
you out there. Try asking again.”</p>
<p>She nodded as she rose and shook his hand, “Thank you.”</p>
<p>Unfortunately, she had no luck the rest of that day, but she did
notice that most of the people she met smiled at her and now greeted her
warmly, while the ruffians on the street shied away, fearfully.</p>
<h2 id="chapter-4-a-lovely-meeting">Chapter 4 A Lovely Meeting</h2>
<p>As the priestess walked the streets the next day, she saw a pair of
dirty children, a boy and a girl. She recognized them as the pair that
ran off with Bar Breaker's club. They were lurking at the edge of an
alley.</p>
<p>“Hey! Lady!” The girl called out, smiling.</p>
<p>She made her way over and asked, “Yes?”</p>
<p>The pair were not more than twelve years old and looked about the
same age. They shared the same shade of black hair and had more than a
passing resemblance, causing her to guess they were twins. They wore
rags that barely qualified as clothes.</p>
<p>“You're looking for somebody, right?” The girl asked.</p>
<p>She nodded, “Yes, I am.”</p>
<p>She showed them the drawing and the girl shrugged, “I don't know him,
but I know someone that should.”</p>
<p>“Oh?”</p>
<p>The boy sighed, “Follow me. Our boss seemed pretty happy about what
you did to Bar Breaker, so I think he'll help you find that guy.”</p>
<p>The pair led her down a fairly direct route that passed through
various streets, alleys and briefly, the back of a blacksmith's shop,
eventually arriving at a decrepit warehouse that seemed to be a
squatter's camp.</p>
<p>There was a man there, sitting on a wooden crate. His head was shaved
and he bore a tattoo of an eagle on his scalp, with the wings coming
down the sides of his head, just like sideburns, with the beak coming to
a point on his forehead. The eagle's eyes seemed to meet a person's
gaze, regardless of the angle. If the man grew his hair out, it looked
like the whole thing would vanish into it.</p>
<p>As he looked up, he asked, “Would you be the woman that took down Bar
Breaker?”</p>
<p>She shrugged, “I suppose I am.”</p>
<p>He grinned wide, revealing a number of gold teeth, “You have my
thanks. You still looking for his boss?”</p>
<p>“He tried to kidnap some children from my village. I plan to bring
him to justice.” She explained.</p>
<p>He grinned evilly, “Then that makes us friends!”</p>
<p>“How do you figure?”</p>
<p>“The enemy of my enemy is my friend!” He laughed, “He's been a thorn
in my side for the past ten years. I'd love to see him at the
gallows!”</p>
<p>“Where can I find him?”</p>
<p>He pulled a small scrap of grubby paper from a pocket, tore off an
unused section wrote on it with a piece of charcoal and handed it over,
“He frequents a gentleman's club at that address. Good hunting!”</p>
<p>She bowed, thanked him and headed back to the inn she was staying in,
where she had a map of the city, since she didn't recognize the name of
the street.</p>
<hr />
<p>When the priestess was long gone, the man stopped grinning and said
to the children, “Why do you think Marcus wanted us to send her straight
to him? We could have sent her somewhere dangerous.”</p>
<p>The boy sighed, “Marcus has a mind like a bag full of angry
cats.”</p>
<p>“It’s probably a trap.” The girl sported a wicked-looking grin of
mischief.</p>
<p>“He hired Bar Breaker to warn her off,” the man shrugged, “but also
hired us to send her straight there. Makes no sense.”</p>
<p>“Is it any of our business?” The boy sighed again, “He paid us to do
a job and we've done it. Can we get out of these awful clothes, now?
They itch.”</p>
<p>“You're right, of course. Let's head home. I’ll have the servants
draw you a nice, hot bath.”</p>
<hr />
<p>The priestess approached the club, named Rawlings', after its owner.
It was in one of the better neighborhoods, where all the houses had
guards. The building was red brick, with only very small windows on the
ground floor, about the same size as arrow slits on a castle. There was
a pair of double doors at the front, with a single guard on duty,
standing perfectly still, staring into space.</p>
<p>After half an hour of surreptitiously skulking around the building,
she discovered it once had a back entrance, but that was now blocked
with new bricks.</p>
<p>She watched the entrance for some time. Male nobles entered and
exited, as well as some servants, both male and female. It looked like
the only way a woman was allowed in was as a servant.</p>
<p>She decided to try the direct approach. She walked straight up to the
door, using the confidence that comes of being practically
untouchable.</p>
<p>As she came near the door, the guard, Aaron Kozinski, stepped neatly
in her path, blocking the way.</p>
<p>“Excuse me, young man, but I need to go in there.” She spoke
boldly.</p>
<p>Aaron finally looked her in the eye, “You don't work here and you're
not a gentleman, so you're definitely not a member.”</p>
<p>She backed away, out of his personal space, and pulled out the
drawing of the man she was looking for, “I need to find this man. I'm
told he frequents this club. Is he inside?”</p>
<p>Without even looking at the drawing, Aaron shrugged, “Couldn't tell
you.”</p>
<p>“Can't or won't?” She demanded.</p>
<p>“Both.”</p>
<p>“Why not?”</p>
<p>“I protect the club's clients. That includes their privacy.”</p>
<p>The priestess took a better look at the man. He was wearing chain
mail and a black and white striped tabard with the club's symbol on it,
a pair of crossed, black daggers. He also wore plate gauntlets and a
pair of heavy, plate boots. His helmet covered the top of his head and
had a nose guard, but left most of his face and neck exposed. He held a
round shield with the club's symbol and wore a sheathed sword on his
belt.</p>
<hr />
<p>With a brief flick of his eyes, Aaron assessed the threat the
priestess posed. She carried no weapons, but he recognized her robes.
She was an empath-priest. That would make it tricky to stop her, but not
impossible.</p>
<hr />
<p>She tried a new approach, not wanting to fight, “The man I'm looking
for tried to kidnap children from my village. I want to bring him to
justice.”</p>
<p>“Have you any proof?”</p>
<p>“My own word and the word of many of my village, as
eye-witnesses.”</p>
<p>“I'm just supposed to take your word for it?” The guard spoke without
a hint of emotion.</p>
<p>She tried several more arguments, but each was defeated by Aaron, who
was using impeccable, cold logic. She argued more heatedly. It was then
that a window on an upper floor was opened, making a loud squeak as the
old hinge was forced to work for the first time in years.</p>
<p>She looked up as a head poked out the window to look down at the both
of them. It was the man she was looking for! He even winked at her! She
was so shocked that she didn't say or do anything.</p>
<p>With a smug grin on his face, he called out, “Aaron, you having
trouble with her? Do you need some backup?”</p>
<p>Aaron called back, “No trouble, sir.”</p>
<p>“Carry on, then!”</p>
<p>The man disappeared back inside, accompanied by distant laughter, and
the squeaky hinge was forced to work in reverse.</p>
<p>The priestess finally recovered from the shock of seeing the man,
pointed at the window and shouted, “That was him!”</p>
<hr />
<p>Aaron remained silent. She still hadn't given him any proof.</p>
<p>She backed away, getting ready to charge. Seeing this, he drew his
sword. He didn't want to hurt her, but it was better to be ready for
anything.</p>
<p>She ran straight at him! Aaron braced for the impact and made no
hostile move. He brought his shield up at the last moment, putting it
right in the path of her face! He angled his sword in the same instant
to cut into her leg, careful to be certain the force of her impact was
what damaged her. If she was going to attack, then he was going to make
it hurt. The crunch of her nose breaking and the clang of her skull on
his shield echoed around the street! Blood poured from her leg around a
fresh hole in her robe, staining it!</p>
<p>Her momentum pushed her upward, over the shield, as her feet came off
the pavement! Aaron shoved her away, leaving her sprawled on the ground.
With his back already against the doors, the reverse force wasn't enough
to knock him down.</p>
<p>She groaned for a moment and slowly got into a sitting position. She
looked confused and probably had a concussion. She tore a bit of cloth
from the hem of her robe and bandaged her leg. She tore another strip
free to press to her nose.</p>
<p>Aaron assumed his usual stance, staring straight ahead. He didn't
move to his usual position at the side of the door, though. He cleaned
his sword with a cloth from his pocket and then sheathed it. He also
wiped the blood off his shield.</p>
<hr />
<p>After half an hour, the bleeding from the priestess’ nose finally
stopped and she got to her feet. She eyed her opponent. He was a smart
one and if she was to get past him, she needed to learn more about
him.</p>
<p>She limped forward, got right in his face and demanded, “Why are you
protecting him?”</p>
<p>“Why not? I've no proof he did anything.”</p>
<p>She flailed at the man with no force, simply trying to make
skin-to-skin contact. It wasn't an easy thing to do, since only his face
and neck were available. He blocked most of her strikes, but she managed
to touch his cheek with a single finger!</p>
<h2 id="chapter-5-the-price-of-empathy">Chapter 5 The Price of
Empathy</h2>
<p>Aaron held his dead wife. Hours passed and it was well into the
night. The last vestiges of the fire were out.</p>
<p>The peasants tried to get him to let her go several times, but he
snarled at them like an animal! Eventually, one of his lieutenants came
to see him, but had no success in reaching him. Finally, at nearly dawn,
the king arrived.</p>
<p>The king spoke firmly, as though giving a command, “Aaron, put her
down!” More calmly, he continued, “Let her go. She's already gone.”</p>
<p>Aaron trembled, clearly in conflict. He stopped trembling and put
down his wife. He looked at the king, a mixture of impotent rage and
duty on his face.</p>
<p>The king, quite unexpected, moved to the man and embraced him, “I'm
sorry. You should have been here. You should have been home.”</p>
<p>Aaron went limp in his king's arms, sobbing like a child.</p>
<hr />
<p>The mixture of conflicted grief, anger and duty hit the priestess
like an exploding mountain! The force of it was the single worst thing
she'd experienced in all her years as a priestess. The power of it
knocked her flat on her back!</p>
<p>Riding on the tail of it was a powerful wave of mind-numbing
apathy.</p>
<p>Beyond that was duty, filling the man's mind from one mental horizon
to the other. As the duty filled every nook and cranny, a fresh wave of
apathy washed over it and the two layered together, almost as one,
single emotion. His duty was, miraculously, being fed by his apathy. His
apathy was, in turn, feeding on his duty.</p>
<p>There were no vulnerabilities in that armor, no chinks. The man would
never budge, would never falter, would never give up. Never again would
he love. Neither would he hate. All he cared for was duty. All he lived
for was duty. He would die before he surrendered, but he would
<em>never</em> break.</p>
<p>The priestess was paralyzed by the emotions rushing through her mind!
Never before had she touched such feelings. It was a long moment before
she realized the man's feelings were so powerful, she'd lost herself in
them!</p>
<p>As she applied her training and focused her mind, the intensity of
the experience reduced, slowly. She got to her feet, very unsteadily.
She eyed the man in fear; she'd rather feel the pain of another severed
head, than ever touch the man again! He was living in what others would
consider the worst kind of torture, a personal, living hell, and he
<em>preferred</em> it that way!</p>
<p>Aaron looked down at the stricken woman and said, “Ma'am, please
don't touch me.”</p>
<p>Trembling with shock, she limped away, having decided to cut her
losses, for the time being. She needed medical attention, time to
consider and a much better plan of attack.</p>
<p>Aaron returned to his post.</p>
<hr />
<p>Mr. Orlov, more commonly known as Eagle, the man with the tattooed
scalp, watched the scene with interest. He also eyed Marcus the same
way. The other members of the club, all gathered around the windows,
simply thought the spectacle a sort of rare entertainment.</p>
<p>When the woman was gone, he asked, “Why bring her here?”</p>
<p>Marcus grinned, “I owe a debt to someone.”</p>
<p>“Who?” Eagle asked.</p>
<p>“My guard, down there.”</p>
<p>Eagle's only response was a quizzical expression.</p>
<p>Marcus elaborated, “Ever hear of the Ashen Blades?”</p>
<p>“Assassin clan that got wiped out by some gate guard, right?” Eagle
nodded.</p>
<p>“He's the guard.”</p>
<p>“And your stake in this?”</p>
<p>“I'm the last of the Ashen Blades.” Marcus whispered, all mirth gone
from his face, “I want him to suffer.”</p>
<p>“You think that priestess can manage that?”</p>
<p>Marcus grinned evilly, “I'm counting on it.”</p>
<hr />
<p>The priestess limped into the clinic a few hours later. Bar Breaker
was sitting on his sick bed, trying to find a way to hold a spoon
without pain, with both arms in a splint. There was a bowl of soup in
front of him on a rolling tray.</p>
<p>Dr. Petrov rushed to her side and helped her to one of the beds.</p>
<p>After examined her leg, he asked, “What happened to you? Looks like
someone stabbed you, but I can't believe that's possible.”</p>
<p>She grunted as he poured a stinging liquid on the wound that smelled
of brandy and began stitching.</p>
<p>Her voice sounded a bit odd, due to the broken nose, “Indirect force.
I charged. Blocked me. Sword, shield.”</p>
<p>“I guess that explains your nose, too. Sounds like the man knows your
limits.”</p>
<p>She nodded.</p>
<p>He finished stitching her up and then instructed, “Let me see that
nose.”</p>
<p>He spent a few minutes examining her and then brought her a cold, wet
cloth to hold to it.</p>
<p>As she sat and held the cloth to her swollen nose, he asked, “Who did
this to you?”</p>
<p>She muttered, “Guard. Rawlings'.”</p>
<p>“Ah! That's why I knew the face of the man in your picture. He's
Marcus Rawlings. He owns a gentleman's club.”</p>
<p>“Who's the guard?” She asked.</p>
<p>“Aaron Kozinski. I know him from my days in the king's regiment, as
their medic. Taught his men how to keep their limbs after serious
injuries.”</p>
<p>“More, please.” She grunted.</p>
<p>He sighed and shook his head, “Aaron's story is quite tragic. I don't
know the details, though. The king or one of his men could tell you, if
you happen to know one of them well.”</p>
<p>The priestess smiled, nodded and then let someone take care of her
for once, instead of the other way around.</p>
<h2 id="chapter-6-the-undelivered-letter">Chapter 6 The Undelivered
Letter</h2>
<p>Three days later, the priestess paid a visit to the king, who was
overjoyed to see her.</p>
<p>“Sister! It’s so good to see you!”</p>
<p>The throne room was different. There were fewer expensive decorations
about and, based on the long table, the room was now a sort of meeting
hall. There was a group of nobles working with city planners at the
table, a set of maps spread out and being argued over.</p>
<p>The king gestured her toward a side chamber and followed her in. It
was a small sitting room, for smaller meetings. The queen was already in
the room, examining some papers with an irritated expression on her
face. When she looked up and saw the priestess, she smiled broadly and
greeted her warmly.</p>
<p>Once they were all seated and pleasantries out of the way, the king
asked, “What brings you to us?”</p>
<p>She told them the complete story of how she'd met the guard now
serving the gentleman's club as a bouncer, including his name.</p>
<p>The king's face clouded with grief, “The man I failed.”</p>
<p>The queen held her husband's arm, to comfort him, as he told the
man's story from start to finish, even including some details of his
life since leaving the king's regiment.</p>
<p>When he got to the story of the man losing his family, the priestess
muttered, “That explains the grief, duty and apathy, all at once.”</p>
<p>The king expressed his own grief, “I should have left my regiment in
place. I shouldn't have sent him away from the city. It’s my fault his
family is gone!”</p>
<p>The priestess shook her head, “No, my king. It isn't. You made the
best decision you could have. The other regiments were too far away.
Yes, it cost a man his family, but you saved many more families. The
blame lies on the shoulders of the arsonist.”</p>
<p>The queen smiled and silently mouthed, “Thank you.”</p>
<p>After a long pause to digest her words, the king asked, “Would you
like royal assistance? I'd be happy to loan you a few of my best
men.”</p>
<p>She considered, “No. Our friendship is too well known and this is
likely to get messy in the end. I don't want to drag you into it.”</p>
<p>He nodded, “Very well.”</p>
<p>“Do you know the man's heart?”</p>
<p>“No.” The king's eyes became watery as he admitted, “He wouldn't
explain why he resigned. I think he felt he couldn't explain without
offending me. My guess is he blames me for the loss of his wife.”</p>
<p>She nodded, “You may be right about that. His heart was in conflict,
at the time. His grief and his duty couldn't be reconciled. Now, his
heart dwells in a place filled with a mixture of apathy and duty. To
him, they're now one and the same. He feels nothing else. I've never
touched such feelings before.” She shuddered, “I hope never to do so
again.”</p>
<p>“What can I do to help?”</p>
<p>“I need to reach him, to find or make a crack in his emotional armor.
Please, tell me about his wife and daughter.”</p>
<p>With a sniff to force back some tears, the queen spoke, “His wife's
name was Kassandra. She had a warm and gentle nature. Very loving and
devoted to her husband. It was wonderful to see the way his eyes lit up
every time he saw her. She was a good friend and I dearly miss her.”</p>
<p>The king smiled at the memory and cried at the loss, “Their
daughter's name was Sasha. She was a toddler at the time, always happy,
like I remember her mother. She loved her father and was always excited
to see him when he came home.”</p>
<p>The priestess asked, “Do you think his wife would approve of the way
he's living his life?”</p>
<p>“No.” The queen shook her head, “I know that for a fact.”</p>
<p>“How do you know?”</p>
<p>“She once gave me a letter to give to him, in the case of her death,
but I haven't seen him since. I planned to give it to him the next time
he came to the castle. At the time, I thought he was simply taking time
to grieve. It was several weeks before I asked and was told he'd
resigned. He felt so strongly about resigning that I didn't want to
cause him more pain, by reminding him of his loss. I think that was an
error in judgment, now.”</p>
<p>The priestess asked, “May I have the letter?”</p>
<p>“Yes, of course.” The queen nodded and excused herself, to retrieve
it.</p>
<p>The king spoke, “I just want Aaron to be happy. I think you may have
a good chance of moving him in the right direction. You're the first to
know his feelings since the loss of his wife. Please, try to help
him.</p>
<p>“I don't know if it will do you any good or not, but I'll write a
letter for you to take to Aaron, to vouch for your character.”</p>
<p>The king took a few minutes to write the letter and sealed it with
wax and his signet ring.</p>
<p>Within a few minutes, the queen was back, with the letter from
Aaron's wife.</p>
<p>The priestess thanked them and departed.</p>
<hr />
<p>After another three days to heal, she approached the club, still
limping slightly. Aaron was at his post, beside the door.</p>
<p>She stepped in front of him, “I've spoken with the king and queen
about you.”</p>
<p>She handed him the letter from the king, which he opened and read.
With that complete, he stuffed it into his tunic, under his chain mail,
showing no sign of emotion.</p>
<p>“The queen gave me a letter Kassandra wrote for you before she
died.”</p>
<p>Aaron flinched, ever so slightly, at the sound of his wife’s name.
She pulled it out.</p>
<p>“I'm going to read it to you.” She said and then began.</p>
<hr />
<p><em>To my dearest husband, Aaron,</em></p>
<p><em>If you're reading this, then I've died, probably
unexpectedly.</em></p>
<p><em>Initially, I thought the idea of this letter morbid and
disturbing, but as I've watched you go out each day, to patrol the city,
I've worried you would never return, as you often come home injured
after fighting with criminals in the street. After some time with these
thoughts, I began instead, to worry what would happen if I
died.</em></p>
<p><em>I know how much you love me and I love you for that! You care for
me so deeply, I cry happy tears, daily. I miss you each day as you
work.</em></p>
<p><em>I know you, husband. I know your heart and I know that each of us
is the foundation for the other. I worry what may become of you, in my
absence.</em></p>
<p><em>You must go on without me. I don't like to think of sharing you
in the hereafter, but I know that you'll never be happy without a woman
at your side. When you've mourned me, in your own due time, please go
out and find someone new. Find someone that makes you happy, someone
that knows your heart.</em></p>
<p><em>Know, my husband, that this will make me happy, to know that
you're being taken care of by someone that loves you.</em></p>
<p><em>Our daughter and I are nearly always together. If by some chance
we both died, I say this is even more important. You must do as I say in
this.</em></p>
<p><em>As your wife, I beg you to obey me, without question, just this
once.</em></p>
<hr />
<p>Aaron was trembling. He held out his hand for the letter. He took it
and read it for himself, quietly. He examined the signature. He knew the
delicate loops on the letter 'a' and the sharp corners on the 'K'. It
was real.</p>
<p>Tears streaked down his cheeks. He slipped the letter into his tunic,
alongside the one from the king.</p>
<p>He looked the priestess in the eye, “Thank you.”</p>
<hr />
<p>Steeling herself for the worst, she took his unresisting hand in her
own. Gratitude washed through her, mixed with both fresh and old grief.
Beyond this was remorse and a great sense of lost time. The apathy was
gone, but the duty remained. He was suffering, for now, but hopeful for
the future.</p>
<p>The priestess returned his steady gaze and for the first time since
she was a child, spoke her name aloud, “My name is Alena. I know your
need and I will forsake my calling to fill it. I can't ignore your pain,
because to do so would also mean forsaking my calling.”</p>
<p>Alena felt her empathic ability leave her, knowing full well she
would never feel it again.</p>
<p>She heard the voice of her god, in her mind, for the first and last
time: <em>Congratulations on a good choice.</em> She’d always suspected
her god was female, but hadn’t known it until she heard the voice.</p>
<p>Aaron smiled, dropped his shield and hugged her, crying on her
shoulder for quite a long time, letting out every last trapped emotion,
for the first time in years.</p>
<p>When the sobbing stopped, she whispered, softly, “Aaron, what is your
duty?”</p>
<p>He straightened up and stared into space. He pulled out the letter
from the king and re-read it.</p>
<p>“The king vouches for you and says that if you're on this quest, then
it is just. There is no higher compliment in this kingdom. By the king's
word and your own, Marcus Rawlings will face justice. My duty is to see
that done.”</p>
<p>Picking up his shield, he opened the door and marched inside.</p>
<hr />
<p>Eagle watched with great amusement as the guard marched up the
stairs.</p>
<p>Marcus screamed, “What are you doing, Aaron? You should be on duty,
by the door!”</p>
<p>Aaron paused at the threshold of the room and declared, “The king has
personally vouched for the woman waiting outside. By that, alone, I am
compelled to believe her words. I'm taking you into custody, so justice
can be done.”</p>
<p>Marcus drew a pair of daggers from hidden sheaths on each arm,
cursing at Aaron.</p>
<p>The men in the club moved away from Marcus. Aaron stepped away from
the stairs and allowed them to exit, leaving only the three of them.</p>
<p>Eagle noisily bit into an apple, grinning like the cat that ate the
canary.</p>
<p>Marcus turned his head to the man and demanded, “Do something, man!
I'll pay you whatever you want!”</p>
<p>Eagle smiled, “What, and ruin the best entertainment I've had all
year?”</p>
<p>He nodded to Aaron and bit into the apple again.</p>
<p>Aaron approached Marcus, ready for anything.</p>
<p>Marcus stepped forward and thrust with both daggers at different
angles! Aaron caught the one on the left with his shield, forcing it out
too wide to do any harm, while angling his sword for a skilled parry and
attack combination that brought the edge of his sword sliding around the
dagger's guard and into Marcus' hand!</p>
<p>Marcus dropped the dagger, bleeding.</p>
<p>He tried again, aiming his remaining weapon for one of Aaron's eyes.
Aaron parried with his sword and swung his shield at high speed,
slamming it into the man's head. There was a resounding clang that
echoed through the building and the man dropped to the floor,
unconscious!</p>
<p>Aaron cleaned his sword on Marcus' clothes and sheathed it. He easily
hefted the man over one shoulder and carried him outside.</p>
<p>Alena led the way, taking them to the law man's office. When Marcus
was safely behind bars, a comparison was made to the drawing and
everyone agreed, he was the man. Alena sent for Dr. Petrov; it wouldn't
do to let the prisoner die before he could face judgment, after all.</p>
<h2 id="chapter-7-sweet-surrender">Chapter 7 Sweet Surrender</h2>
<p>The next year brought a fresh, new spring with it. Alena was wearing
a beautiful, lace-covered wedding gown, something she thought she'd
never wear. It had been lovingly sewn by the women of the village. She
was in the main hall of the temple that had once been her home. The room
was packed and overflowing; everyone wanted to be there! The queen was
seated in the front row, crying and blowing her nose, a smile on her
face.</p>
<p>The king marched down the aisle with Alena on his arm, since her own
father was long dead. It was an odd image, since the king was younger
than her.</p>
<p>Aaron was standing there, at the front, next to the new priest, a
content smile on his face. He wore his gleaming regimental armor, having
spent the last week carefully polishing each piece to a mirror-shine.
Alena was so happy he'd gotten his old job back.</p>
<p>She was also ecstatic she was getting married! Aaron was such a
loving man and they were happy together.</p>
<p>They knelt before the priest. They exchanged vows, then rings and
were pronounced husband and wife.</p>
<p>They didn't live happily ever after, but they argued less than
average and grew old together. What more could any couple ask for?</p>
<h1 id="end">END</h1>
</div>
]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Community Service Fairy</title>
<link>https://owentyme.us/shorts/short-of-tyme/community-service-fairy-godmother.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/shorts/short-of-tyme/community-service-fairy-godmother.html</guid>
<pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 08:01:31 -0600</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>Seeing systemic injustice in the laws established by the Queen of the
Fairies, <em>may she reign forever</em>, Sophorica breaks them to draw
attention to their absurdity, literally painting New York City red.
After all, if the only crime is to be caught and any offense can be
forgiven simply by being sneaky, then the law itself can only be
considered a cruel joke.</p>
<p>Her crime is expunged from history and the human race is none the
wiser, but the Queen, <em>may she reign forever</em>, sentences
Sophorica to perform one act of community service in the human realm for
each human witness. This service takes the form of granting wishes to
human children as their fairy godmother, until they’re happy.</p>
<p>However, the awful truth is that granting wishes rarely brings
happiness, forcing Sophorica to learn as much as she can about her
charges, that she might get them to wish for what they really need,
rather than what they want.</p>
<p>Will Sophorica find a way to free herself from the twisted, unjust
punishment wrought by the Queen, <em>may she reign forever</em>,
successfully demonstrating the flaws in fairy law or will she be forever
banished to the human world as a Fairy Godmother?</p>
</blockquote>
<div id="prose" class="prose">
<h1 id="community-service-fairy-godmother">Community Service Fairy
Godmother</h1>
<h2 id="short-of-tyme-3">Short of Tyme #3</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://owentyme.us/shorts/short-of-tyme/community-service-fairy-godmother.html#a-fairys-day-in-court" id="toc-a-fairys-day-in-court">A
Fairy’s Day in Court</a></li>
<li><a href="https://owentyme.us/shorts/short-of-tyme/community-service-fairy-godmother.html#first-charge" id="toc-first-charge">First Charge</a></li>
<li><a href="https://owentyme.us/shorts/short-of-tyme/community-service-fairy-godmother.html#second-charge" id="toc-second-charge">Second
Charge</a></li>
<li><a href="https://owentyme.us/shorts/short-of-tyme/community-service-fairy-godmother.html#third-charge" id="toc-third-charge">Third Charge</a></li>
<li><a href="https://owentyme.us/shorts/short-of-tyme/community-service-fairy-godmother.html#the-only-winning-move" id="toc-the-only-winning-move">The
Only Winning Move</a></li>
<li><a href="https://owentyme.us/shorts/short-of-tyme/community-service-fairy-godmother.html#another-fairys-day-in-court"
id="toc-another-fairys-day-in-court">Another Fairy’s Day in
Court</a></li>
<li><a href="https://owentyme.us/shorts/short-of-tyme/community-service-fairy-godmother.html#may-she-reign-forever" id="toc-may-she-reign-forever">May
She Reign Forever</a></li>
</ul>
<h2 id="a-fairys-day-in-court">A Fairy’s Day in Court</h2>
<p>“Did you hear what she did?” The whisper carried through the cell
door, clearly intentionally and in a cultured, snobbish, female
voice.</p>
<p>Sophorica didn’t hear the response, but it must have been a negative,
even though <em>everyone</em> already knew the answer.</p>
<p>“Oh! She made <em>such a mess</em> in the mortal world!” The snob
went on.</p>
<p>Yep, they’re were talking about her. Everyone was. Now, they weren’t
even trying to hide it anymore. <em>No one</em> could out-gossip a
fairy, even if they tried for a thousand years. It was intentional
snubbing to shame the accused over the greatest crime known to
fey-kind.</p>
<p>Again, the other party in the conversation was too quiet to be
heard.</p>
<p>“Oh, yes! I hear the queen, <em>may she reign forever</em>, is going
to punish her <em>severely</em>.” The snob spoke with great delight.</p>
<p>Like the giggle of a twisted, corrupt angel, the snob guard outside
the cell laughed.</p>
<p>As cells went, it wasn’t a bad one. The queen, <em>may she reign
forever</em>, at least had taste. The couches were comfortable,
beautifully decorated in blue and gold, plus there was plenty to eat,
good wine to drink, the bed was one of the best Sophorica had ever slept
on and the view from the wide-open window was breath-taking, allowing
her to see a magnificent waterfall cascade over the homes of the river
fey, carefully guided into flowing paths down the high, stone cliff.</p>
<p>It was almost, but not quite, like being free and that was the point:
offering the condemned some of the greatest pleasures in life, subtly
reminding them of all they were about to lose once their guilt was
confirmed and proclaimed, by royal decree. She was tempted to fly out
the open window, but knew the way the queen, <em>may she reign
forever</em>, thought. It would be a fate worse than death and worse
than the fate already in store for her.</p>
<p>In all the history of the fey-folk, Sophorica knew of only one case
where the accused had won, despite all the contrived evidence the
prosecutor brought before the queen, <em>may she reign forever</em>, to
ensure a guilty verdict. The queen, <em>may she reign forever</em>, did
not like losing and severely punished the prosecutor in place of the
accused, for having lost the case.</p>
<p>Sophorica could hear the last dozen or so verdicts echo in her head:
<em>Off with his/her head!</em></p>
<p>The queen, <em>may she reign forever</em>, was very fond of that one
lately.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, being magical creatures, a beheading wasn’t always
lethal. She’d met a few Dullahan, forced to spend eternity carrying
their heads under an arm wherever they went as a sign of punishment.
They usually had their wings clipped, as well, forcing them to walk
forever after.</p>
<p>Sophorica’s reverie was interrupted by a knock at the door. She
quickly stood and looked at herself in the mirror, since it wouldn’t do
to let her jailer think she was having an effect.</p>
<p>Sophorica was currently human in shape and size, with long, curled,
golden hair. In deference to her high-born nature, she wore her ears
long and pointed, to advertise to the lesser races the need to treat her
with respect. Similarly, her long, insect-like wings were also visible,
to remind them of who and what she was, each of them translucent and
sparkling. She wore a figure-hugging, knee-length blue and gold dress,
showing off the curvaceous feminine features her current form possessed.
Her shoes were the slip-on kind, with high heels, matching the motif of
her dress.</p>
<p>On a moment’s whim, she changed her eye color from green to blue,
deciding it should match her dress. She also reduced the height of her
shoes, just in case she got stuck with them as a result of the queen’s,
<em>may she reign forever</em>, judgment.</p>
<p>Shape-shifting and magic to alter clothes were both a privilege, not
a right, and could be taken away, so she made sure she was comfortable
<em>and</em> looked good.</p>
<p>“You may enter.” Sophorica spoke, managing a haughty sneer, despite
her imprisonment.</p>
<p>Jenessica, her jailer, entered the room and gave her the snobbish
grin she always wore. She was dressed in an ankle-length, red dress, cut
low in front, presumably to show off the cleavage she did not, in fact,
possess. She also had long, brown hair and brown eyes.</p>
<p>“Oh, you! It’s time for your trial, <em>princess</em>!” The snob
spoke the word like an insult, “I do, <em>so</em> look forward to
hearing your fate!”</p>
<p>Jenessica was holding an elegantly thin, wooden wand in one hand,
impatiently tapping her other hand with it. The need for an external
device to enhance her powers, such as a wand, marked her as having weak
magic. Her shape-shifting was quite temporary as a result, lasting no
more than an hour at a time. Jenessica’s wings looked like those of a
butterfly, with red, orange and yellow mixed together, red being the
dominant color. The edges were outlined in black.</p>
<p>Sophorica nodded, giving her jailer the kind of look she reserved for
something scraped off the bottom of her shoe, and stepped into the
hall.</p>
<p>Behind her, Jenessica instructed, “To the left,
<em>princess</em>.”</p>
<p>Again, the last word was spoken like the most vile of insults. Her
jailer wasn’t overly fond of royalty, aside from the queen, <em>may she
reign forever</em>, but that was probably just a matter of the
collective curse of being subject to her rule.</p>
<p>Sophorica turned left and walked the hall, until instructed to turn
again. After several more turns, she heard the sound of a great many
voices in the distance. When the last turn was made, she found herself
in a room so large, it wasn’t possible to have been contained in the
building and had therefore just walked through an open portal. The
effect was so seamless, Sophorica hadn’t even sensed it. Such was the
incredible power of the queen, <em>may she reign forever</em>, that she
could bend the rules of reality to her liking, at a whim.</p>
<p>Sophorica thought on the queen’s, <em>may she reign forever</em>,
decree regarding proper respect. It really bothered her that she
couldn’t even think about the queen, <em>may she reign forever</em>,
without the insertion of that <em>cursed phrase</em> into the
sentence!</p>
<p>The room appeared to have been constructed from a forest clearing,
reality-warped into a solid structure, with all the accouterments for a
proper trial. It held all of the fey court’s current nobles and the
servants they went nowhere without. That had clearly been made possible
by distorting space until there was enough room, giving the trees on the
edge of the room a bizarre, twisted look, like an Escher-space made of
trees, just beyond the barrier holding it all together as a room. With
its distorted space, the queen, <em>may she reign forever</em>, had used
the resultant time distortions to invite the nobles for the trial at the
most convenient moment possible, as she’d always done. The overall
effect was impressive. The primary purpose was just to stroke her
massive ego, with the public demonstration of power being secondary.</p>
<p>Sophorica hated the queen, <em>may she reign forever</em>, but
couldn’t help but be taken in by what she’d done. Every mistake she made
was twisted until it became an advantage. She applied the same talent to
politics, resulting in a reign of just under ten-thousand years! Her
enemies became her allies or were never heard from again. There were
persistent rumors that her worst enemies had been erased from history
entirely, having never even been born!</p>
<p>She looked on the face of the queen, <em>may she reign forever</em>,
who was dressed in a green and brown dress that including many
embroidered, silk leaf-like flaps that fluttered in the air, making her
appear almost like a living, walking, talking tree. She wore a
glittering crown of gold with emeralds set in it, atop her head, where
it contrasted the metallic, silver curls of her hair, which appeared to
have been spun from actual silver!</p>
<p>“The accused may sit!” The queen, <em>may she reign forever</em>,
commanded!</p>
<p>Sophorica resisted for the briefest fraction of a second and then, of
their own accord, her legs betrayed her by obeying the command, marching
her to the appropriate seat, where she sat, against her will. Stepping
in the room, behind her, Jenessica took station at the edge of the room,
as bailiff.</p>
<p>Sitting in a high seat formed by twisting the shape of a tree into a
proper judge’s seat and desk, the queen, <em>may she reign forever</em>,
looked down.</p>
<p>The queen, <em>may she reign forever</em>, began by reading the
charges, “Sophorica, you stand accused of meddling in mortal affairs.
According to the expert witness of dozens of balance-keepers, you
<em>literally</em> painted the city of New York red! Is this true?”</p>
<p>Refusing the say the <em>cursed phrase</em> out loud, Sophorica stood
and responded, “Yes, mother.”</p>
<p>There was a sudden intake of breath from all present! Sophorica was
guilty of a massive breach of etiquette, publicly speaking to the queen
in such a familiar way, and during a court proceeding, no less! It was,
however, not actually a crime. Though, after the trial was over, she was
certain it would be declared as one.</p>
<p>The queen, <em>may she reign forever</em>, raised her voice, reaching
a level of volume just shy of pain, “Sophorica, as this is an official
court proceeding, you will not refer to me as ‘mother’ or I will be
forced to hold you in contempt of court. Today, that carries a
punishment of death by mortality!”</p>
<p>‘Death by mortality’ referred to stripping a fey of their immortal
nature, usually along with banishment to the mortal realm, to live as a
human, or some lower creature, if the queen, <em>may she reign
forever</em>, was in a foul enough mood.</p>
<p>“Yes, ma’am.” Sophorica nodded, knowing ‘ma’am’ was another studied
insult, “May I request, then, that you refer to me by my title of
‘Princess’, rather than by name, due to the seriousness of this
matter.”</p>
<p>“Very well, Princess.” The queen, <em>may she reign forever</em>,
sounded quite angry, but was unable to refute the logic, “How do you
defend your actions?”</p>
<p>Sophorica smiled like The Trickster himself, who she noted was
sitting in the front row. She gave Coyote a nod, who smiled back,
showing off his canines. He looked almost like a werewolf, covered head
to toe in fur, resembling the animal that was named after him, aside
from the fact he often walked on two legs.</p>
<p>She began, “In 1924, you did something very similar to the city in
question, after getting extremely drunk. I was simply following your
example. Having noted that I was inebriated, I took similar action.”</p>
<p>“<em>I am not on trial at this time, but you are!</em>” The queen,
<em>may she reign forever</em>, thundered, “However, I will note, for
the court record, that the Princess did not restore time to an earlier
point, to erase her actions. She did not maintain the balance of the
mortal realm.”</p>
<p>Seeking to push the narrative toward the real crux of the issue,
while still in the public’s eye, Sophorica explained, “Of course I
didn’t! That would have defeated the meaning of what I was doing!”</p>
<p>“What, pray tell, was your purpose in such an obvious and open
display of magic in the eyes of mortals?”</p>
<p>“To demonstrate the folly of our laws! The <em>only</em> crime is to
be caught! If I’d painted the entire town red and gotten away without
being spotted, it would be acceptable, but since I was caught,
red-handed, so to speak, I’m on trial, here and now.”</p>
<p>The court began to murmur, loudly! It was loud enough that the queen,
<em>may she reign forever</em>, shouted, “I will have <em>silence</em>
in this court!”</p>
<p>Everyone closed their mouths, suddenly unable to speak. Sophorica
smiled at Coyote, who winked back. The message was heard, loud and
clear. It would be whispered about, for years to come, but not in the
presence of the queen, <em>may she reign forever</em>. Never in her
presence, if the speaker wanted to stay among the upright and
breathing.</p>
<p>“Very well!” The queen, <em>may she reign forever</em>, began, “Since
you clearly show no remorse for your actions and cannot defend them,
Princess, you will be punished. I will erase your actions from the
memory of all mortals and warp reality to remove the effects of your
actions. Since you harmed the balance of the mortal realm, you will
perform one act of community service to the mortal realm for every
witness to your actions. According to the records provided by the
balance-keepers, this will be 6,409 individuals.”</p>
<p>“Yes, ma’am.” Sophorica nodded and asked, “What form will my service
take?”</p>
<p>The queen, <em>may she reign forever</em>, grinned evilly, speaking
the words as the curse they were, “<em>Fairy Godmother</em>. The
majority of your magical powers will be stripped for the duration, with
the major exception being the ability to grant the wishes of the unhappy
children of the mortal realm, that you may bring them happiness. You
will serve each of your charges until they’re truly happy.”</p>
<p>Sophorica could see the intentional flaw in the queen’s, <em>may she
reign forever</em>, logic. Granting wishes never made anyone happy.
Usually, quite the opposite, the curse of Genies and Fairy God-Parents,
everywhere. To complete the task, she would have to convince her charges
to wish for what they needed, rather than what they wanted, a nearly
impossible distinction, especially for children.</p>
<p>With the punishment pronounced, it was so. As her wings shrunk and
faded away, Sophorica felt her powers change according to the queen’s,
<em>may she reign forever</em>, command, knowing she might possibly
never again use magic at her own will. The only power she retained
control of was her natural, selective invisibility to mortals, a power
the queen, <em>may she reign forever</em>, would never dare strip of any
fairy, without first making them mortal, it being an essential part of
keeping the balance of the mortal realm.</p>
<p>The queen, <em>may she reign forever</em>, continued, “You shall
begin your service in the very city you have wronged,
<em>immediately</em>.”</p>
<p>Sophorica’s dress fluttered in the wind as she fell through a
portal!</p>
<h2 id="first-charge">First Charge</h2>
<p>Sophorica found herself falling through the air, looking down at a
city of millions, with tall, glass and concrete buildings, reaching up
to the sky! The brilliant light of dawn left the city as a mixture of
long shadows and brightly-lit buildings on the edge of the island of
Manhattan.</p>
<p>Without a lot in the way of thought, she tried to slow her fall with
her wings, only to be reminded of the harsh reality of her situation:
she had no wings!</p>
<p>She relaxed and took a moment to think. The queen, <em>may she reign
forever</em>, must have thought it amusing to drop her off in the mortal
realm at ten-thousand feet. Were the consequences her fault, then? How
could she be blamed if she made a crater?</p>
<p>Sophorica smiled and decided to make the most of it, to display her
defiance to the queen, <em>may she reign forever</em>, by angling
herself into the wind, to minimize resistance and maximize acceleration!
She would show her disdain for her monarch, <em>ah, at last, a way to
avoid the cursed phrase</em>, by leaving a huge mark in the pavement
that would be difficult to explain to the rest of the court, for she
knew they would be watching.</p>
<p>At five-thousand feet, Sophorica was falling with lethal velocity and
a gleeful smile!</p>
<p>At four-thousand, she turned and looked back, to the sky, winking and
making faces at the court, secure in her belief they could see her.</p>
<p>At three-thousand, she passed through a cloud and turned her
attention back to the ground, angling herself for a busy street. She
glanced to one side, taking in the view of Lady Liberty.</p>
<p>At somewhere under two-thousand, she passed below the height of the
tallest building.</p>
<p>When she reached one-thousand she was surrounded by buildings,
looking into a street filled with cars, zipping from place to place.</p>
<p>She closed her eyes and accepted her fate, knowing it would be
painful, but what was pain, to an immortal? She spread her arms and legs
wide, intending to leave a humanoid crater!</p>
<p>Seconds passed and just as she expected to slam into the ground at
pavement-shattering velocity, the wind that had been howling in her ears
ceased. She cautiously opened her eyes, finding herself floating about
fifteen feet in the air, helpless, spinning as though trapped in a
bubble of zero gravity. She struggled for a moment and ended up hanging
upside-down, with her dress hanging down, in an embarrassing
fashion.</p>
<p>As soon as her struggles left her in this undignified position,
whatever held her in the air ceased and she dropped, hitting the
pavement, head-first!</p>
<p>As Sophorica groaned and got to her feet, brushing dirt and grass off
her skirt, she heard a small child giggle. With the instinct of a Fairy
Godmother, she knew the voice of her charge and also knew she could
never be invisible to her charge, unless they wished for it.</p>
<p>She looked to see the source of the voice, taking in the appearance
of a small girl in dirty, green pants, with holes in the knees and a
stained, white T-shirt with a cartoon kitten on it. She had brown hair,
brown eyes and couldn’t have been more than five or six years old.</p>
<p>Sophorica was in some kind of large park, near a playground, filled
with other children. She hadn’t remembered a park, having clearly aimed
for a street. It must have been her monarch’s doing, spoiling her
entrance to the mortal realm, while also placing her near her first
charge.</p>
<p>Once again, she felt a little thrill at her discovery of a way to
avoid the cursed phrase. Should she meet another fey during her stay in
the mortal world, she would definitely have to share the discovery.</p>
<p>Sophorica walked over to her charge and knelt, saying, “I’m
Sophorica. What’s your name?”</p>
<p>The girl looked into her eyes and asked in an overly-rapid voice,
“Are-you-a-stranger? My-mom-said-I-shouldn’t-talk-to-strangers,
but-my-brother-said-I-should-talk-to-every-stranger-and-play-in-the-street,
too.”</p>
<p>“I’m not a stranger.” Sophorica smiled and shook her head, “I’m your
Fairy Godmother.”</p>
<p>“What’s-a-Fairy-Godmother?” The child asked in the same rapid-fire
fashion.</p>
<p>“Fairy Godmothers help children, like yourself,” Sophorica felt a
compulsion to tell the whole truth, which she tried to resist, doing
little more than damping her hair with sweat as she spoke in a miserable
tone of voice, “by granting wishes.”</p>
<p>She’d been planning not to advertise that fact and wanted to,
instead, guide her charge toward wishing for what she needed, rather
than what she wanted.</p>
<p>The little girl’s eyes lit up, becoming like saucers, “Like a
genie?”</p>
<p>Sophorica fought the compulsion, once more, but failed, speaking
through clenched teeth, “Yes. Anything you want, just ask.”</p>
<p>So, she couldn’t lie when asked a direct question and worse, she was
forced to speak the whole truth. Well, if that was the game, then she
would have to think hard about the truth. Fey were well-known for their
capricious ability to twist the truth until it stank like a lie.</p>
<p>As Sophorica opened her mouth, to give it a try, the little girl
spoke the awful words, “I wish…”</p>
<hr />
<p>Three hours later, after having granted every wish the child could
think of, including, but not limited to: a candy bar, a hamburger, a bag
of gummy bears and a new doll. Sophorica was tired and frustrated,
because she couldn’t get a word in edgewise, interrupted by the child’s
stream of greedy requests every time she tried to speak. She was
grateful her charge wasn’t very imaginative, though, seeming content to
ask for small things, like candy, greasy food and toys.</p>
<p>Sophorica muttered, mostly to herself, “I wish you’d listen to me,
for just a moment.”</p>
<p>Surprised, the girl looked up at her from the grass of the park and
asked, “Fairies make wishes, too?”</p>
<p>Having finally gained the kid’s attention for a moment, she nodded,
“Yes, we do.”</p>
<p>“What do you wish for, then?” The little girl’s eyes were full of
curiosity.</p>
<p>Smiling, Sophorica took the opportunity to speak a clear truth, “I
wish you were happy.”</p>
<p>To her surprise, the girl started crying, great big tears that ran
down her face and mingled with the snot that had just started pouring
from her nose!</p>
<p>It took a while for her to comfort the girl enough to calm her down,
but when she did, unhappy details poured out, in a torrent, “Mom and her
boyfriend fight and hit each other! And George breaks all my toys! And I
hate school! And I don’t have any friends! And…” she sniffed, “Daddy
won’t come home!”</p>
<p>Sophorica considered, carefully. Among mortals, broken homes were
often the cause of unhappiness and misery, but there were certain lines
that shouldn’t be crossed, at least not if she could help it. She needed
more information.</p>
<p>“Where’s your daddy?”</p>
<p>“New Jersey.” The girl wiped her tears away.</p>
<p>Good. He wasn’t dead. Sophorica wasn’t about to raise the dead if she
had any say in the matter.</p>
<p>“Would it make you happy if he came home?”</p>
<p>The girl silently nodded.</p>
<p>Sophorica prodded, “You have to say the words…”</p>
<p>The girl nodded and spoke, “I wish Daddy would come home and we could
be a family again!”</p>
<p>Sophorica waved her hand in the air and used her magic, producing a
sparkly glow in the air, just as she’d done with every prior wish, even
the ones she hadn’t wanted to grant.</p>
<hr />
<p>Off in the not-so-distant land of New Jersey, a man working in a
warehouse felt a pang in his heart, a longing to go home, to his wife
and kids. He’d left them after discovering his wife cheating on him with
another man, but in truth, leaving her hadn’t made him happy. In fact,
it had been quite the opposite. He decided to forgive her, because he
still loved her. They could work it out, he knew they could!</p>
<hr />
<p>Off in an apartment building, near the park, a woman lay in bed,
beside her lover, feeling unfulfilled. The relationship with him had
been exciting, when it was a hidden thing, but now, in retrospect, it
had been a massive mistake. She’d alienated her husband in the process
and turned her home into a series of continuous arguments with her
teenage son and the man she knew she didn’t love.</p>
<p>She longed to see her husband’s face. They weren’t yet divorced, so
perhaps there was still a chance?</p>
<p>Hoping for a return to the way things used to be and certain the way
things were was a foolish mistake, she got up and dressed, then she
turned to the man in her bed, saying, “This isn’t working. I want you
out of my house and I want my husband back.”</p>
<p>“What?”</p>
<p>It turned into another physical altercation, but this time, she
called the police. Almost as soon as her former lover was gone from the
house, the phone rang.</p>
<p>When she picked it up and heard the voice of her husband, tears of
joy filled her eyes!</p>
<hr />
<p>Sophorica lowered her hand and the glow faded.</p>
<p>The girl looked around and pointed out, “Nothing happened!”</p>
<p>“That was a big wish,” Sophorica explained, “so it will take a little
time, okay?”</p>
<p>“Okay.”</p>
<p>Swaggering toward the small corner of the park where the girl had
been left to her own devices, a teenage boy called out from the other
side of a decorative bush, “Hey brat, where are you?”</p>
<p>The girl popped up and complained, “I’m not a brat! I have a
name!”</p>
<p>The teen grumbled, “Fine, Susie, come on! It’s time to go home!”</p>
<p>Susie obediently stepped over to him, still holding her new doll,
which he pulled from her protesting hands with superior strength,
wrenched its head off and then tossed both pieces aside.</p>
<p>“What, you’re not gonna cry, this time?” The boy looked eager to see
the sight.</p>
<p>Susie shrugged, in response. It obviously wasn’t the first time
George had broken her toys.</p>
<p>Speaking as though disappointed, he demanded, “Come on, let’s
go!”</p>
<p>Susie waved to Sophorica.</p>
<p>George asked, “Who are you waving at?”</p>
<p>“The nice lady!” She pointed at her Fairy Godmother.</p>
<p>He roughly grabbed Susie’s hand and ordered, “Forget your imaginary
friend and <em>come on</em>!”</p>
<p>Walking quietly, so as not to disturb the situation, Sophorica
followed. She didn’t care for the way George treated his sister, but
without a wish, there was nothing she could do. Susie occasionally
glanced at her in perplexity over the fact her brother couldn’t see
her.</p>
<p>She protested and pointed again, with her free hand, “But she’s right
there!”</p>
<p>“There’s no one there!” George groaned and pulled her along, walking
too fast for his sister’s short legs, forcing her to run, to avoid being
dragged.</p>
<p>One short walk/run later, they arrived at a run-down apartment
building that was rather old, but still serviceable. After a ride in an
elderly elevator, they entered an apartment.</p>
<p>George and Susie, both surprised, looked on the smiling face of their
father, standing beside the crying form of their mother.</p>
<p>The children spoke at the same time, surprised by the unexpected
change in their home, “Dad?”</p>
<p>The man rushed to his children and hugged them both, whispering
through tears of joy, “I’m home and I’m never leaving again!”</p>
<p>When her father let go of her, Susie turned and looked at Sophorica,
saying, “Thank you. I’m so happy!”</p>
<p>Not seeing the Fairy Godmother in the room, her father asked, “Who
are you talking to?”</p>
<p>Sophorica felt her connection to the child fade and a sudden burst of
magic was released, affecting only the girl. As Sophorica faded from
Susie’s sight and memories, she turned back to her father and hugged him
tight, crying and happy.</p>
<p>The new Fairy Godmother was pleased to have changed Susie’s life in a
positive way. She hoped the parents would stay together, too. She’d
given them a slight, magical nudge, but the feelings they were acting on
were real.</p>
<p>She decided to embarrass her monarch by embracing her new role and
even going that extra little bit further.</p>
<p>She quietly vowed, to herself, “I’ll be the best Fairy Godmother the
mortal world had ever seen!”</p>
<p>With nothing left for her to do, she felt a bond form with a new
charge and the magic, acting of its own accord, whisked her away in a
burst of unseen sparkles.</p>
<hr />
<p>The Queen of the Fairies ground her teeth together at the sight of
her daughter, reuniting her charge’s family, displayed for all the court
to see, via a large pool of standing water, in the hollow of a tree
trunk, which she’d turned into an impromptu scrying device! Just a
little over three hours! That was a new record! No other Fairy Godmother
had <em>ever</em> helped a charge so quickly!</p>
<p>To her own embarrassment, the court was whispering and murmuring,
already gossiping. Under normal circumstances, she would have beheaded
them all for such an indiscretion, but in this situation, that would
only make her look weak.</p>
<p>As fitting a ruler of the fey court who’d been in power since the
dawn of human civilization, the queen was quite paranoid, imagining the
court was already gossiping about her failure to mete out a fitting
punishment on the princess.</p>
<p>With a mere thought, she warped reality so their words carried to her
ears.</p>
<p>“-see that?” One of the nobles spoke, “The queen, <em>may she reign
forever</em>, must be livid!</p>
<p>The noble’s wife surreptitiously glanced at the queen, “Look at her
face! She looks like she’s about to explode!”</p>
<p>“Shh! She might hear you!”</p>
<p>The queen trembled with rage! How dare her own daughter make a
mockery of her punishment! As she looked on the happy scene in the old
apartment and heard the child say the words that released Sophorica from
service, an idea occurred to the queen. She smiled a wicked smile.</p>
<p>She listened as Sophorica made her silly vow and her evil grin
widened. If her daughter was content to be the best Fairy Godmother to
ever live, then she needed a suitable challenge, a difficult child, with
which to prove herself.</p>
<p>The queen started to laugh the wicked laugh she always used when
plotting an unpleasant fate for others. Seeing the queen’s rapid
adjustment from rage to full-bore sadistic laughter, the whispering and
gossip of the court ceased.</p>
<p>Everyone watched, with baited breath, as the scene in the scrying
pool changed.</p>
<h2 id="second-charge">Second Charge</h2>
<p>Sophorica found herself in the park, once more, surrounded by
children, unseen and unheard.</p>
<p>She knew she had a new charge, she could feel it in her heart, but
she didn’t know who they were and there were numerous children to pick
from. She closed her eyes and listened, hoping her Fairy Godmother
instincts would kick in again when she heard their voice.</p>
<p>The general hubbub of children at play washed over her and she caught
snippets of conversation about games, toys and various imaginary
concepts, including a dragon.</p>
<p>Her brow creased as she heard a distant cry of pain, but knew it
wasn’t her charge. As she listened to a child whimpering, she wished
there was something she could do.</p>
<p>Then she heard the voice, knowing in her heart, it was the one, “Give
me your money or I’ll break your arm!”</p>
<p>Her heart sunk about as low as it could go: she’d been assigned to a
bully! Her imagination ran wild with the horrendous possibilities of
being forced to torture other children with her magic!</p>
<p>Opening her eyes, she peered across the park, seeing a muscular teen
holding a boy of ten years against the cinder block wall of the back
side of the restrooms.</p>
<p>As she walked over, the younger boy produced a few dollars and handed
them over, resulting in his release. The victim scurried away as fast as
possible.</p>
<p>Her charge counted his money and then turned around, allowing
Sophorica a proper view of him. He was no more than fifteen years old,
with blond hair dyed blue in places and some slight evidence of a
poorly-shaved chin, with a few long whiskers the razor missed. He wore a
black T-shirt with the sleeves torn off and blue-jeans. As he pocketed
the money, he looked up, a contrived look of pure innocence on his
face.</p>
<p>“Hey, what’s with the ears?” He asked, “You going to a Star Trek
convention or something?”</p>
<p>Sophorica answered plainly, “I’m a fairy.”</p>
<p>“Hey,” the boy shrugged, “it’s not my place to judge, lady.”</p>
<p>He started walking away.</p>
<p>She called out to him, “Are you happy?”</p>
<hr />
<p>Jimmy paused, confused and upset. What kind of question was that to
ask a stranger? Was anyone in the world happy? As far as he could tell,
the world was a miserable place, full of miserable people, that all
hated each other. How could anyone be happy?</p>
<p>His mom was a drunk, having turned to the bottle after his dad died.
She barely earned enough to feed them both, but her booze clearly came
first. He’d taken to bullying other kids, just to get enough food on the
table. She never asked how he could afford the groceries he brought
home, costing about twice the money she gave him.</p>
<p>He worked hard to be strong, so threats could get him the money he
needed to survive, because actually breaking bones would just bring lots
of trouble.</p>
<p>Every day, every hour, all Jimmy thought about was how to survive.
How in the world could he ever be happy? Just being asked the question
pissed him off! Other kids had it easier. Other kids had rich parents,
that filled their pockets with money <em>and</em> gave them plenty to
eat. Other kids had dads that provided, but his dad was dead and he
couldn’t even remember him.</p>
<p>Why in the world had the gay lady asked him that? Why would she
care?</p>
<hr />
<p>Trembling with anger, the boy turned to Sophorica and shouted, “No,
I’m not! Who in this miserable world is happy?”</p>
<p>“What would it take to make you happy?” She persisted.</p>
<p>Staring at her in shock, for a moment, he turned away, muttering,
“Enough money to survive and a sober mom.”</p>
<p>Sophorica smiled and prompted, sweetly, “Is that a wish?”</p>
<p>“You’re dang right it is, now leave me alone!” He growled.</p>
<p>Hoping the wording was close enough, Sophorica waved her hand,
producing a stream of sparkles.</p>
<hr />
<p>Jimmy arrived home around noon. He was mildly bothered the gay lady
seemed to have followed him home, but wasn’t overly worried. If it came
to a fight, he’d win; she was practically a stick figure. If he had to,
he’d call the cops and they would definitely get her to leave.</p>
<p>As he stepped in the house, his mother, dressed in her nightshirt,
handed him a sealed envelope, addressed to him. For once, she was
sober.</p>
<p>“Open it,” she requested, “I’m dying to find out what it says.”</p>
<p>He checked the return address, surprised to see it had come from a
law office.</p>
<p>Opening it, he read the first few lines and asked, “Do I have an
uncle, named James?”</p>
<p>She nodded, “You do. You were named after him and he’s your
godfather, though I haven’t seen him in more than ten years.” She looked
sad, “We had a big argument and then he stopped visiting.”</p>
<p>Jimmy nodded and gravely informed her, “Well, he died.”</p>
<p>His mother started to cry as he continued reading. He got to the end
and stared at the last line, shocked by what he saw there.</p>
<p>He asked, “The last time you talked with James, what did you fight
about?”</p>
<p>“My drinking habit. He wanted me to quit and…I didn’t want to.”</p>
<p>He handed her the letter, saying, “Is this enough reason?”</p>
<p>As she read, he sat at the kitchen table and thought it over. If his
mom was sober for three months, he’d get a trust fund, giving him more
than enough money to survive and even maybe fix up the house. She also
had to stay sober, or the money would stop coming.</p>
<p>As she finished reading, she started crying and promised, “I’ll get
clean.”</p>
<p>Working together, they went through the entire house and poured every
last drop of booze down the drain. The coming weeks were incredibly
rough on both of them, but Jimmy watched over her as she went through
every stage of withdrawal. She got violently sick for a while, unable to
keep anything down, not even water.</p>
<p>In one of the worst of moments, as his mom lay in bed, hallucinating,
he spoke aloud, with concern, “I wish this were easier for you!”</p>
<p>There was an unexpected flash of light outside the bedroom window and
his mom fell asleep. That was her turning point, where she started to
slowly get better.</p>
<p>When she was well enough, Jimmy helped her go out, to AA meetings,
where she talked things out with other alcoholics.</p>
<p>It turned into one of the hardest times in his life, balancing school
and looking after his mom, but at the same time, he felt more hopeful
than ever. It was strange the way the gay lady asked him what would make
him happy and then it just started happening, as if by magic.</p>
<p>When the time came for them to meet with the lawyer, his mom
presented her three months sobriety chip and the lawyer handed over the
first check.</p>
<p>Jimmy was happy, for the first time he could remember. He knew he
wouldn’t have to worry about survival anymore and his mom was sober.</p>
<p>When they got home, he told his mom how he felt, saying, “Thank you
for doing this for me. I’m so happy you’re sober and we don’t have to
worry about money anymore!”</p>
<p>As they hugged, there was a bright flash of light outside, which
Jimmy promptly forgot all about, along with all his memories of the gay
lady.</p>
<hr />
<p>The queen was furious! The most difficult child she could come up
with on short notice and Sophorica practically side-stepped it, making
the child happy with only two wishes! It had taken three months, but
that had been easy to fast-forward through, by manipulating the flow of
time.</p>
<p>Once more, the court was whispering and the queen heard a suppressed
snigger. He blood boiled with rage at the indignity of it! <em>How dare
they snigger at their queen!</em></p>
<p>She opened her mouth, to speak her nearly-favorite words, but with a
moment’s pause, thought better of it. There were already too many
Dullahan and it would make her appear weak, something she couldn’t
afford. No, punishing the court wasn’t the right answer, even though it
would have been satisfying.</p>
<p>She turned her attention to her daughter’s charge, hearing the boy
speak the words releasing Sophorica.</p>
<p>This time, she would have to find the vilest of children, a true
monster, without remorse or conscience, but…no. She couldn’t actually
give her an impossible charge. She had to find the most broken child she
could, but there always had to be a chance, no matter how small.
Freezing time in the court, she stepped out, spending several weeks on
research, only to return, as if nothing had happened.</p>
<p>Once again, her face became a mask of evil delight as she worked the
minor magic that would take Sophorica to her next charge.</p>
<p>The view in the scrying pool refocused on the exterior of a prison,
with an open-air yard surrounded by fences topped with barbed wire.
Sophorica stood there and looked on the prison, a look of surprise on
her face.</p>
<p>There was an outcry from a member of the court, namely Coyote, “My
queen<em>, may you reign forever,</em> if I may be so bold, by all our
laws, it has to be possible for Sophorica to complete her task without
raising suspicion! If her charge is in that prison, then you must allow
her the use of some of her powers, just to get close!”</p>
<p>The queen grumbled, seeing the logic of The Trickster’s words, so she
asked, “And what did you have in mind?”</p>
<p>“Shape-shifting and simple illusions, to appear in human form, with
appropriate props, that she may visit her charge.”</p>
<p>The queen spoke with reluctance, unable to refute his logic, “Very
well. She may use her power to appear in human form and provide herself
with appropriate glamours, to avoid raising suspicion.”</p>
<h2 id="third-charge">Third Charge</h2>
<p>Sophorica looked on the prison. On one side, there were high fences,
with barbed wire. On the other side, there was a parking lot for prison
workers and visitors. The entrance was at the front, through which
visitors might enter or a released prisoner might exit. Along the street
was a bus stop and opposite the prison was an empty field, full of scrub
brush.</p>
<p>She was somehow sure her charge was inside, which didn’t bode well.
As she was considering how to determine which of the prisoners was her
charge, a name trotted to the forefront of her mind: Leo Valdez
Pena.</p>
<p>As she was considering how she might enter the prison, she felt two
of her old powers unlock, slightly. She suddenly knew she could
shape-shift, but sensed about the only thing she could do was make her
ears look more human and perhaps adjust the length and style of her
hair. She felt like simple glamours might be possible, as well. With a
few tools with which to do her work, she formed a plan.</p>
<p>First, she hiked down the road about half a mile, in the direction of
the closest city.</p>
<p>She closed her eyes and concentrated on her appearance. Her hair,
which had been hanging as curls, straightened itself and formed into a
tight braid, while her ears shortened and lost their points, making her
look human.</p>
<p>Her dress turned gray and transformed into a smart-looking business
skirt, white blouse and a matching, professional-looking suit coat. Her
shoes remained the same shape, but changed in color, to match her new
outfit. The changes to her clothes were just a glamour and would last
only a few hours without concentration, similar to the limited
shape-shifting of a wand-wielding fairy.</p>
<p>She took a moment to look down at herself, critically. She mostly
looked the part, but she lacked a few small details.</p>
<p>Closing her eyes again, she focused on forming a pair of glasses in
one hand, which she donned, making her look more intellectual. Then, she
focused on forming a leather bag in her other hand, large enough to hold
legal documents. She felt the weight of the heavy bag as it formed, full
of paper and other suitable supplies.</p>
<p>Looking down at the bag through her new glasses, she reflected on the
nature of glamours: solid imagination, real enough to touch, but which
would melt away to nothing, sooner or later. Fairy gold was the
stereotypical example humans had experienced in the past, the ‘reward’
given to humans that demanded riches from a captured fairy. Leprechauns
were particularly prone to giving it out, to avoid giving away their
real treasures.</p>
<p>Glancing both ways down the road, to make sure she was alone, she
willed her invisibility to end and walked back toward the prison, where
she entered.</p>
<p>Presenting a glamour that appeared to be a complicated legal document
regarding her ‘new client’ and her need to see him immediately, she was
ushered through a metal detector, while her bag was put through an X-ray
machine and then briefly opened.</p>
<p>She was guided to a small room with painted cinder block walls
furnished with a table and two chairs. She sat and waited for a time and
then her charge, Leo, was brought in and placed opposite her, by the
guards. He was cuffed to the table, but had enough freedom of movement
to be able to hold a pen and sign a document, if required.</p>
<p>Leo’s head was shaved and he had the swarthy skin of a Latino. He was
on the cusp of adulthood, probably seventeen. His arms and neck were
covered in tattoos, which Sophorica guessed were gang-related. He wore
the odd black and white stripes that were coming back into fashion for
prison uniforms.</p>
<p>He eyed her critically and she was grateful her outfit wasn’t
particularly revealing.</p>
<p>“Who’re you?” He asked, “They say you’re my lawyer, but I know I
can’t afford you.”</p>
<p>In response, she removed a small business card from her bag and set
it in front of him.</p>
<p>As he watched, in surprise, the text of the card changed from that of
a plain, boring lawyer’s business card to read as follows:</p>
<p><em>Sophorica, your Fairy Godmother.</em></p>
<p><em>My job is to make you happy, by granting your wishes.</em></p>
<p>She stared in mild horror at the last part, having not intended it,
but it was part of her curse. She couldn’t lie to him and had to tell
the whole truth, but she was grateful she could at least communicate
with him silently.</p>
<p>Leo smiled, “Chido! Nice magic trick, lady.”</p>
<p>Internally, she was very grateful he didn’t believe her. With any
luck, his skepticism would prevent him from making any wishes.</p>
<p>Sophorica asked, with genuine concern, “Are you happy?”</p>
<p>He started to laugh, “I get caught selling drugs, tried as an adult,
I’m thrown in prison with grown men and she asks me if I’m happy?” He
started to cry, “Of course not, lady! I messed up, big time. I should
have capped the pig that arrested me, instead of letting it happen.”</p>
<p>“And would killing him have made you happy?”</p>
<p>“Yeah, sure.” He didn’t look all that sure.</p>
<p>“Really?”</p>
<p>He shrugged, “It would have kept me out of this place.”</p>
<p>“Well, as your-” Sophorica tapped the card on the table, “would you
tell me your story? I’d like to get to know you better, so I can find
some way to help.”</p>
<p>He smiled, “I see no reason to argue with getting to know a beautiful
woman,” his smile faded, “but I need to know: does this stay between us,
like other lawyers? I mean, you’re a bit crazy, with that little magic
trick, but do we have that attorney privilege thing?”</p>
<p>With the certainty she couldn’t break her word to a charge showing on
her face, she vowed, “I give you my word, I’ll never repeat anything you
share in confidence.”</p>
<p>Sighing, he began, “When I was six, my parents died in a car
accident. With no one else to take care of me, my cousin, Gabriel, took
me in. He didn’t work much, but he always had money. Turns out he was a
drug dealer, working for the cartel.</p>
<p>“By the time I was eleven, he was paying me to deliver drugs, cause
who would expect a kid to have drugs? His buyers liked the whole
delivery service thing he had going and gave me big tips. One guy once
gave me a hundred dollar bill as a tip, but he was high as a kite, in
the middle of a big party with his friends, showing off. Gabriel always
told me just by being there, I helped him bring home more cash.</p>
<p>“Two years later, I was working my own little corner of the
neighborhood, always with one of his guys watching my back. They all
treated me like a little brother and I felt like I had a big family.
They always gave me a heads-up if the pigs were on the street.</p>
<p>“When I was fifteen, my cousin gave me a gun, to defend myself. I
always kept it on me and I even threatened a guy with it once, when he
gave me lip over the prices, but I never wanted to use it.</p>
<p>“Then, out of the blue, just a few months ago, a cop showed up and
wouldn’t leave me alone. Turned out, the guy that was supposed to have
my back was gone, off getting a drink. I argued with the pig for a bit
and then, in the tussle, I dropped some of the product.</p>
<p>“The pig saw it and went for his gun, but I was faster. I put it
right to his head,” Leo’s rough exterior faded and he started to cry,
“but I couldn’t do it! If I’d just pulled that trigger, I’d still be
free!”</p>
<p>“What did you do?” Sophorica prompted.</p>
<p>Leo finished, “I put it down and he arrested me. He was nice about it
during the trial and spoke up for me, saying I seemed like a nice kid
who’d just got in too deep. It didn’t help.”</p>
<p>She considered and asked, “What do you think would make you
happy?”</p>
<p>He chuckled, “There you go again, talking about happiness, like it’s
easy to find.”</p>
<p>“I’m just trying to help.” She tried again, “Most lawyers would only
be concerned with defending you, but as your-” she tapped the business
card again, “-my concerns run deeper than that. So, please tell me, what
would make you happy?”</p>
<p>“Well,” Leo considered, “I guess a fresh start, somewhere new, with
everything squared away with my cousin, so he won’t come looking for
me.”</p>
<p>“Is that a wish, then?” She prompted.</p>
<p>“You’re crazy, you know that?” Leo laughed, “But sure, it’s a
wish.”</p>
<p>Sophorica winked as she raised her hand and whispered,
conspiratorially, “I’m not crazy.”</p>
<p>She waved her hand, producing sparkles in the air, much to the shock
and surprise of her charge!</p>
<hr />
<p>The queen screamed in rage, losing her temper! The Escher-space
outside the room took on a more sinister appearance as the trees became
darker and more gnarled, losing many of their leaves! The room darkened
to the level of starlight, making every shadow appear like monsters as
dry leaves started blowing on a chilly wind!</p>
<p>Nothing she did worked! Sophorica’s talent for her new job was
maddening. The boy she’d been assigned to was practically a hardened
criminal and within the hour, she had him making a wish for greater
happiness! Oh, it would take months to grant, but the deed was already
done!</p>
<p>The queen wracked her brain, looking for a solution, some way to halt
her daughter’s relentless push for freedom.</p>
<p>As she calmed down, in deep thought, she heard the whispers, coming
from every corner of the room, louder than ever! If things continued as
they were, she would be finished as queen, through the actions of her
upstart child! If she didn’t find some way to save face, she was certain
the nobles would band together. It was the last measure, meant to ensure
the ruling fairy stayed strong: she could be removed from the throne by
a unanimous vote of no confidence from the nobles of the court.</p>
<hr />
<p>Months passed and Leo’s actual lawyer managed to get him out of
prison, on a technicality. Remembering the crazy fairy’s obsession with
his happiness, he talked things out with his cousin and squared
everything.</p>
<p>As a sort of apology for involving him in the family business,
Gabriel gave him a fat roll of bills and wished him well, surprising him
quite a bit. From all he’d heard, it was really rare for the cartel to
let someone out, but sometimes, for family, it could be done.</p>
<p>Leo moved to a new city and got a job at a car wash, detailing
cars.</p>
<p>After a month of working, while he was adding up a day worth of
receipts for his boss, the crazy fairy showed up, her ears long and
pointed, reminding him of Spock. She wore a blue dress with gold
trim.</p>
<p>She smiled and asked, “Are you happy?”</p>
<p>“Yeah, I am.” He smiled back, “Thank you.”</p>
<p>“I’m glad I could help.”</p>
<p>There was a burst of light from her and she slowly faded from his
sight. When he couldn’t see her anymore, he couldn’t remember her,
either. He got back to work, unsure of why he’d stopped.</p>
<h2 id="the-only-winning-move">The Only Winning Move</h2>
<p>Years passed in the blink of an eye as the queen manipulated the flow
of time, watching Sophorica deal with charge after charge. She was
disgusted by her daughter’s natural talent for being a lowly Fairy
Godmother. Where most that were punished with the job were only
interested in ending their servitude, she seemed genuinely interested in
helping her charges, easily getting them to open up, simply by asking in
a concerned tone, if they were happy.</p>
<p>The gossip in the background raised in volume and the queen hated
them for it, but there was nothing she could do, not without making
things worse. She wanted to kill them all, since they’d witnessed her
shame. She wanted to silence them, but there was no way. Most of all,
she wanted to see Sophorica fail.</p>
<p>She considered her options as she watched her daughter help a child
to happiness in just a few minutes, flat, setting a new record! She had
no choice. If she was to retain the throne, she had to take a risk.
Sophorica <em>had to fail</em> and the only way the queen could think of
to do it was to cheat.</p>
<p>From the perspective of the court, the queen briefly blurred and then
she grinned, slightly. It wasn’t her classic, evil smile, but rather the
smile of one who’d been disappointed multiple times and was now only
hopeful, rather than sure.</p>
<p>In that same instant the queen blurred, Jenessica vanished.</p>
<p>The gossiping court’s volume went up this time, not down.</p>
<hr />
<p>Sophorica found herself in the bedroom of a little girl with long,
brown hair and brown eyes. She couldn’t have been more than eight years
old. She wore a plastic tiara and a tiny, pink watch.</p>
<p>She sat at a small table, which had been set for a pretend tea party,
with the guests being a few Barbie dolls, a stuffed toy pig that was
dressed up as a pirate, including an eye patch, and a toy that looked
like a fluffy white-furred humanoid cat wearing a pink dress. To one
side of the short table was an open picture book, displaying the scene
where Cinderella met her Fairy Godmother.</p>
<p>They looked into each other’s eyes and the girl smiled, immediately
asking, “Are you my Fairy Godmother?”</p>
<p>“I am and-”</p>
<p>“Do you grant wishes?” The girl interrupted.</p>
<p>“I do, but-”</p>
<p>“I wish…”</p>
<hr />
<p>Sophorica was finding her new charge exhausting. Based on the sheer
volume of toys in the luxuriously large bedroom, the selfish brat
clearly had rich parents that gave her everything, aside from their
time, and still, she wished for everything under the sun, as though
trying to fill the void with toys and snacks!</p>
<p>She knew what the girl needed: time with her parents, but as things
were, she’d never get the child to ask for it. The only reason she knew
the kid’s name was Jenny, was because the family butler came by to offer
her lunch, speaking to her by name.</p>
<p>As soon as the meal was over and the butler left them alone, once
more, the torrent of wishes continued!</p>
<p>The only breaks she got were when the child excused herself to go to
the restroom, with startlingly frequency. Sophorica imagined she had
some kind of health issue or a smaller than average bladder.</p>
<p>By the time the day was done and the girl got ready for bed,
Sophorica was grateful, for her arm had gotten tired from waving new
toys into existence all day.</p>
<p>The old butler came to tell her goodnight and read her a story,
saying, “Regretfully, young miss, your parents could not be with you
this evening. They wanted me to tell you they love you, however.”</p>
<p>When the old guy had left, turning the lights out, Jenny started to
cry.</p>
<p>Sophorica started, “If you’d like-”</p>
<p>“I wish you’d shut up and leave me alone for the night!” Jenny
ordered and covered her head with her pillow, still crying.</p>
<p>Unable to protest, Sophorica found herself marching out of the room,
where she quietly opened and closed the door. She spent the night
sleeping in an old chair tucked into the corner of the hallway of the
luxurious mansion. She’d gotten used to sleeping when and where she
could. At least she was indoors, for once. She normally slept in the
back yards of her charges, since their homes were too small for her to
avoid suspicion.</p>
<hr />
<p>The second day with Jenny brought a fresh torrent of wishes, each
more selfish than the last.</p>
<p>Sophorica tried many times to get a word in edgewise, only to be
repeatedly interrupted by wishes and then she was eventually ordered, “I
wish your mouth was glued shut!”</p>
<p>Sophorica watched her arm rise, against her will, to wave! Sparkles
dropped to the floor, and the wish was granted! She breathed through her
nostrils and continued to listen.</p>
<p>As the day wore on, she got depressed and when it was over, she was
once more grateful. This time, she left the bedroom of her own accord.
As she fell asleep in the chair, she felt trapped and beaten. There was
nothing she could do.</p>
<hr />
<p>The queen looked on, in delight, as day after day passed, with
Sophorica making no progress with her new charge. It was a pleasant
change of pace, seeing her daughter struggle so, as she was meant
to!</p>
<p>The gossip of the court continued, but the queen was confident they
were talking about her daughter, instead of their queen.</p>
<p>She was proud of herself and all it had taken was a bag full of lies,
the help of a faithful servant, who just so happened to hate Sophprica,
and a dollop of magic.</p>
<hr />
<p>Sophorica was beginning to get curious about Jenny’s health issue.
She went to the restroom nearly once an hour while she was awake! That
couldn’t possibly be normal.</p>
<p>Purely out of concern for her charge, she surreptitiously followed
Jenny to the restroom and pressed her ear to the door, hoping to get
some clue as to what was going on, so she might help.</p>
<p>“No, no, no!” An adult woman spoke, inside the bathroom, “Now isn’t
the time to argue! Our queen, <em>may she reign forever</em>, has given
us a task! We must complete it!”</p>
<p>There was a pause, during which Sophorica realized she knew the
voice, but couldn’t quite place it. It was definitely a fairy,
though.</p>
<p>“Very well, then. I’ll give you a long rest after this is over. Will
that do?”</p>
<p>That voice was so <em>familiar</em>, but who was it? It was driving
her crazy.</p>
<p>“Good, then we have an agreement?”</p>
<p>She imagined her charge was quietly talking with the fairy, which
didn’t make any sense and implied her monarch had taken an active hand,
which was quite against the rules. Perhaps she’d promised the child a
wish Sophorica wasn’t able to grant. Sophorica was powerful, but she had
her limits, while her monarch seemed to have no limits.</p>
<p>“Good. Now do your part, because I have to go!”</p>
<p>There was a bright flash of light, spilling out around the edges of
the door and the sound of a flushing toilet. Sophorica took it as her
cue to run back to Jenny’s room.</p>
<p>When the girl returned, the stream of non-stop wishing continued.
Sophorica endured it until the child headed for the bathroom again. Once
more pressing her ear to the door, she listened.</p>
<p>The fairy spoke, “We need to find a way to make the spell last
longer! She might get suspicious. Can you imagine what would happen if
she started listening at the door?”</p>
<p><em>Who was it?</em> The female fairy’s voice was so familiar, but it
had been years since she’d heard the voice of another fairy.</p>
<p>“No, no, I’m sorry. I know you’re doing your best.”</p>
<p>She closed her eyes and tried to picture the face attached to the
voice.</p>
<p>“Oh, you! You’re right, the <em>princess</em> is so stupid, she’ll
never figure it out!”</p>
<p>The glue on Sophorica’s lips crumbled away, for the way the word
‘princess’ had been spoken caused her to remembered who it was and that
gave her evidence enough to know her monarch had cheated, for the fairy
in the restroom was Jenessica, her former jailer. Knowing the rules had
been violated, Sophorica felt her power unfold to its full potential.
Thinking of the name of the child, Jenny, it should have been obvious:
<em>Jenny and Jenessica were one and the same!</em></p>
<p>With a wave of her hand, the door to the restroom became like a
one-way mirror, allowing her to see her former jailer standing in the
room, alone, holding her wand up, as though having a conversation with
it! She’d always wondered why she only heard one voice outside her cell
and now, she knew. The fairy was so lonely, her wand had become her only
friend and she was probably crazy. If Sophorica hadn’t been so angry,
she might have pitied the woman.</p>
<p>With another wave of her hand, the spell she’d placed on the door
ended and she vanished.</p>
<h2 id="another-fairys-day-in-court">Another Fairy’s Day in Court</h2>
<p>“Did you hear what she did?” The whisper carried through the cell
door, clearly intentionally. It was a cultured, snobbish, female
voice.</p>
<p>“Oh, yes.” Another fairy answered, “I was there. As you may recall,
the monarch used a scrying pool to watch the entire thing! I just wish
you could have been there!”</p>
<p>“Oh, you!” Jenessica laughed, “I was on Earth at the time, following
orders.”</p>
<p>“Yeah, can’t blame you for that. It would have been ‘Off with her
head!’ if you hadn’t done what she said.”</p>
<p>The two women giggled, together, as the queen did her best to ignore
them. She hated being the subject of gossip, but with the vote of no
confidence having ousted her from the throne, there was nothing she
could do, other than wait. It had been a long month in confinement,
though the food and wine were good, despite the recently-installed iron
bars on the window.</p>
<p>Clearly, her former court thought she was a flight risk. If she’d
been able to, she would have reality warped her way out of the
situation, but even with her incredible power, defying the entire court
was impossible. No, the cell was quite secure and the comforts of it
were starting to really bother her, knowing she would soon be without
them, for her status as a noble was sure to be stripped, if the new
ruler even allowed her to live. After all, she’d been caught, with the
entire court as witnesses, because she’d insisted her daughter’s
punishment be a public spectacle.</p>
<p>There was a distant fanfare, sounding like the arrival of the royal
procession! The court had finally selected a ruler and as the former
queen, her trial would be the first order of business. She sighed, in
frustration.</p>
<p>There was a polite rap at the door.</p>
<p>The former queen stepped up to the mirror and checked her outfit. She
still looked every part the queen. She decided to go down with pride, to
her final moment, if necessary.</p>
<p>Summoning her most imperious tone, she commanded, “Enter.”</p>
<p>Jenessica and her new partner, a river-fey with green hair, blue skin
and black eyes, stepped into the room.</p>
<p>Jenessica spoke, “Oh, you! It’s time for your trial, queenie, <em>may
you rot forever</em>!” The snob laughed, “I do, <em>so</em> look forward
to hearing your fate!”</p>
<p>The former queen’s teeth ground together. Clearly, the court had
overturned her decree regarding royal respect, freeing the worm of a
jailer to insult her, right to her face!</p>
<p>She considered turning Jenessica into the maggot she was, but there
was no point. The court would just undo it, quite quickly.</p>
<p>The former queen submitted and followed Jenessica’s orders, walking
the halls, headed for the throne room. They entered, looking on the gold
and silver supports under the glass-topped surfaces of the tables set
aside for the court, while the new ruler was standing beside the throne
on its raised dais, wearing a white dress, trimmed with gold, her red
hair cascading down her back.</p>
<p>She didn’t recognize the fairy, but with the ability of nobles to
change their shape, at will, she could be anyone. Until she spoke, she
would never know who it was, for fey could always know each other by
voice and word, even if their voice was different.</p>
<p>Jenessica led her into the room, to a seat set aside specifically for
the accused.</p>
<p>When the new queen rapped for attention and everyone was seated, the
prosecutor read a long list of charges, indicating every last thing the
old queen had ever done on the throne that anyone might ever dare to
disagree with, at the last ending with her manipulation of Sophorica’s
service as a Fairy Godmother, with the intent of trapping her in the
job.</p>
<p>The new queen remained silent.</p>
<p>Witnesses were called, who all eagerly testified, with the last being
Jenessica, who supplied, “The former queen specifically instructed me to
prevent Sophorica from completing her task as a Fairy Godmother. I knew
it was wrong, of course, but when facing a tyrant with the power to have
you killed, or worse, what more can you say than, ‘Yes, ma’am’?”</p>
<p>The new queen stood and finally spoke, “What do you have to say for
yourself, my former queen, <em>may you rot forever</em>?”</p>
<p>The old queen finally knew the identity of the new queen: despite
outward changes, she would always know the voice of her only daughter,
Sophorica!</p>
<p>The old queen stood and explained, “All I did was for the best of the
kingdom.”</p>
<p>Soophorica commanded, “Never, ever lie again, mother, now answer the
question!”</p>
<p>She felt the power of the new queen, backed up by the court, infusing
her mind and body, changing her, forever. Everyone in the court, aside
from the former and new queens, cringed, for stripping a fey of the
ability to lie had never been done before! It was unthinkable that
anyone would!</p>
<p>Unable to lie, she started to cry, in visible pain as she spoke
honestly, “I did it all for my own ego. I can’t defend my actions.” She
hung her head in shame, her last veneer of pride shattered.</p>
<p>Sophorica considered for a time and spoke, “I pronounce you guilty of
all charges.”</p>
<p>The old queen nodded, asking, through her tears, “What is to be my
punishment?”</p>
<p>Her daughter smiled, slightly, “You’re to serve the children of the
mortal world, as a Fairy Godmother, until you learn humility, or
ten-thousand years have passed, whichever is greater. Your punishment is
to begin immediately!”</p>
<p>With a yelp of surprise, the old queen fell through a portal and was
gone.</p>
<h2 id="may-she-reign-forever">May She Reign Forever</h2>
<p>Coyote joined the new queen as she stepped down from the throne,
saying, “Congratulations on a well-executed plan. How does it feel to be
queen?”</p>
<p>Sophorica smiled, weakly, then touched the gold and emerald crown on
her head, “It’s heavier than I expected. All I wanted was to shake
things up a bit. I never intended to oust the queen from the throne and
never wanted her job, but when the court is unanimous about a request,
how can one argue?”</p>
<p>Coyote winked, “The best ruler is the reluctant one, rather than she
who seeks power.”</p>
<p>She nodded and sighed, “True. I promise to rule with kindness, rather
than an iron fist. I’ll sow peace, instead of fear.”</p>
<p>“Oh, this is going to be fun!” The Trickster grinned, “I had to be so
careful under your mother’s rule, but with you in charge, what might I
get away with? It will be infinitely more fun!”</p>
<p>Sophorica protested, “Hey, don’t stir up trouble already! I haven’t
even settled in, yet.”</p>
<p>“No promises.” Coyote winked and walked away.</p>
<p>She chuckled at his brazen declaration, but in truth, she wasn’t
worried. He was The Trickster, after all. Yes, he tended to sow chaos
wherever he went, but it was always with purpose. He would teach her and
keep her on her toes and, yes, it would be fun.</p>
<p>Coyote would be trouble, but she’d have to remember to take it with
good humor, because he’d likely be quietly supporting her and
manipulating the court, to her advantage, no matter how much trouble he
was in at the moment.</p>
<p>It had been his idea to challenge the queen, after all, something he
slyly offered up while she was drunk out of her skull on wine. She
wondered if the idea really had been inspired by drink or if he’d gotten
her drunk just to get her to follow his crazy plan. She knew she’d never
know the answer, for he never explained himself and never stopped
smiling, making him impossible to read.</p>
<p>Despite The Trickster’s mercurial nature, she trusted him and
probably always would.</p>
<h1 id="end">END</h1>
</div>
]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Science Fiction and Fantasy</title>
<link>https://owentyme.us/index.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/index.html</guid>
<pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 16:36:25 -0600</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<div class="center">
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/images/logo.300x300.png" style="box-shadow:none;" /></p>
</div>
<h1 id="science-fiction-and-fantasy-author">Science Fiction and Fantasy
Author</h1>
<p>I’m <a href="https://owentyme.us/about.html">Owen Tyme</a>, a novelist that writes
fantasy and science fiction. I’m especially fond of mixing the two
genres. I write both novels and short stories.</p>
<p>To learn more, click one of the below covers for my published works
or follow one of the links on this page.</p>
<h2 id="ashen-blades"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/index.html">Ashen
Blades</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/index.html">Ashen Blades</a> centers
around the life of a half-demon girl that calls herself the Hunter,
whose parents were murdered by demons. Joining her crusade against
demon-kind are the Ashen Blades, also known as the Order of Ash and
Smoke, an organization of demon hunters.</p>
<p><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/she-hunts-demons.html"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/images/Cover-SheHuntsDemons.jpeg" /></a> <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/she-goes-to-war.html"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/images/Cover-SheGoesToWar.jpg" /></a> <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/demon-for-president.html"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/images/Cover-DemonForPresident.jpg" /></a> <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/she-seeks-peace.html"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/images/Cover-SheSeeksPeace.jpg" /></a></p>
<h2 id="the-wizards-scion"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/index.html">The
Wizard’s Scion</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/index.html">The Wizard’s Scion</a>
follows the life of a great and powerful wizard’s son, Levi Jacobs, as
he grows from a teenage boy with almost no control over his magic to a
wizard of great power and reputation, that masters the secrets of time
travel.</p>
<p><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/troll-song.html"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/images/Cover-TrollSong.jpeg" /></a> <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/forgotten-legends.html"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/images/Cover-ForgottenLegends.jpeg" /></a> <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/the-third-wish.html"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/images/Cover-TheThirdWish.jpg" /></a> <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/dark-moon.html"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/images/Cover-DarkMoon.jpg" /></a> <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/the-inverted-glass.html"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/images/Cover-TheInvertedGlass.jpg" /></a></p>
<h2 id="sky-children"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/index.html">Sky
Children</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/index.html">Sky Children</a> is a prequel
series to <a href="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/index.html">The Wizard’s
Scion</a>, centered on the adventures of Zechariah Jacobs, an electrical
engineer that crashes on a supposedly unexplored planet, which happens
to give him magical powers via a mysterious virus, making him a
wizard.</p>
<p><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/sky-children.html"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/images/Cover-SkyChildren.jpg" /></a> <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/wrath-of-the-sky.html"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/images/Cover-WrathOfTheSky.jpg" /></a></p>
<h2 id="the-book-of-newts"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/index.html">The
Book of Newts</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/index.html">The Book of Newts</a>
follows the adventures of a witch that uses magic combined with science
to fly through space.</p>
<p><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/starwitch.html"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/images/Cover-Starwitch.jpg" /></a></p>
<h2 id="rumors-of-war-coming-soon"><a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/rumors-of-war/index.html">Rumors of War</a> (Coming
Soon!)</h2>
<p><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/rumors-of-war/index.html#troll-war"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/images/Cover-TrollWar.jpg" /></a></p>
<h2 id="short-stories-free-ebooks"><a href="https://owentyme.us/short_stories.html">Short
Stories (Free Ebooks!)</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://owentyme.us/short_stories.html#shorts">Short of Tyme</a> is a series of
short stories that you can find alongside my novels, in the same online
stores. If you’re on the fence about buying my books, then why not try
something free that’s a little shorter?</p>
<p>In particular, <em>She Goes to Summer Camp</em> will give you a
glimpse into the Ashen Blades series, since it’s part of it.</p>
<p><a href="https://owentyme.us/short_stories.html#emergent-consequences"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/images/Cover-EmergentConsequences.jpeg" /></a> <a
href="https://owentyme.us/short_stories.html#she-goes-to-summer-camp"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/images/Cover-SheGoesToSummerCamp.jpg" /></a> <a
href="https://owentyme.us/short_stories.html#community-service-fairy-godmother"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/images/Cover-CommunityServiceFairyGodmother.jpg" /></a> <a
href="https://owentyme.us/short_stories.html#sweet-surrender"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/images/Cover-SweetSurrender.jpg" /></a></p>
]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>The Book of Newts</title>
<link>https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/index.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/index.html</guid>
<pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 20:06:55 -0600</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<h1 id="the-book-of-newts">The Book of Newts</h1>
<p><span class="book-cover"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/../../images/Cover-TheBookOfNewts.jpg" /></span> <em>The Book of
Newts</em> is a remarkable volume. Paradoxically, while The Book is
exceptionally magical, the information contained within is largely not.
It details every wonder of engineering, science and astronomy that’s
been discovered by its past owners, but this information is only visible
to its owner. To all others, it appears to be a thick volume describing
every variation of newt that has ever existed, in meticulous detail,
complete with hand-drawn illustrations.</p>
<p>The Book yearns for new knowledge. To that end, it inspires those
that own it to ever greater heights, taking them to the stars and
beyond, to reach their greatest potential, but nothing in life comes
without a price and its owners rarely foresee the balance coming
due.</p>
<p>While The Book is sometimes willing to wait, it’s never satisfied and
will always drive its owner to the next horizon, to the next discovery,
that it might grow a little thicker under the weight of new
knowledge.</p>
<p>Throughout history, The Book has been the driving factor behind many
things, particularly the colonization of the stars and terraforming of
many worlds, all to serve its insatiable hunger for more.</p>
<p>Witches and wizards are drawn to the magic of The Book, but woe
betide any that choose to stand in the way of the inevitable march of
progress, because The Book has a will of its own and a terrible power to
subtly bend its owner’s mind, leaving them just as hungry for more
knowledge.</p>
<p>At first, The Book seems like a blessing, but it might also be termed
a curse. That’s because it always seems to draw unwanted attention, but
never to itself, and its owners become magnets for trouble of all sorts.
Accusations of witchcraft often follow them, because science beyond the
wildest imaginings of the common man may as well be magic.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="plan">Release Plan</h2>
<p>Currently, the plan is to release this series in a manner that
resembles television, with episodes consisting of up to four chapters
and seasons about ten episodes long. Each novel of the series will be
analogous to a season of a show.</p>
<p>Each season will be initially free to read on <a
href="https://www.royalroad.com">Royal Road</a> and <a
href="https://www.wattpad.com">Wattpad</a>. When the next season is
ready to be posted, the old season will be published both in Ebook and
print editions, while the versions in their original, online locations
will become one or two episode teasers.</p>
<p>The first season is done and the first chapter was published on
Monday, January 6, 2025. The rest will follow a chapter at a time, every
Monday, Wednesday and Friday.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="starwitch"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/starwitch.html">Starwitch</a></h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/../../images/badges/status-webnovel.svg" /> <img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/../../images/badges/schedule-m-w-f.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/starwitch.html"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/../../images/Cover-Starwitch.jpg" /></a><br />
<a
href="https://www.royalroad.com/fiction/102509/the-book-of-newts">Read
on Royal Road</a><br />
<a href="https://www.wattpad.com/story/386378071-starwitch">Read on
Wattpad</a></span> Volume one is <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/starwitch.html">Starwitch</a>.</p>
<p>The series begins with Amelia Blackwell, a witch with little magic
talent, but a keen mind, described by the previous owner of The Book as
a prodigy. She accepts ownership of it with curiosity and a voracious
desire to read all she can.</p>
<p>The Book soon gets Amelia and her two older sisters into all sorts of
trouble, because the depth of knowledge Amelia demonstrates breeds
jealousy, strife and accusations of witchcraft for all the wrong
reasons.</p>
<p>Eventually, Amelia constructs a vessel she names <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/starwitch.html">Starwitch</a> and the sisters flee the moon they
once called home, to seek peace among the stars. Instead, they find even
greater strife and a hostile pirate queen that consumes the souls of
witches to extend her own life.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="legacy-of-newts">Legacy of Newts</h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/../../images/badges/status-planning.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/../../images/Cover-LegacyOfNewts.jpg" /></span> Volume two is
<em>Legacy of Newts</em> and will involve dealing with the consequences
of events from volume one.</p>
<p>Having defeated the pirate queen to rescue her sisters from serving
as fuel for that ancient witch’s life, Amelia flees, but the undead
witch is furious beyond measure and gives chase, determined to run them
down.</p>
<p>The sisters seek assistance from everyone they’ve befriended at every
port along the way, but no one has any desire to get between the sisters
and their powerful enemy.</p>
<p>There’s soon fighting in every corner of the star system, because the
Dead Queen’s lieutenants smell blood in the water. Things are poised to
go from bad to worse, because sometimes the devil you know is better
than the one waiting to fill the power vacuum…</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="the-next-horizon">The Next Horizon</h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/../../images/badges/status-planning.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/../../images/Cover-TheNextHorizon.jpg" /></span> Volume three is
<em>The Next Horizon</em>. It will provide greater detail on The Book
and the way it interacts with Amelia.</p>
<p>After settling the matter of the pirates, Amelia and her sisters
enjoy a short time of peace, until she begins having dreams and visions
that reveal the way to travel from one star to the next, because The
Book has finally grown impatient.</p>
<p>Amelia initially resists, because she desires to return to the moon
she was born on, that she might reconnect with a man she fell in love
with, but The Book won’t leave her alone and becomes a source of great
frustration.</p>
<p>When the conflict comes to a head, The Book refuses to cooperate and
takes back the gifts it’s been quietly imparting. As a result, Amelia
discovers it has been bolstering her exceptional ability with
mathematics and piloting. Left to her own devices, the task of
navigating space becomes potentially deadly, because she can no longer
perform the required calculations in her head.</p>
<p>The journey home becomes perilous and tediously long, compared to
just days before, as everything that can get in the way does and she’s
forced to repeatedly check her math on paper, because her life is on the
line.</p>
<p>Just as Amelia and her sisters are struggling with that, they
encounter a duo of deadly witches they left behind and hoped never to
see again, who have since learned to fly through space and wish for a
helping of revenge.</p>
<p>Will Amelia survive long enough to reignite the love she once had, or
will she be forced to give up her greatest desire, just to satisfy The
Book?</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="witchhome">Witchhome</h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/../../images/badges/status-planning.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/../../images/Cover-Witchhome.jpg" /></span> In volume four, titled
<em>Witchhome</em>, Amelia will arrive at a compromise with The Book
they can both live with.</p>
<p>Amelia builds a magic, flying city to serve as a home and place of
refuge while she explores space, a compromise between her desire to put
down roots and the ceaseless need of The Book to go further.</p>
<p>Her massive construction project soon draws attention from all over
the system. Witches and wizards flock to her cause, drawn like moths to
a flame by the potential. Dwarves first supply the resources required,
but soon see the allure of the project and lend a helping hand, that
they might find the same kind of refuge from prejudice.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, it isn’t all good news, and the locals of Amelia’s
home moon soon rise up, to burn the “cursed city of witches” to the
ground. To avoid all-out war, Amelia’s people are forced to launch
early, before even basic safety measures can be tested.</p>
<p>Will Amelia manage to have her cake and eat it too, or will all the
troubles she seeks to escape finally catch up to her? Will her people be
able to finish their work along the way, or will <em>Witchhome</em> come
apart before they can reach assistance?</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="beyond-the-horizon">Beyond the Horizon</h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/../../images/badges/status-planning.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/../../images/Cover-BeyondTheHorizon.jpg" /></span> In volume five,
<em>Beyond the Horizon</em>, Amelia will finally begin exploring, as the
means to find a place her people can call home.</p>
<p>Amelia flies her magic city full of brave witches, wizards and
dwarves to unexplored space, for the sake of establishing a colony where
they won’t be persecuted for their magical talents.</p>
<p>They carry with them seeds and animals of every kind, with which to
make a new home, plus a population composed of every walk of life,
including every skill that might be required both along the way and at
their destination.</p>
<p>The journey is perilous beyond measure, with strange encounters
aplenty, including lethal space weather, aliens with unfathomable
motives and a hazardous encounter with a black hole.</p>
<p>Will Amelia’s people be able to find a world suitable for
terraforming and the construction of a new home, or will their journey
end with disaster, for over-reaching their grasp? Will Amelia be able to
resist naming that planet Witchworld?</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Jigsaw City</title>
<link>https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/index.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/index.html</guid>
<pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 19:35:43 -0600</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<h1 id="series">Jigsaw City</h1>
<p><em>Jigsaw City</em> is a sequel series to <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/../wizards-scion/index.html">The Wizard’s Scion</a>, centered
around the life of Levi’s daughter, Nicole Jacobs, and her quest to
reunite the pieces of a magical city that was broken up millions of
years before she was born.</p>
<p>This series is currently unpublished.</p>
<h2 id="jigsaw-city">Jigsaw City</h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/../../images/badges/status-done.svg" /></p>
<blockquote>
<p><span class="book-cover"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/../../images/Cover-JigsawCity.jpg" /></span> Nicole Jacobs is
twenty years old and unsure what direction to take in life, becuase the
opportunities available to her are too numerous and no one job fits all
of her talents, but she passes the time doing research on dragons. To
that end, she hatches a dragon egg, but in the midst of the harrowing
work required, she dreams of the ancient, magical City of Kurg, which
yearns to be whole.</p>
<p>She soon discovers, based on a chance encounter with a small magic
item she’d been analyzing, that her mind has been dangerously
intertwined with that of the city, which spreads through her brain like
a disease, slowly taking over. At first, she’s able to keep it under
control by suppressing magic within her own head, but over time, it
begins breaking past the road blocks she desperately erects in its path
as it inches toward total control.</p>
<p>Seeking a cure, she’s forced to research the ancient city, while the
clock ticks down on her sanity and ultimately, her life. Meeting the
strange, stone men that made the city, the Ulkun, she finds they have
few answers for her, but suggest that if she locates the Architect of
Kurg, one of their own kind, he might be of some help. Unfortunately,
due to the fact he was trapped inside a small segment of the sealed city
for millions of years, alone, he’s quite insane, unhelpful and worse,
eventually becomes hostile, forming a plan for galactic domination.</p>
<p>Instead, Nicole seeks the Life Giver, the mysterious being that
created the Ulkun and ordered the construction of Kurg, while collecting
pieces of the city, in the hopes of attracting their attention.</p>
<p>Will Nicole find a cure, freeing herself from the clutches of Kurg,
or will she she lose control of her own mind, taken over by the magic
city? Will the Architect succeed at replacing everyone in the galaxy
with obedient, magically-animated drones with no will of their own or
will Nicole stop him?</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
</blockquote>
<p>Nicole Jacobs is given a small, hexagonal coin for her twentieth
birthday, but during analysis of the strange, magic trinket, she
accidentally copies the magic item’s base spell into her mind, where it
rapidly expands beyond the original design, slowly consuming her mind
from the inside! Nicole reluctantly seeks out the maker of the item,
hoping to find a cure before it’s too late to save her sanity.</p>
<h2 id="fey-fighters">Fey Fighters</h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/../../images/badges/status-done.svg" /></p>
<blockquote>
<p><span class="book-cover"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/../../images/Cover-FeyFighters.jpg" /></span> Forced to give up
their original home due to the constant incursions of humans, the
fairies long ago retreated from Earth to an out of the way corner of the
galaxy to live in peace, but when humans accidentally stumble upon them,
they aren’t happy and this time, they’re not willing to give up their
home without fighting until either the extinction of themselves or the
human invaders!</p>
<p>However, nothing’s as it seems, because the humans only arrived as
the result of a series of accidents, having been forced to make an
unsafe faster-than-light jump through space to the nearest potentially
habitable system, which resulted in the destruction of their star ship!
With nowhere else to go and faced with the hostile locals, they
staunchly defend themselves against constant fey assault.</p>
<p>Two soldiers on opposite sides, pixie Commander Stargazer Candleflash
and human Sergeant Edwin Harris, find their fates forever entwined,
first by hatred and the desire for revenge, but then, as they crash
together in a rainforest full of danger, they’re forced to work
together, just to survive.</p>
<p>Will these two rivals, who have every reason to hate each other,
survive or will their bickering get them killed? Is it possible a
fragile peace can be forged from their own personal cease-fire or will
the doomsday weapons held by both sides be released, ensuring the
destruction of everyone?</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
</blockquote>
<p>On a distant planet tucked away in a barely explored region of the
galaxy, war breaks out between humans that are forced to land there and
the fairies that left Earth during World War II, because the human race
had become too violent to share a planet with.</p>
<p><em>Fey Fighters</em> introduces true fairies to the setting, who
will also be seen in volume three, where they’ll play a vital role
providing exposition and will also play a part in <em>The Great
Purpose</em>, due to the linked nature of both demons and fey.</p>
<h2 id="collector-of-kurg">Collector of Kurg</h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/../../images/badges/status-planning.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/../../images/Cover-CollectorOfKurg.jpg" /></span> Having accepted
the fact that the City of Kurg is permanently bonded to her mind and
soul, Nicole seeks to collect all of the missing fragments of the
magical city, both on and off her home planet, soon coming into conflict
with rogue trolls, ancient monsters, aliens, gun-slinging snails,
monkeys with crossbows, giants and even fairies.</p>
<p><em>Collector of Kurg</em> will bring Nicole’s adopted mother,
Cha’da, into the series, as Nicole encounters her sailing the wilds of
the world’s ocean.</p>
<p>This one is likely to be a collection of short, but connected tales,
rather than a novel, with each planet visited being its own story.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="baba-yaga-lives">Baba Yaga Lives!</h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/../../images/badges/status-planning.svg" /></p>
<blockquote>
<p><span class="book-cover"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/../../images/Cover-BabaYagaLives.jpg" /></span> Baba Yaga started
out wanting to live a little longer, falling to the temptations of
necromancy to extend her life, gaining a mere decade or so with each
human soul she consumes. Eventually growing dissatisfied with such
meager fare, she turns her attention to consuming the souls of magical
creatures for the extra power they contain and her body slowly becomes
more magic than flesh, transforming her into a thaumavore.</p>
<p>However, with the rise of science and magical creatures of the galaxy
growing wise to her tricks, there’s precious little for her to eat. She
can’t afford the hefty price enchanted items sell for on the galactic
market and finds their weak magic unsatisfying, anyway, but she does
come across a rare and undervalued curio: one of the hexagonal coins
that make up the magical City of Kurg, an object so impossibly filled
with magic, it has the power to resist her every attempt to consume
it!</p>
<p>She seeks to unlock the hidden power of the coin, hoping to extend
her life until the end of time with its nearly limitless magic.
Unfortunately for her, not just anyone can access the magic of Kurg,
something only a city administrator can do. Learning this fact by
touching the mind of the coin, she seeks a conversation with Nicole, the
only available administrator.</p>
<p>Nicole’s quest to collect the missing pieces of the City of Kurg
brings her right to Baba Yaga’s doorstep and since their goals are
nothing alike and totally at odds, the meeting devolves into a magical
duel! War for ownership of the city follows, eventually leading to a
sprawling battle inside the legendary chicken-legged hut of Baba Yaga, a
magically-folded, mind-bending space that would give even M. C. Escher a
headache!</p>
<p>Will Nicole overcome the crone’s superior, time-tested spells or will
Nicole, as an extension of Kurg, become Baba Yaga’s living larder?</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
</blockquote>
<p><em>Baba Yaga Lives!</em> will bring legendary magical creatures to
the city, including Levi’s old familiar, Inorath, because Nicole will
need information on Baba Yaga and many of them are even older than the
ancient witch.</p>
<h2 id="the-great-purpose">The Great Purpose</h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/../../images/badges/status-planning.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/../../images/Cover-TheGreatPurpose.jpg" /></span> In this volume of
<em>Jigsaw City</em>, the true purpose of Kurg is revealed: it was
designed as a powerful weapon for fighting a war that’s as old as the
universe. The Life Giver is back, in need of Nicole and her city’s
power, while the Life Giver’s nemesis, The Void, attempts to invade the
Milky Way, to begin consuming everyone and everything there.</p>
<p><em>The Great Purpose</em> will bring the Hunter from <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/../ashen-blades/index.html">Ashen Blades</a> to the city, to
combat a nearly limitless supply of demons, because they’ve finally
succeeded in opening a stable portal to the galaxy. It will also involve
the Hunter’s arch-nemesis, Vogerath, since the portal was his plan.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="lost-city">Lost City</h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/../../images/badges/status-planning.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/../../images/Cover-LostCity.jpg" /></span> Nicole and the Hunter
may have won the battle with demon-kind and The Void, but the cost is
extremely high: Nicole sacrifices her life for the success of their
crazy suicide mission and the Hunter finally reaches the limits of both
her demon and witch powers, with disastrous consequences.</p>
<p>Nicole’s body is restored by automatic functions of the City of Kurg,
but her mind is shattered by re-birth as its living avatar. Lost,
confused and alone, will Nicole ever return to her home and those she
loves or will she forever wander a dying, parallel universe, seeking a
home she can’t even remember?</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the Hunter is also lost and alone, but in immediate peril.
She emerges from the spatial tear formed by The Void’s final kick at
thirty-thousand feet above a strange, alien planet, with absolutely no
idea where she is. Even worse, she’s lost the power of the elements and
been left to her own devices, totally unable to fly. Will she survive
the fall and find some way to get home or will she remain forever
lost?</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="the-memory-hunt">The Memory Hunt</h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/../../images/badges/status-planning.svg" /></p>
<p>Nicole discovers the fact that her memories were backed up by the
city before she was killed, but unlike her body, it was unable to fully
restore her mind.</p>
<p>Seeking to regain a greater measure of humanity, Nicole goes back to
collecting lost fragments of the City of Kurg, mostly for the sake of
restoring her memories.</p>
<p>This takes her beyond the galaxy she knows, to far-flung areas of the
multiverse, because when the ancient city broke up, parts of it left the
galaxy, while some few traveled to parallel universes.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Sky Children</title>
<link>https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/wrath-of-the-sky.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/wrath-of-the-sky.html</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 06:40:08 -0600</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<h1 id="sky-children">Sky Children</h1>
<blockquote>
<p><span class="book-cover"><a
href="https://books2read.com/WrathOfTheSky"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/../../images/Cover-WrathOfTheSky.jpg" /></a><br />
<a href="https://books2read.com/WrathOfTheSky">Store Links</a></span>
After the hornet’s nest Zechariah Jacobs kicked, by revealing the dark
secrets of the Northwestern Galactic Empire, all he wants is to get
home, but that may not be so easy. The Imperial Intelligence Core is out
for blood and more committed then ever to killing Zech, that they might
more reasonably claim his evidence of the colony they nuked is
false.</p>
<p>Zech and the crew of his star ship battle their way home by the skin
of their teeth, only for Zech to get some awful news: the Empire has
sent an entire fleet, which is packed to the gills with thermonuclear
ordnance and their primary mission is to glass the planet.</p>
<p>Zech and friends seek all the allies they can get, reaching out to
ogres and a remote village that turns out to be far more than meets the
eye, while an ex-pirate officer of his ship requests space pirate and
even alien aid. Meanwhile, Zech and the wizard he’s apprenticed to work
to mix magic and technology, to build weapons they hope will turn the
tide of war, including teleporters, energy shields and multifunction
guns that shoot spells, based on software.</p>
<p>Friendly ships arrive in orbit to help, but in too few numbers,
compared to the colossal fleet the Empire has fielded. Will Zech and his
friends survive the terrible fury of the Empire or will they lose
everything they love, including the very ground they stand on?</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="looking-for-more">Looking For More?</h2>
<p>The next book in <a href="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/index.html">Sky Children</a> is <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/index.html#wild-sky">Wild Sky</a>.</p>
]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Sky Children</title>
<link>https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/index.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/index.html</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 06:34:30 -0600</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<h1 id="series">Sky Children</h1>
<p><em>Sky Children</em> is a prequel series to <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/../wizards-scion/index.html">The Wizard’s Scion</a>, centered on
the adventures of Zechariah Jacobs, an electrical engineer that crashes
on a supposedly unexplored planet, which happens to give him magical
powers via a mysterious virus, making him a wizard.</p>
<h2 id="sky-children"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/sky-children.html">Sky Children</a></h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/../../images/badges/status-published.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/sky-children.html"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/../../images/Cover-SkyChildren.jpg" /></a></span> The series starts
with volume one, titled <a href="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/sky-children.html">Sky Children</a>, in
which Zechariah crash lands on an ‘unexplored’ planet, only to uncover a
terrifying government conspiracy to hide the existence of the Mind Fire
virus, which grants magic powers to those infected by it.</p>
<p>Even worse, the intelligence people will do just about anything to
hide the truth, including nuking their own colonies, from orbit. In
point of fact, such a tragedy once happened on Zechariah’s new home
world, using the guise of a quarantine to corral the witnesses, for
extermination.</p>
<p>Learning these facts, Zecharaih vows to do something about it and
eventually, when he and his friends find a buried star ship, they force
that revelation on the entire empire he left behind, because the people
have a right to know.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="wrath-of-the-sky"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/wrath-of-the-sky.html">Wrath of the
Sky</a></h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/../../images/badges/status-done.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/wrath-of-the-sky.html"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/../../images/Cover-WrathOfTheSky.jpg" /></a></span> Volume two is
<a href="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/wrath-of-the-sky.html">Wrath of the Sky</a>.</p>
<p>As a result of revealing the existence of the Mind Fire virus to the
public, Zechariah’s new home world catches the eye of his old nation,
the Northwestern Empire, which sends an invasion fleet of ships,
thousands strong, to wipe out the evidence so the truth can be
erased.</p>
<p>Zechariah and his people work to gain allies and build defenses of
all kinds, ranging from the scientific to the magical.</p>
<p>This book will be available for purchase February 7, 2025.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="wild-sky">Wild Sky</h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/../../images/badges/status-rewrite.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/../../images/Cover-WildSky.jpg" /></span> Volume three is Wild
Sky.</p>
<p>Having settled things with the Northwestern Empire, Zechariah is
contacted by the the new empress, who was on his side of the recent
conflict. With a civil war looming, due to Zechariah’s actions, he and
his people step up to aid her.</p>
<p>However, as things grow more dire, Zechariah seeks to achieve ever
greater feats and falls to the temptation of using rage magic, a
dangerously addictive, but incredibly powerful form of magic. Caught up
in the addiction, he begins to destroy his entire life by hiding it from
everyone.</p>
<p>This book is unpublished.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Sky Children</title>
<link>https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/sky-children.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/sky-children.html</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 06:29:06 -0600</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<h1 id="sky-children">Sky Children</h1>
<blockquote>
<p><span class="book-cover"><a
href="https://books2read.com/SkyChildren"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/../../images/Cover-SkyChildren.jpg" /></a><br />
<a href="https://books2read.com/SkyChildren">Store Links</a></span> In a
far-flung future where humans have colonized much of the galaxy,
Zechariah Jacobs is a colonist sent out by the Northwestern Empire,
aboard a star ship destined for the frontier, but there’s a rebellion on
board and he’s forced to scuttle the ship, on the captain’s orders.</p>
<p>Launching an escape pod, Zechariah lands alone, on an “unexplored”
planet. Knowing help is months, if not years away, he explores. He finds
plant and animal life remarkably similar to what his colony ship would
have seeded and shortly after encounters remarkably human-looking
natives, with pointed ears!</p>
<p>As he’s taught the local language, he learns the forest-dwelling
locals are elves and just beyond the hill is a village of dwarves. He’s
introduced to the dwarves and their leader, Winzon, who calls himself a
“history miner.” Winzon takes him to one of his best finds: an ancient
wrecked space fighter, that’s thousands of years old!</p>
<p>Zechariah accesses the black box, discovering his people used a
quarantine as an excuse to nuke one of their own colonies from orbit,
seeing awful images of the fighter gunning down the survivors, leaving
him wondering why!</p>
<p>Almost as if in answer, he catches an illness called “Mind Fire,”
which grants him strange, magic powers that defy science!</p>
<p>Using magic and technology, he helps Winzon’s search for more tech,
eventually discovering a star ship! Feeling disquieted by what they
know, they gather a crew for the ship, teach them using software left in
the ship’s computer, then go on a mission to visit one of the Empire’s
media hubs, to share all they know with the public.</p>
<p>Will they get the truth out or will the crew of the ship become the
most recent in a long line of victims snuffed out by the empire’s secret
cover-up operation?</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="looking-for-more">Looking For More?</h2>
<p>The next book in <a href="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/index.html">Sky Children</a> is <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/wrath-of-the-sky.html">Wrath of the Sky</a>.</p>
]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Starwitch</title>
<link>https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/starwitch.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/starwitch.html</guid>
<pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 19:44:02 -0600</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<h1 id="starwitch">Starwitch</h1>
<p>Starwitch is volume one of <a href="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/index.html">The Book of
Newts</a>, which follows the adventures and trials of a witch that owns
a magical book detailing many secrets of science, engineering, magic and
most particularly, space travel.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><span class="book-cover"><a
href="https://www.royalroad.com/fiction/102509/the-book-of-newts"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/../../images/Cover-Starwitch.jpg" /></a><br />
<a
href="https://www.royalroad.com/fiction/102509/the-book-of-newts">Read
on Royal Road</a><br />
<a href="https://www.wattpad.com/story/386378071-starwitch">Read on
Wattpad</a></span> Home, safety, and a place to belong – they seem so
easy to find, at least for everyone but Amelia Blackwell and her
sisters, who run from accusations of witchcraft at every turn.</p>
<p>It started so simply, with a book. No one might have predicted that a
book apparently filled with pictures of newts might lead to so much
trouble, but <em>The Book of Newts</em> is no ordinary volume on
taxonomic detail of amphibians. The magic book reveals its true nature
only to Amelia, at the age of ten, teaching her mathematics, science and
engineering – subjects she would not otherwise have been exposed to.</p>
<p>Ironically, she and her sisters are accused of witchcraft for having
built a horseless carriage, because to the ignorant villagers, there’s
no difference between magic and science. They settle in a new land, only
to find the same breed of persecution.</p>
<p>In an unusual ray of hope, they’re told of a distant kingdom that
openly accepts witches, but shortly after they settle there, the light
at the end of the tunnel turns out to be an awful house fire surrounding
their gilded cage: they’re drafted into the local military, because
their new nation uses witches as living weapons.</p>
<p>The sisters accept the idea that peace will never be found on the
ground. Looking to the stars, Amelia builds a space vessel powered by
magic and steam, to carry them to a brighter future, hopefully without
the strife that’s always followed them.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, the people of the stars have their own worries: an
ancient, undead pirate queen, who consumes the souls of powerful witches
to extend her own life. The Dead Queen takes Amelia’s sisters and leaves
the magically-weak engineer to die, all as a sick form of sport.</p>
<p>Will Amelia survive long enough to overcome this greatest of all
threats and rescue her sisters, or will they become fuel to feed the
waning magic of a woman that should have been dead centuries before?</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
</blockquote>
<p><em>Starwitch</em> centers on the life of Amelia Blackwell, the
youngest of a trio of sisters and witches, who start out living on a
moon and eventually use magic to launch themselves into space, to escape
persecution for their witchcraft and various troublesome political
events.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, they eventually encounter the Dead Queen, an ancient
undead pirate witch that consumes the magic and lives of other witches,
to extend her own existence.</p>
<p>The series begins with Amelia aboard her magic light sail ship,
<em>Starwitch</em>, just a few days after it was badly damaged and her
sisters were kidnapped by the Dead Queen, left with only enough
resources to follow the far larger ship.</p>
<p>That’s an intentional and cruel choice by the Dead Queen, because
Amelia’s magic is deemed too weak to consume. She instead left Amelia
for dead in the hopes of some sport, something the Dead Queen has done
to countless weak witches.</p>
<p>Amelia has just enough resources to attack, but not enough to limp to
safety, so unless she gets back either the mythril spell-core of her
ship or at least one of her sisters, she’s a dead woman.</p>
<h2 id="release-schedule-and-details">Release Schedule and Details</h2>
<p>The first chapter was published on Monday, January 6, 2025 and
further chapters will come one at a time, every Monday, Wednesday and
Friday.</p>
]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
