<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
<title>Owen Tyme - Science Fiction and Fantasy Author</title>
<link>https://owentyme.us/</link>
<description>Owen Tyme writes science fiction and fantasy novels</description>
<category>Indie Author</category>
<copyright>Copyright 2025, Owen Tyme</copyright>
<lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 12:00:39 -0600</lastBuildDate>
<pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 12:00:39 -0600</pubDate>
<atom:link href="https://owentyme.us/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<item>
<title>Jigsaw City</title>
<link>https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/index.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/index.html</guid>
<pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 12:00:17 -0600</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<h1 id="series">Jigsaw City</h1>
<p><em>Jigsaw City</em> is a sequel series to <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/../wizards-scion/index.html">The Wizard’s Scion</a>, centered
around the life of Levi’s daughter, Nicole Jacobs, and her quest to
reunite the pieces of a magical city that was broken up millions of
years before she was born.</p>
<h2 id="plan">Release Plan</h2>
<p>Currently, the plan is to release this series a chapter at a time, on
<a href="https://www.royalroad.com">Royal Road</a>. When the second
volume is ready to be posted, the first volume will be published both in
Ebook and print editions, while the versions in their original, online
locations will become short teasers, perhaps six chapters long.</p>
<p>The first chapter of volume one was published on Saturday, March 8,
2025. The rest will follow a chapter at a time, every Tuesday, Thursday
and Saturday.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="jigsaw-city"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/jigsaw-city.html">Jigsaw City</a></h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/../../images/badges/status-webnovel.svg" /> <img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/../../images/badges/schedule-tues-thurs-sat.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/../../images/Cover-JigsawCity.jpg" /></span> Nicole Jacobs is given
a small, hexagonal coin for her twentieth birthday, but during analysis
of the strange, magic trinket, she accidentally copies the magic item’s
base spell into her mind, where it rapidly expands beyond the original
design, slowly consuming her mind from the inside! Nicole reluctantly
seeks out the maker of the item, hoping to find a cure before it’s too
late to save her sanity.</p>
<h2 id="fey-fighters">Fey Fighters</h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/../../images/badges/status-done.svg" /></p>
<blockquote>
<p><span class="book-cover"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/../../images/Cover-FeyFighters.jpg" /></span> Forced to give up
their original home due to the constant incursions of humans, the
fairies long ago retreated from Earth to an out of the way corner of the
galaxy to live in peace, but when humans accidentally stumble upon them,
they aren’t happy and this time, they’re not willing to give up their
home without fighting until either the extinction of themselves or the
human invaders!</p>
<p>However, nothing’s as it seems, because the humans only arrived as
the result of a series of accidents, having been forced to make an
unsafe faster-than-light jump through space to the nearest potentially
habitable system, which resulted in the destruction of their star ship!
With nowhere else to go and faced with the hostile locals, they
staunchly defend themselves against constant fey assault.</p>
<p>Two soldiers on opposite sides, pixie Commander Stargazer Candleflash
and human Sergeant Edwin Harris, find their fates forever entwined,
first by hatred and the desire for revenge, but then, as they crash
together in a rainforest full of danger, they’re forced to work
together, just to survive.</p>
<p>Will these two rivals, who have every reason to hate each other,
survive or will their bickering get them killed? Is it possible a
fragile peace can be forged from their own personal cease-fire or will
the doomsday weapons held by both sides be released, ensuring the
destruction of everyone?</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
</blockquote>
<p>On a distant planet tucked away in a barely explored region of the
galaxy, war breaks out between humans that are forced to land there and
the fairies that left Earth during World War II, because the human race
had become too violent to share a planet with.</p>
<p><em>Fey Fighters</em> introduces true fairies to the setting, who
will also be seen in volume three, where they’ll play a vital role
providing exposition and will also play a part in <em>The Great
Purpose</em>, due to the linked nature of both demons and fey.</p>
<h2 id="collector-of-kurg">Collector of Kurg</h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/../../images/badges/status-planning.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/../../images/Cover-CollectorOfKurg.jpg" /></span> Having accepted
the fact that the City of Kurg is permanently bonded to her mind and
soul, Nicole seeks to collect all of the missing fragments of the
magical city, both on and off her home planet, soon coming into conflict
with rogue trolls, ancient monsters, aliens, gun-slinging snails,
monkeys with crossbows, giants and even fairies.</p>
<p><em>Collector of Kurg</em> will bring Nicole’s adopted mother,
Cha’da, into the series, as Nicole encounters her sailing the wilds of
the world’s ocean.</p>
<p>This one is likely to be a collection of short, but connected tales,
rather than a novel, with each planet visited being its own story.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="baba-yaga-lives">Baba Yaga Lives!</h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/../../images/badges/status-planning.svg" /></p>
<blockquote>
<p><span class="book-cover"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/../../images/Cover-BabaYagaLives.jpg" /></span> Baba Yaga started
out wanting to live a little longer, falling to the temptations of
necromancy to extend her life, gaining a mere decade or so with each
human soul she consumes. Eventually growing dissatisfied with such
meager fare, she turns her attention to consuming the souls of magical
creatures for the extra power they contain and her body slowly becomes
more magic than flesh, transforming her into a thaumavore.</p>
<p>However, with the rise of science and magical creatures of the galaxy
growing wise to her tricks, there’s precious little for her to eat. She
can’t afford the hefty price enchanted items sell for on the galactic
market and finds their weak magic unsatisfying, anyway, but she does
come across a rare and undervalued curio: one of the hexagonal coins
that make up the magical City of Kurg, an object so impossibly filled
with magic, it has the power to resist her every attempt to consume
it!</p>
<p>She seeks to unlock the hidden power of the coin, hoping to extend
her life until the end of time with its nearly limitless magic.
Unfortunately for her, not just anyone can access the magic of Kurg,
something only a city administrator can do. Learning this fact by
touching the mind of the coin, she seeks a conversation with Nicole, the
only available administrator.</p>
<p>Nicole’s quest to collect the missing pieces of the City of Kurg
brings her right to Baba Yaga’s doorstep and since their goals are
nothing alike and totally at odds, the meeting devolves into a magical
duel! War for ownership of the city follows, eventually leading to a
sprawling battle inside the legendary chicken-legged hut of Baba Yaga, a
magically-folded, mind-bending space that would give even M. C. Escher a
headache!</p>
<p>Will Nicole overcome the crone’s superior, time-tested spells or will
Nicole, as an extension of Kurg, become Baba Yaga’s living larder?</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
</blockquote>
<p><em>Baba Yaga Lives!</em> will bring legendary magical creatures to
the city, including Levi’s old familiar, Inorath, because Nicole will
need information on Baba Yaga and many of them are even older than the
ancient witch.</p>
<h2 id="the-great-purpose">The Great Purpose</h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/../../images/badges/status-planning.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/../../images/Cover-TheGreatPurpose.jpg" /></span> In this volume of
<em>Jigsaw City</em>, the true purpose of Kurg is revealed: it was
designed as a powerful weapon for fighting a war that’s as old as the
universe. The Life Giver is back, in need of Nicole and her city’s
power, while the Life Giver’s nemesis, The Void, attempts to invade the
Milky Way, to begin consuming everyone and everything there.</p>
<p><em>The Great Purpose</em> will bring the Hunter from <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/../ashen-blades/index.html">Ashen Blades</a> to the city, to
combat a nearly limitless supply of demons, because they’ve finally
succeeded in opening a stable portal to the galaxy. It will also involve
the Hunter’s arch-nemesis, Vogerath, since the portal was his plan.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="lost-city">Lost City</h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/../../images/badges/status-planning.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/../../images/Cover-LostCity.jpg" /></span> Nicole and the Hunter
may have won the battle with demon-kind and The Void, but the cost is
extremely high: Nicole sacrifices her life for the success of their
crazy suicide mission and the Hunter finally reaches the limits of both
her demon and witch powers, with disastrous consequences.</p>
<p>Nicole’s body is restored by automatic functions of the City of Kurg,
but her mind is shattered by re-birth as its living avatar. Lost,
confused and alone, will Nicole ever return to her home and those she
loves or will she forever wander a dying, parallel universe, seeking a
home she can’t even remember?</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the Hunter is also lost and alone, but in immediate peril.
She emerges from the spatial tear formed by The Void’s final kick at
thirty-thousand feet above a strange, alien planet, with absolutely no
idea where she is. Even worse, she’s lost the power of the elements and
been left to her own devices, totally unable to fly. Will she survive
the fall and find some way to get home or will she remain forever
lost?</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="the-memory-hunt">The Memory Hunt</h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/../../images/badges/status-planning.svg" /></p>
<p>Nicole discovers the fact that her memories were backed up by the
city before she was killed, but unlike her body, it was unable to fully
restore her mind.</p>
<p>Seeking to regain a greater measure of humanity, Nicole goes back to
collecting lost fragments of the City of Kurg, mostly for the sake of
restoring her memories.</p>
<p>This takes her beyond the galaxy she knows, to far-flung areas of the
multiverse, because when the ancient city broke up, parts of it left the
galaxy, while some few traveled to parallel universes.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Jigsaw City</title>
<link>https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/jigsaw-city.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/jigsaw-city.html</guid>
<pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 11:59:38 -0600</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<h1 id="jigsaw-city">Jigsaw City</h1>
<blockquote>
<p><span class="book-cover"><a
href="https://www.royalroad.com/fiction/108234/jigsaw-city"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/../../images/Cover-JigsawCity.jpg" /></a><br />
<a href="https://www.royalroad.com/fiction/108234/jigsaw-city">Read on
Royal Road</a></span> Nicole Jacobs is twenty years old and unsure what
direction to take in life, because the opportunities available to her
are too numerous and no one job fits all of her talents, but she passes
the time doing research on dragons. To that end, she hatches a dragon
egg, but in the midst of the harrowing work required, she dreams of the
ancient, magical City of Kurg, which yearns to be whole.</p>
<p>She soon discovers, based on a chance encounter with a small magic
item she’d been analyzing, that her mind has been dangerously
intertwined with that of the city, which spreads through her brain like
a disease, slowly taking over. At first, she’s able to keep it under
control by suppressing magic within her own head, but over time, it
begins breaking past the road blocks she desperately erects in its path
as it inches toward total control.</p>
<p>Seeking a cure, she’s forced to research the ancient city, while the
clock ticks down on her sanity and ultimately, her life. Meeting the
strange, stone men that made the city, the Ulkun, she finds they have
few answers for her, but suggest that if she locates the Architect of
Kurg, one of their own kind, he might be of some help. Unfortunately,
due to the fact he was trapped inside a small segment of the sealed city
for millions of years, alone, he’s quite insane, unhelpful and worse,
eventually becomes hostile, forming a plan for galactic domination.</p>
<p>Instead, Nicole seeks the Life Giver, the mysterious being that
created the Ulkun and ordered the construction of Kurg, while collecting
pieces of the city, in the hopes of attracting their attention.</p>
<p>Will Nicole find a cure, freeing herself from the clutches of Kurg,
or will she she lose control of her own mind, taken over by the magic
city? Will the Architect succeed at replacing everyone in the galaxy
with obedient, magically-animated drones with no will of their own or
will Nicole stop him?</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="release-schedule-and-details">Release Schedule and Details</h2>
<p>The first chapter was published on Saturday, March 8, 2025 and
further chapters will come one at a time, every Tuesday, Thursday and
Saturday.</p>
<h2 id="looking-for-more">Looking For More?</h2>
<p>The next book in <a href="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/index.html">Jigsaw City</a> is <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/index.html#fey-fighters">Fey Fighters</a>.</p>
]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Science Fiction and Fantasy</title>
<link>https://owentyme.us/index.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/index.html</guid>
<pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 11:58:41 -0600</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<div class="center">
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/images/logo.300x300.png" style="box-shadow:none;" /></p>
</div>
<h1 id="science-fiction-and-fantasy-author">Science Fiction and Fantasy
Author</h1>
<p>I’m <a href="https://owentyme.us/about.html">Owen Tyme</a>, a novelist that writes
fantasy and science fiction. I’m especially fond of mixing the two
genres. I write both novels and short stories.</p>
<p>To learn more, click one of the below covers for my published works
or follow one of the links on this page.</p>
<h2 id="ashen-blades"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/index.html">Ashen
Blades</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/index.html">Ashen Blades</a> centers
around the life of a half-demon girl that calls herself the Hunter,
whose parents were murdered by demons. Joining her crusade against
demon-kind are the Ashen Blades, also known as the Order of Ash and
Smoke, an organization of demon hunters.</p>
<p><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/she-hunts-demons.html"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/images/Cover-SheHuntsDemons.jpeg" /></a> <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/she-goes-to-war.html"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/images/Cover-SheGoesToWar.jpg" /></a> <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/demon-for-president.html"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/images/Cover-DemonForPresident.jpg" /></a> <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/she-seeks-peace.html"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/images/Cover-SheSeeksPeace.jpg" /></a></p>
<h2 id="the-wizards-scion"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/index.html">The
Wizard’s Scion</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/index.html">The Wizard’s Scion</a>
follows the life of a great and powerful wizard’s son, Levi Jacobs, as
he grows from a teenage boy with almost no control over his magic to a
wizard of great power and reputation, that masters the secrets of time
travel.</p>
<p><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/troll-song.html"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/images/Cover-TrollSong.jpeg" /></a> <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/forgotten-legends.html"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/images/Cover-ForgottenLegends.jpeg" /></a> <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/the-third-wish.html"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/images/Cover-TheThirdWish.jpg" /></a> <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/dark-moon.html"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/images/Cover-DarkMoon.jpg" /></a> <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/the-inverted-glass.html"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/images/Cover-TheInvertedGlass.jpg" /></a></p>
<h2 id="sky-children"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/index.html">Sky
Children</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/index.html">Sky Children</a> is a prequel
series to <a href="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/index.html">The Wizard’s
Scion</a>, centered on the adventures of Zechariah Jacobs, an electrical
engineer that crashes on a supposedly unexplored planet, which happens
to give him magical powers via a mysterious virus, making him a
wizard.</p>
<p><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/sky-children.html"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/images/Cover-SkyChildren.jpg" /></a> <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/wrath-of-the-sky.html"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/images/Cover-WrathOfTheSky.jpg" /></a></p>
<h2 id="jigsaw-city"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/index.html">Jigsaw
City</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/index.html">Jigsaw City</a> is a sequel
series to <a href="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/index.html">The Wizard’s
Scion</a>, which centers around a young woman’s quest to reunite the
pieces of a magical city that was broken up millions of years before she
was born, because her mind has been magically bonded to the city.</p>
<p><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/jigsaw-city/jigsaw-city.html"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/images/Cover-JigsawCity.jpg" /></a></p>
<h2 id="the-book-of-newts"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/index.html">The
Book of Newts</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/index.html">The Book of Newts</a>
follows the adventures of a witch that uses magic combined with science
to fly through space.</p>
<p><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/book-of-newts/starwitch.html"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/images/Cover-Starwitch.jpg" /></a></p>
<h2 id="rumors-of-war-coming-soon"><a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/rumors-of-war/index.html">Rumors of War</a> (Coming
Soon!)</h2>
<p><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/rumors-of-war/index.html#troll-war"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/images/Cover-TrollWar.jpg" /></a></p>
<h2 id="short-stories-free-ebooks"><a href="https://owentyme.us/short_stories.html">Short
Stories (Free Ebooks!)</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://owentyme.us/short_stories.html#shorts">Short of Tyme</a> is a series of
short stories that you can find alongside my novels, in the same online
stores. If you’re on the fence about buying my books, then why not try
something free that’s a little shorter?</p>
<p>In particular, <em>She Goes to Summer Camp</em> will give you a
glimpse into the Ashen Blades series, since it’s part of it.</p>
<p><a href="https://owentyme.us/short_stories.html#emergent-consequences"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/images/Cover-EmergentConsequences.jpeg" /></a> <a
href="https://owentyme.us/short_stories.html#she-goes-to-summer-camp"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/images/Cover-SheGoesToSummerCamp.jpg" /></a> <a
href="https://owentyme.us/short_stories.html#community-service-fairy-godmother"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/images/Cover-CommunityServiceFairyGodmother.jpg" /></a> <a
href="https://owentyme.us/short_stories.html#sweet-surrender"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/images/Cover-SweetSurrender.jpg" /></a></p>
]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Dark Moon</title>
<link>https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/dark-moon.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/dark-moon.html</guid>
<pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 11:39:02 -0600</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<h1 id="dark-moon">Dark Moon</h1>
<blockquote>
<p><span class="book-cover"><a
href="https://books2read.com/TymeDarkMoon"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/../../images/Cover-DarkMoon.jpg" /></a><br />
<a href="https://books2read.com/TymeDarkMoon">Store Links</a></span> The
Steel Wizard, Captain Levi Jacobs, second-guesses himself over a shuttle
and her crew that dangerously vanish into deep space. As search and
rescue operations fail to turn up any any trace of them and he’s
pressured to declare them ‘missing, presumed dead’, his worries
grow.</p>
<p>After following a nearly-hopeless trail of bread crumbs, he discovers
the shuttle crew managed to return to their home planet, but were killed
shortly after arriving by a skilled necromancer-witch named Cha’da and
her crew of goblin pirates. With his hopes of rescuing his people
dashed, Levi turns his attention to punishing the responsible party.</p>
<p>In the background, strange mysteries unfold as the invisible moon no
one knew the world had reveals itself as a crescent that grows toward a
full circle in the sky!</p>
<p>As the sun sets and the full moon rises, Levi faces Cha’da in a
magical duel, but nothing is as it appears. Cha’da isn’t evil, having
killed the shuttle crew in self-defense, while subtly trying to redirect
her blood-thirsty pirate crew to a less violent way of life.</p>
<p>As night begins and strange ‘Harbingers of Doom’ from the moon crash
into the ocean, bent on harvesting life energy, the two enemies are
forced to fight back-to-back, just to survive!</p>
<p>Will Levi and Cha’da live long enough to save the world or will the
alien harvesters steal the souls of everyone they love as part of their
dark harvest?</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="looking-for-more">Looking For More?</h2>
<p>The next book in <a href="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/index.html">The Wizard’s Scion</a> is <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/the-inverted-glass.html">The Inverted Glass</a>.</p>
]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Contacting Owen</title>
<link>https://owentyme.us/contact.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/contact.html</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 11:05:39 -0600</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<h1 id="contacting-owen">Contacting Owen</h1>
<p>I very much welcome contact with fans. I’ll gladly answer questions
about my novels or chat about the writing process. Please also feel free
to <em>politely</em> report typos in my work.</p>
<p>Business inquiries regarding adaptations of my work may also be
E-Mailed, but all other business queries will be filed as spam and
likely deleted without response. For example, if you want to do a TV or
movie adaptation of my work, feel free to reach out.</p>
<p>On the other hand, if you’re just trying to sell me something or
promote your services to me, your message will be filed as spam.</p>
<p>I’m especially <strong>NOT</strong> interested in hearing from
advertisers looking to promote my work for a fee. I’ve got my own plans
for promotion and if I receive such a message from you, I’m likely to
pay <em>special</em> attention to it and note the name of your company,
to ensure I <em>never</em> do business with you, because you clearly
ignored these instructions.</p>
<p>In short, <strong>DO NOT</strong> send me spam of any kind.</p>
<p>You can reach me via E-Mail at <a href="mailto:owentyme@yahoo.com"
class="email">owentyme@yahoo.com</a>.</p>
]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Sky Children</title>
<link>https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/wrath-of-the-sky.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/wrath-of-the-sky.html</guid>
<pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2025 08:26:07 -0600</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<h1 id="sky-children">Sky Children</h1>
<blockquote>
<p><span class="book-cover"><a
href="https://books2read.com/WrathOfTheSky"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/../../images/Cover-WrathOfTheSky.jpg" /></a><br />
<a href="https://books2read.com/WrathOfTheSky">Store Links</a></span>
After the hornet’s nest Zechariah Jacobs kicked, by revealing the dark
secrets of the Northwestern Galactic Empire, all he wants is to get
home, but that may not be so easy. The Imperial Intelligence Core is out
for blood and more committed then ever to killing Zech, that they might
more reasonably claim his evidence of the colony they nuked is
false.</p>
<p>Zech and the crew of his star ship battle their way home by the skin
of their teeth, only for Zech to get some awful news: the Empire has
sent an entire fleet, which is packed to the gills with thermonuclear
ordnance and their primary mission is to glass the planet.</p>
<p>Zech and friends seek all the allies they can get, reaching out to
ogres and a remote village that turns out to be far more than meets the
eye, while an ex-pirate officer of his ship requests space pirate and
even alien aid. Meanwhile, Zech and the wizard he’s apprenticed to work
to mix magic and technology, to build weapons they hope will turn the
tide of war, including teleporters, energy shields and multifunction
guns that shoot spells, based on software.</p>
<p>Friendly ships arrive in orbit to help, but in too few numbers,
compared to the colossal fleet the Empire has fielded. Will Zech and his
friends survive the terrible fury of the Empire or will they lose
everything they love, including the very ground they stand on?</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="looking-for-more">Looking For More?</h2>
<p>The next book in <a href="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/index.html">Sky Children</a> is <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/index.html#wild-sky">Wild Sky</a>.</p>
]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Troll Song</title>
<link>https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/troll-song.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/troll-song.html</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 13:44:53 -0600</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<h1 id="troll-song">Troll Song</h1>
<blockquote>
<p><span class="book-cover"><a
href="https://books2read.com/TrollSong"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/../../images/Cover-TrollSong.jpeg" /></a><br />
<a href="https://books2read.com/TrollSong">Store Links</a></span></p>
<p>Lyra never intended to cause the extinction of the troll race, but
when she uses the power of troll song to read the mind of a dwarf, she’s
forced to compare her life of abuse to that of a loving family.</p>
<p>Acting for the good of the world, she betrays her family and her race
by revealing the secrets of the trolls. For the sake of the dwarves,
Lyra kills her oldest sister, creating an opportunity for the dwarves to
defeat a disorganized army composed of their brothers.</p>
<p>The middle sister, Lyra’s childhood nemesis and personal tormentor,
Nicole, is furious beyond all rationality over her youngest sister’s
actions, determined to make Lyra pay, no matter the cost! Death would be
too good for Lyra, so Nicole seeks to telepathically destroy her mind,
instead!</p>
<p>Luring her sister into a trap, Lyra drops an entire mountain of ice
on their heads, intent on ending Nicole at the expense of her own
life!</p>
<p>They wake from their frozen sleep thousands of years later in a world
of wonders both scientific and magical. As Nicole escapes, the contest
begins anew and she gains control of a powerful star ship, intending to
use it as a platform for her vengeance!</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Lyra gains modern allies, including the influential family
and friends of a young wizard, Levi Jacobs.</p>
<p>Will Lyra defeat her murderous sister or will Nicole destroy Lyra’s
mind to fulfill her vow of vengeance? Will Lyra end the troll threat or
will Nicole become a scourge on the entire world, raiding and pillaging
as she sees fit?</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="looking-for-more">Looking For More?</h2>
<p>The next book in <a href="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/index.html">The Wizard’s Scion</a> is <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/wizards-scion/forgotten-legends.html">Forgotten Legends</a>.</p>
]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Sky Children</title>
<link>https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/index.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/index.html</guid>
<pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 17:46:04 -0600</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<h1 id="series">Sky Children</h1>
<p><em>Sky Children</em> is a prequel series to <a
href="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/../wizards-scion/index.html">The Wizard’s Scion</a>, centered on
the adventures of Zechariah Jacobs, an electrical engineer that crashes
on a supposedly unexplored planet, which happens to give him magical
powers via a mysterious virus, making him a wizard.</p>
<h2 id="sky-children"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/sky-children.html">Sky Children</a></h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/../../images/badges/status-published.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/sky-children.html"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/../../images/Cover-SkyChildren.jpg" /></a></span> The series starts
with volume one, titled <a href="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/sky-children.html">Sky Children</a>, in
which Zechariah crash lands on an ‘unexplored’ planet, only to uncover a
terrifying government conspiracy to hide the existence of the Mind Fire
virus, which grants magic powers to those infected by it.</p>
<p>Even worse, the intelligence people will do just about anything to
hide the truth, including nuking their own colonies, from orbit. In
point of fact, such a tragedy once happened on Zechariah’s new home
world, using the guise of a quarantine to corral the witnesses, for
extermination.</p>
<p>Learning these facts, Zecharaih vows to do something about it and
eventually, when he and his friends find a buried star ship, they force
that revelation on the entire empire he left behind, because the people
have a right to know.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="wrath-of-the-sky"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/wrath-of-the-sky.html">Wrath of the
Sky</a></h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/../../images/badges/status-published.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><a href="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/wrath-of-the-sky.html"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/../../images/Cover-WrathOfTheSky.jpg" /></a></span> Volume two is
<a href="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/wrath-of-the-sky.html">Wrath of the Sky</a>.</p>
<p>As a result of revealing the existence of the Mind Fire virus to the
public, Zechariah’s new home world catches the eye of his old nation,
the Northwestern Empire, which sends an invasion fleet of ships,
thousands strong, to wipe out the evidence so the truth can be
erased.</p>
<p>Zechariah and his people work to gain allies and build defenses of
all kinds, ranging from the scientific to the magical.</p>
<p>This book will be available for purchase February 7, 2025.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="wild-sky">Wild Sky</h2>
<p><img src="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/../../images/badges/status-rewrite.svg" /></p>
<p><span class="book-cover"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/books/sky-children/../../images/Cover-WildSky.jpg" /></span> Volume three is Wild
Sky.</p>
<p>Having settled things with the Northwestern Empire, Zechariah is
contacted by the the new empress, who was on his side of the recent
conflict. With a civil war looming, due to Zechariah’s actions, he and
his people step up to aid her.</p>
<p>However, as things grow more dire, Zechariah seeks to achieve ever
greater feats and falls to the temptation of using rage magic, a
dangerously addictive, but incredibly powerful form of magic. Caught up
in the addiction, he begins to destroy his entire life by hiding it from
everyone.</p>
<p>This book is unpublished.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Artemis Watson</title>
<link>https://owentyme.us/characters/ashen-blades/artemis-watson.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/characters/ashen-blades/artemis-watson.html</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 19:48:37 -0600</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<p><span class="book-cover-right" style="max-width: 400px;"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/characters/ashen-blades/ArtemisWatson-15Years-AnimeStyle.jpg"
title="An AI-generated image of Artemis Watson, in 1945" /></span></p>
<h1 id="artemis-watson">Artemis Watson</h1>
<p>Artemis Watson is the protagonist in the series <a
href="https://owentyme.us/characters/ashen-blades/../../books/book-of-newts/index.html">Ashen Blades</a>, though
more technically, she has no name.</p>
<p>She has brown hair, extremely blue eyes and an obsession with wearing
the color black. She always wears the top hat she inherited from her
father. She also perpetually wears gloves. For preference, she prefers
elbow-length, fingerless gloves. This might initially seem to be a
stylistic choice, but there are <a href="https://owentyme.us/characters/ashen-blades/artemis-watson.html#psychology">deeply
psychological reasons for this</a>. She is technically a goth, but she
was dressing that way before the term became popular. In her own mind,
she once thought, “Black is where it’s at.”</p>
<p>She’s a half-demon, half-human girl that was born in 1897, in New
York City. Her mother was a demon witch and her father was a demon
hunter, more specifically an Ashen Blade, which is an organization
dedicated to hunting and eliminating demons on Earth, for the sake of
humanity. This gives her both the powers of a demon and a witch, two
forms of magic that are stronger together.</p>
<p>Artemis looks entirely human at a glance, but that’s only because she
always wears a skirt that hides her tail, which tends to twitch in time
to her mood, much like that of a cat. Combined with the tendency of her
eyes to easily reflect light, a little thought can bring one to the
conclusion she has some traits in common with cats. This is because her
mother had feline traits in demon form, though her demon form was the
size and shape of a regular house cat.</p>
<p>She suffers from a curse from a demon that makes her unable to say
anything other than “It’s a secret”, which tends to really irritate her.
As such, she’s really embraced rude gestures as one of her favorite ways
to communicate.</p>
<p>Due to the nature of demons and the way their true names can be used
to compel them, Artemis was never actually named by her parents and all
the ways that others refer to her are merely nicknames. Personally, she
calls herself ‘the Hunter’, because she considers all demons prey and
has made killing them all her mission in life.</p>
<p>The black market arms dealer she bought her guns from in the 1940’s
gave her the nickname ‘Little Miss Secret’, based on the the only thing
she can say and she was always fond of him, so she loves that nickname.
Her friends often shorten it to just ‘LMS’.</p>
<p>During the third book, she was briefly able to speak her mind and her
private detective partner chose to name her Artemis, rather than calling
her ‘the Hunter’, because that sounded more like a title than a name to
him. Her last name comes from her father, Jake Watson.</p>
<p>Artemis is mischievous, but often cheerful and smiles a lot, at least
when she isn’t angry. Unfortunately, she’s often quite angry. She’s
prone to playing practical jokes, especially with grumpy and serious
people. With demons, her mischievous side becomes extremely cruel,
because she hates them so much.</p>
<p>This is another area in which she takes after a cat and she sometimes
tortures demons to death the way a cat plays with a mouse, though she’s
grown slightly less cruel over time, because demons have sometimes
escaped from her during such moments, leading to her giving them quicker
deaths.</p>
<p>Like a cat, Artemis is extremely smell-oriented, with an ability to
discern humans from demons by scent. She can also use her heightened
sense of smell to fight blind, which gives her great advantages in a
fight.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="special-powers">Special Powers</h2>
<p>Artemis has the powers of both a demon and a witch, though she leans
more heavily on her demon powers, because they came with useful
instincts that tell her how to use them.</p>
<p>Her witch powers have been much slower to mature, but so far, she’s
demonstrated fire magic hot enough to produce blue flame and smoke
magic.</p>
<p>Her demon powers give her the ability to teleport between shadows,
extreme physical durability, great strength, super-human speed and an
enhanced sense of smell. Hypothetically, she’ll also never die of old
age.</p>
<p>Artemis is fond of combining her ability to teleport with her sense
of smell in the dark, allowing her to teleport from enemy to enemy in a
fashion that leaves her opponents terrified about where she might pop up
next.</p>
<p>One of her least favorite powers is the ability to consume demons to
recharge her magical reserves, which is something demons sometimes do to
each other, when they’re feeling peckish. She can’t stand the taste of
them, however.</p>
<p>She combines smoke magic with demon magic to produce solid magical
projections of objects stored in her hat.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<p><span class="book-cover-right" style="max-width: 400px;"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/characters/ashen-blades/AnnmarieNossett-AnimeStyle.jpg"
title="An AI-generated image of the mother of Artemis Watson, who&#39;s named Annmarie Nossett" /></span></p>
<p>The spirit of her mother acts as a living protective spell that that
keeps the world at arms-length from Artemis, unless she chooses to let
someone in.</p>
<p>Anyone that tries to touch her befalls a mysterious, magical accident
brought on by probability manipulation magic. Anyone that intends her
harm tends to experience a deadly accident. Demons are rarely killed by
this effect, due to how durable they are, but it can still be quite
damaging to them.</p>
<p>However, the spell isn’t perfect: indirect attacks and strikes can
hit her.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<p><span class="book-cover-right" style="max-width: 400px;"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/characters/ashen-blades/JakeWatson-AnimeStyle.jpg"
title="An AI-generated image of the mother of Artemis Watson, who&#39;s named Annmarie Nossett" /></span></p>
<p>The spirit of her dead father is bound to her hat, which she
subconsciously turned into a portal to a pocket dimension. Her father
manages manipulating space and sometimes even time for her, extending
the level of control she can exert over the interior of her hat, as well
as the precision with with she can manipulate the contents.</p>
<p>The space inside her hat is fairly large and she once stored an
entire military jeep within it.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<p>Her most powerful magical technique is a combination of witch fire
magic and demonic void magic, which produces what’s known as the
all-consuming flame. This is so hot, it glows in the ultraviolet
spectrum and most anything that’s hit by it is burned to nothingness.
Demons that are struck by this are effectively consumed by Artemis,
giving her a short-term boost to her magic powers.</p>
<p>The all-consuming flame is one of the few ways she knows of to
permanently kill a demon, who normally return to Hell when killed, then
seek to return to Earth.</p>
<p>She’s encountered many natures spirits over the years, each of which
serves as the avatar of a single element. In 1972, the Wood Spirit (AKA
the Jungle Spirit) picked a fight with her and the end result was
Artemis gaining access to its powers, which gave her the power to
transform into a huge, black cat or to armor her clothing with iron wood
panels, coming to resemble an armored knight with a shield.</p>
<p>She’s since had similar experiences with Water, Air and Metal.</p>
<p>The Water Spirit gave her the power to turn into a massive,
black-skinned shark and other water-related powers she has little use
for, aside from the ability to breathe underwater and survive the
pressure at any depth, which is sometimes handy, since she never did
like using scuba gear.</p>
<p>The Air Spirit gave her the power to fly, control air currents and to
fly. She can also create bursts of air in a vacuum or refresh stale air,
which allowed her to breathe on the Moon. Hypothetically, she might be
able to turn into a large, black bird, but she’s never tried to.</p>
<p>The Metal Spirit gave her the power to encase herself in metal at
will and presumably the ability to control metal objects. She once used
its power to cover her clothes in armor plates composed of alternating
layers of titanium and tungsten, for much greater durability than her
iron wood armor, at a mere fraction of the weight.</p>
<h2 id="favored-weapons-and-equipment">Favored Weapons and
Equipment</h2>
<p>Artemis started out using various discarded kitchen knives she
rescued from the trash, with a clear favorite being a full-size
butcher’s knife. These were later supplemented with a baseball bat and
ball. Unfortunately, the ball and bat were destroyed fighting
demons.</p>
<p>In more modern times, Artemis has mostly switched to guns that fire
.45 rounds, because they have enough punch to put a hole through a
skull, whcsh is the only way to kill a demon. She has an M1911 pistol
and a Thompson sub-machine gun. The Tommy gun is her favorite, but due
to the expense of full-auto fire, the rest of the detective agency she
works with have convinced her to use it only when necessary.</p>
<p>She eventually replaced the baseball bat with a Japanese wakizashi
that has a blue hilt wrapping and a tsuba (hilt guard) in the shape of
an open, blue rose. This has so far proven to be durable enough to
withstand her full demonic strength. She often projects her
all-consuming flame onto the blade, which extends her reach.</p>
<p>Here’s the (mostly) untold story of this sword: it was originally a
show piece made to hang on a wall, but the smith that made it still took
the work seriously, because even a decorative weapon might be needed
during a home invasion. The last of its Japanese owners immigrated to
the United States before World War II, but as things became difficult
for Japanese, they needed money and pawned it. When the war got even
more serious, the shop had a hard time selling it and Artemis picked it
up for a bargain price.</p>
<p>When Artemis needs heavier weapons, she has a .50 Browning M2 machine
gun with a shoulder strap to give it a little extra stabilization, which
she’s strong enough to fire from the hip. The few opponents that were
unlucky enough to see this weapon didn’t last long.</p>
<p>Her biggest and most ridiculous weapon is an M168 Vulcan Cannon,
which is normally vehicle mounted, but she can just barely manage to
fire it from the hip, though she isn’t very accurate with it, because
it’s just too big. On the other hand, considering the rate of fire that
thing is capable of, she tends to spray and pray. She mostly keeps it
for the sake of her gun collection, rather than considering it a useful
weapon, though a small number of demons have been on the receiving end
of it, on occasions when she <em>really</em> lost her temper. She rarely
has ammunition for it, because the bullets are not available at sane
prices.</p>
<p>Her top hat is one of her most prized possessions, because it
belonged to her father. It contains a pocket dimension, which holds all
of her other possessions and serves as the home of her mother’s
familiar, Mashu’ra, a juvenile demon in the form of a kitten. Mashu’ra
serves Artemis by looking after and caring for her weapons, including
reloading her guns, though no one is quite sure how a kitten manages
that.</p>
<p>In 1972, the Wood Spirit (AKA Jungle Spirit) gave Artemis some magic
clothes that change shape at a whim and are durable enough to act as
light body armor that can stop bullets. They also clean and repair
themselves. They can take on just about any style, including useful
forms like a space suit or hazmat gear.</p>
<p>In 1986, the Water Spirit gave her a shark-tooth necklace that really
doesn’t match her usual style of accessories, but she <em>does</em>
reluctantly wear it. It hasn’t yet displayed any magical abilities, but
it may in the future.</p>
<p>In 2024, the Air Spirit gave her a decorative, silver comb, which
came with the incidental power to alter her hair style and color at
will. She uses it to change her hair color as her mood changes, or as
her twisted and black sense of fashion dictates. She tends to picked
somber colors that match her goth-like persona, including blue, when she
was depressed. However, when Alice emerged and took control of their
body, her hair turned blond (see the section on <a
href="https://owentyme.us/characters/ashen-blades/artemis-watson.html#psychology">Psychology</a> for more information).</p>
<p>Also in 2024, the Metal Spirit gave her a bracelet with black,
cast-iron plates linked by stainless steel chain. It hasn’t yet
displayed any magical abilities, but it may in the future. She isn’t one
for jewelry, but she does like this accessory, since the Metal Spirit
was wise enough to recognize her sense of style, unlike the Water
Spirit.</p>
<h2 id="early-life-and-growth-early-life-growth">Early Life and Growth
{#early-life-growth)</h2>
<p><span class="book-cover-right" style="max-width: 400px;"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/characters/ashen-blades/ArtemisWatson-10Years-AnimeStyle.jpg"
title="An AI-generated image of Artemis Watson, in 1922" /></span></p>
<p>At the age of three years old, in the year 1900, her parents were
murdered by a demon in front of her, but due to her mother’s magic,
their spirits were bound to her. Her mother, Annmarie, turned herself
into a living, protective spell.</p>
<p>The father of Artemis was also killed, but his spirit was bound to
his top hat, a favorite item. This is the same top hat Artemis
wears.</p>
<p>Artemis has followed a rather unusual pattern of growth all her life:
she doesn’t grow older until she emotionally matures, then her body
changes fairly instantly, to match her mental state.</p>
<p>For example, when she was twenty-five years old, she looked ten,
because in all that time, she never quite matured enough to progress any
further.</p>
<p>In 1922, she had a chance encounter with a private detective, demon
hunter and Ashen Blade named Reggie Stewart. At the time, she was little
more than a remorseless killing machine that preyed on the demons of New
York City, using a butcher’s knife.</p>
<p>In that first encounter, she stole one of Reggie’s pistols, her very
first gun, which she’s never given up.</p>
<p>Upon leaning of the man’s dangerous job, she began following him and
eventually realized she’d found a kindred spirit. They became partners
and together, they really cleaned up the streets of New York.</p>
<p>While they were together, Artemis matured until she resembled a girl
of fifteen years, though she remained short and petite, at only five
feet tall.</p>
<p>Eventually, in 1942, Reggie was killed and the Ashen Blades assigned
her a new detective partner: Clayton Simmons.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<p><span class="book-cover-right" style="max-width: 400px;"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/characters/ashen-blades/ArtemisWatson-Vietnam-AnimeStyle.jpg"
title="An AI-generated image of Artemis Watson, in 1972, during her trip to Vietnam" /></span></p>
<p>She really didn’t mature much over the next few decades, until the
two of them went to Vietnam, in 1972, to exterminate an arch-demon that
had come to Earth.</p>
<p>While they were there, Artermis had a rough experience with the death
of a solider and got human blood on her hands, leading to an emotional
breakdown, but when she eventually recovered, she grew a little
older.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<p><span class="book-cover-right" style="max-width: 400px;"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/characters/ashen-blades/ArtemisWatson-17Years-AnimeStyle.jpg"
title="An AI-generated image of Artemis Watson at a more mature age" /></span></p>
<p>In book three, the curse that prevents her from speaking her mind was
briefly lifted and she was able to speak with her father. After that
emotional experience, she once again grew a little older.</p>
<p>In book four, after the loss of a dear friend, the grieving process
finally fully took her into adulthood, because she was forced to discard
some very childish coping mechanisms in order to heal.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<h2 id="psychology">Psychology</h2>
<p>Due to the hardships of being a half-demon and the trauma Artemis has
experienced, she isn’t exactly mentally stable. In point of fact, she
has multiple personalities.</p>
<p>The first is The Hunter, which is her base personality. The Hunter
represents her ego.</p>
<p><span class="book-cover-right" style="max-width: 400px;"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/characters/ashen-blades/ArtemisWatson-TheDemon-AnimeStyle.jpg"
title="An AI-generated image of Artemis Watson in her demonic form" /></span></p>
<p>The second is her inner demon, which she’s spent a lifetime fighting
to contain, because this personality is a murderous creature with no
moral compass. The demon is more or less her Id, an emotional creature
with no self-control.</p>
<p>The one time the demon gained full control of their body, she
transformed into a humanoid cat monster absolutely brimming with muscle,
which is more or less the demonic form of Artemis.</p>
<p>In that battle, the demon also publicly declared its name: The Eighth
Deadly Sin, Willful Insanity. She goes by Insanity, for short.</p>
<p>Hypothetically, Insanity was born the day Reggie Stewart was killed,
because Artemis completely lost control of herself, only coming to her
senses after the mixed group of demons and humans was defeated, with the
humans fleeing, while the demons were…extremely dead, with evidence of
claws and teeth.</p>
<p>Reggie witnessed the incident before he died and spoke as if he was
impressed, but Artemis has no memory of it.</p>
<p>Strangely enough, Insanity has a fondness for Jake, their father.</p>
<p>Insanity and the Hunter have a rather unusual relationship, in that
they hate and love each other, but neither of them would have it any
other way. When they face outside threats to their mind, lie telepathic
attacks, they usually face them together, despite the way Insanity
insists she’ll someday eat the Hunter.</p>
<p>What it comes down to is a matter of predator and prey dynamics, in
which Insanity has claimed the Hunter as prey, so Insanity refuses to
let anyone else kill her.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<p><span class="book-cover-right" style="max-width: 400px;"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/characters/ashen-blades/ArtemisWatson-Alice-AnimeStyle.jpg"
title="An AI-generated image of Artemis Watson, as Alice" /></span></p>
<p>During the climax of book four, Artemis was splashed with
approximately an entire pint of LSD, which resulted in the emergence of
a third personality, who calls herself Alice, due to a song that was
playing at the time (<em>White Rabbit</em>, by Jefferson Airplane). Due
to how confused she was at the time, she took on an approximation of the
appearance of Alice from <em>Alice’s Adventures in Wonderland</em>,
blond hair and all.</p>
<p>Alice cares for the Hunter like a sister and has demonstrated a
tendency to side with her against Insanity, helping to keep the demon
under control.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<p>Quite aside from this, Artemis occasionally hallucinates that she has
blood on her hands, because she was there when Reggie died and got blood
all over them, which is why she wears gloves. This hallucination got
worse in 1972, when her gloves got splashed with blood.</p>
<p>When Artemis gets tremendously angry, beyond merely losing her
temper, her eyes glow. This is part of her demonic ancestry, though it
is exceptionally rare.</p>
<h2 id="travels">Travels</h2>
<p>Artemis hates to travel, because she gets extremely motion sick in
vehicles. However, she has visited a number of places, both in and out
of the United States, including White Sands and Carlsbad Cavern, both in
New Mexico, The Cauldron of the Elements (a remote volcanic caldera
somewhere in the United States, which once hosted a summer camp),
California, Kansas, Canada, The Amazon, Egypt, the bottom of the Mariana
trench, Mount Everest, Vietnam, Tokyo in Japan, Alice Springs in
Australia, a snowy mountainside that may have been in Tibet, the Moon,
and a pocket dimension known as The Last Sanctuary.</p>
<p><span class="book-cover-right" style="max-width: 400px;"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/characters/ashen-blades/ArtemisWatson-Kimono-AnimeStyle.jpg"
title="An AI-generated image of Artemis Watson in a kimono, in 1972" /></span></p>
<p>Here’s a nice image of Artemis during her brief visit to Tokyo, while
her team was taking a break from fighting the demons hiding in the
jungles of Vietnam. On this occasion, her magic clothes went native
without her giving it much thought.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
<p><span class="book-cover-right" style="max-width: 400px;"><img
src="https://owentyme.us/characters/ashen-blades/ArtemisWatson-SummerCamp-AnimeStyle.jpg"
title="An AI-generated image of Artemis Watson in 1986, when she went to summer camp" /></span></p>
<p>In 1986, she went undercover at a summer camp that was infested with
demons. At the time, she was pretending to be a teenager, despite the
fact she was old enough to be the grandmother of the teens that
surrounded her. She got particularly cranky while she was there, because
she doesn’t like to interact with teenagers.</p>
<div style="clear: both;">

</div>
]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Characters</title>
<link>https://owentyme.us/characters/index.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/characters/index.html</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 19:30:55 -0600</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<h1 id="characters">Characters</h1>
<p>On this page you’ll find lists of character names, which will
sometimes be links to pages with more information. All of them come from
my novels and short stories, broken down by series.</p>
<p>For most series, this will cover major characters only.</p>
<p>This page is intended to be both a reference for myself and a way for
readers to learn more about their favorite characters.</p>
<p><strong>Be Warned:</strong> if you follow the links pages for
individual characters, you <em>will</em> find spoilers.</p>
<h2 id="ashen-blades"><a href="https://owentyme.us/characters/../books/ashen-blades/index.html">Ashen
Blades</a></h2>
<p>Major Characters</p>
<ul>
<li>Bagley, Verda</li>
<li>Envy</li>
<li>Gluttony</li>
<li>Greed</li>
<li>Lust</li>
<li>Mashu’ra (AKA Masher)</li>
<li>Nature Spirits
<ul>
<li>Air</li>
<li>Animal</li>
<li>Earth</li>
<li>Fire</li>
<li>Life</li>
<li>Metal</li>
<li>Smoke</li>
<li>Void</li>
<li>Water</li>
<li>Wood (AKA Jungle)</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Pride (AKA Otto Vogerath, Karl Vogerath, the Vogerath Brothers, The
Hydra, etc.)</li>
<li>Simmons, Clayton</li>
<li>Simmons, Lara</li>
<li>Sloth</li>
<li>Stewart, Reggie</li>
<li>The Golem of Prague (AKA The Golem)</li>
<li>Ulmoch</li>
<li>Watson, Alice</li>
<li><a href="https://owentyme.us/characters/ashen-blades/artemis-watson.html">Watson, Artemis</a> (AKA
The Boss, The Hunter, Little Miss Secret, LMS, brat, hey you, girl,
etc.)</li>
<li>Willful Insanity (AKA The Inner Demon, The Eighth Deadly Sin,
etc.)</li>
<li>Wrath</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="sky-children"><a href="https://owentyme.us/characters/../books/sky-children/index.html">Sky
Children</a></h2>
<p>Major Characters</p>
<ul>
<li>Dandy, Captain (King of the Unrooted)</li>
<li>Jacobs, Dinah</li>
<li>Jacobs, Elizabeth (AKA Liz)</li>
<li>Jacobs, Levi</li>
<li>Jacobs, Zechariah</li>
<li>Jerala</li>
<li>Levine, Rachel (AKA Rachel Jacobs)</li>
<li>Ruth</li>
<li>Scar (AKA Butt-Ugly Scarred One, Ugly, Butt, etc.)</li>
<li>Teera</li>
<li>Vessa</li>
<li>Winzon</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="the-wizards-scion"><a
href="https://owentyme.us/characters/../books/wizards-scion/index.html">The Wizard’s Scion</a></h2>
<p>Major Characters</p>
<ul>
<li>Cha’da (AKA Eden Nisim, Terror of the High Seas)</li>
<li>Dandy, Captain (King of the Unrooted)</li>
<li>Gida</li>
<li>Ida</li>
<li>Inorath</li>
<li>Lyra (AKA Lyra Jacobs)</li>
<li>Nicole, Dark (AKA The Demon)</li>
<li>Nicole, Light (The clone)</li>
<li>Jacobs, Dinah</li>
<li>Jacobs, Levi</li>
<li>Jacobs, Rachel</li>
<li>Jacobs, Zechariah</li>
<li>Ogomid</li>
<li>Ruth</li>
<li>Scar</li>
<li>Teera</li>
<li>The Four Horsemen</li>
<li>The Moirai (AKA The Fates)</li>
<li>Vessa</li>
<li>Winzon</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="jigsaw-city"><a href="https://owentyme.us/characters/../books/jigsaw-city/index.html">Jigsaw
City</a></h2>
<p>Major Characters</p>
<ul>
<li>Baba Yaga</li>
<li>Candleflash, Stargazer (AKA Lulu Stargazer Candleflash)</li>
<li>Cha’da</li>
<li>Harris, Edwin</li>
<li>Jacobs, Lyra</li>
<li>Jacobs, Nicole (AKA Nicole the Younger)</li>
<li>Kazic</li>
<li>The City of Kurg</li>
<li>Lognur</li>
<li>Ogomid (King of the Ulkun)</li>
<li>Rosegrass, Aurora (AKA Queen of the Fairies)</li>
<li>Rosegrass, Koko</li>
<li>The Architect</li>
<li>The Final Phoenix</li>
<li>The Life Giver (AKA Life)</li>
<li>Ustrina Roseus (AKA Bevna the Quiet)</li>
<li>Vanubo (AKA Vanu)</li>
<li>Willowcone, Airseed</li>
<li>Willowcone, Nightshade (AKA Queen of the Dryads)</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="the-book-of-newts"><a
href="https://owentyme.us/characters/../books/book-of-newts/index.html">The Book of Newts</a></h2>
<p>In the Book of Newts, many of the small, background characters are
intended to return in later seasons (AKA volumes) and will often be more
important than they appear at first glance.</p>
<p>As such, I’m trying to keep a more complete list of named characters
for this series. However, for the sake of the casual visitor to this
website, I’ll break them down by major and minor characters.</p>
<p>Major Characters</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://owentyme.us/characters/book-of-newts/amelia-blackwell.html">Blackwell,
Amelia</a></li>
<li><a href="https://owentyme.us/characters/book-of-newts/iris-blackwell.html">Blackwell, Iris</a></li>
<li><a href="https://owentyme.us/characters/book-of-newts/marta-blackwell.html">Blackwell,
Marta</a></li>
<li>Bones</li>
<li>Denholm, Scarth</li>
<li>Krauss, “Killer”</li>
<li>Natas, Elsbeth (AKA The Dead Queen)</li>
<li>The Book of Newts (AKA Newton’s Mechanics)</li>
</ul>
<p>Minor Characters</p>
<ul>
<li>Aspenvale, Nyra</li>
<li>Blackwell, Erika</li>
<li>Blackwell, Tim</li>
<li>Bonebuster, Nonar</li>
<li>Knotley, Haley</li>
<li>Icebrow, Dawkin</li>
<li>Maccle, Mr. (Mayor of Macclesfield)</li>
<li>Maccle, Mrs.</li>
<li>Rowley, Edwina</li>
<li>Rumblecleaver, Godfrey (Mayor of Daleshade)</li>
<li>Talbot, Alice</li>
<li>Tillote</li>
<li>Trevlis, Mina</li>
<li>Twoheart, Hobart</li>
<li>Vixen, Agnes</li>
<li>Whitjaw, Orgic</li>
<li>Zindo, Mr.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="rumors-of-war"><a
href="https://owentyme.us/characters/../books/rumors-of-war/index.html">Rumors of War</a></h2>
<p>Major Characters</p>
<ul>
<li>Aketa (AKA The Abomination)</li>
<li>Anji</li>
<li>Ghinead, Brosla (AKA The Alien)</li>
<li>Gunn, Ariel Molly</li>
<li>Idoi, Et’aell (High Priestess of Vok)</li>
<li>Illa (AKA Leona Conway)</li>
<li>Logan, Homer</li>
<li>Lovelymint, Posey</li>
<li>Nepita (Queen of Utros)</li>
<li>Rolar, Arun</li>
<li>Shadowfang, Skylark (Ruler of the Ember Throne and the Unseelie
Court)</li>
<li>Shaffurukattā (AKA Shuffle Cutter)</li>
<li>Shengis (King of Utros)</li>
<li>Stanton, Jane (AKA Sureshot, Special Envoy From Oswil)</li>
<li>Vendros, Turloth</li>
<li>Vok (God of the Vokosians)</li>
<li>Windmaker, Gorgo (King of Fortune Fields, AKA Gorgo Windmaker the
Tenth)</li>
<li>Windmaker, Kadrek (Prince of Fortune Fields)</li>
<li>Wood, Joshua (King of Oswil)</li>
<li>Yetu (Prince of Utros)</li>
<li>Yera (Grandmother, Former Queen of Utros)</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
