<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel><title>Tymely News</title><link>https://owentyme.us/blog/index.html</link>
<description>Straight from Owen Tyme's keyboard</description><language>en</language>
<lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 14:57:25 -0600</lastBuildDate>
<pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 14:57:25 -0600</pubDate>
<atom:link href="https://owentyme.us/blog/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<item><title>
Black Friday/Cyber Monday Sale
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>The Ebooks of my novels go on sale for Black Friday through Cyber Monday, starting tomorrow.</p>

<p><a href="https://books2read.com/b/TrollSong">Troll Song will be 99 cents!</a></p>

<p><a href="https://books2read.com/b/ForgottenLegends">Forgotten Legends will be $1.99!</a></p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_writing.html'>writing</a>, <a href='tag_publishing.html'>publishing</a>, <a href='tag_sale.html'>sale</a></p>

































































<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://owentyme.us/blog/black-fridaycyber-monday-sale.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/blog/./black-fridaycyber-monday-sale.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Owen Tyme</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 10:29:08 -0600</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
On Sale, Now!
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>To celebrate my novels being featured in the local newspaper, the Ebook versions of my novels are on sale until the end of Monday!</p>

<p>Troll Song is currently a dollar off, at $1.99.  <a href="https://books2read.com/b/TrollSong">https://books2read.com/b/TrollSong</a></p>

<p>Forgotten Legends is two dollars off, at $2.99.  <a href="https://books2read.com/b/ForgottenLegends">https://books2read.com/b/ForgottenLegends</a></p>

<p>Hurry and buy them, before it's too late!</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_writing.html'>writing</a>, <a href='tag_publishing.html'>publishing</a>, <a href='tag_sale.html'>sale</a>, <a href='tag_the-wizards-scion.html'>the-wizards-scion</a></p>









































































<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://owentyme.us/blog/on-sale-now.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/blog/./on-sale-now.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Owen Tyme</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2023 16:34:31 -0600</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Shame On Me, I Guess, Part II
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>After a day away from the social-media-platform-that-shall-remain-nameless, I logged in to check the status of my appeal.  Lo and behold, my account has magically been reactivated, just as I predicted!</p>

<p>Why does sharing a photo of myself somehow convince them I didn't actually break any rules, even though their algorithm repeatedly flags me for such?  What the heck is even going on, man?  Why don't they bother to actually explain what's going on?</p>

<p>Honestly, if this is the way they behave, then clearly, the social-media-platform-that-shall-remain-nameless is nearly as much of a dumpster fire as the social-media-platform-formerly-known-as-twitter.  Their algorithm is also clearly on hard drugs.</p>

<p>As an experiment to satisfy my morbid curiosity, I removed the photo of myself from the page on the social-media-platform-that-shall-remain-nameless and replaced it with my publishing mark, just to see how deep this rabbit hole goes.</p>

<p>I half-suspect that my account will be blocked again within a week and a half.  If not, then I'll put the photo back up and see what happens, then.  It may be that putting the face of a human being on a secondary page is what the algorithm doesn't like.</p>

<p>Perhaps an author isn't allowed to be a human being.</p>

<p>After all, the owner of the company has a face only an AI could have generated.  Honestly, I've never seen another human being whose face was so clearly stuck in the middle of the Uncanny Valley and yet, people claim to have met him, in person.  Perhaps they're AI generated, too.</p>

<p>Anyway, I'll keep you all posted as this story of madness swirling around the social media's toilet drain continues.  Hopefully, my experiments will at least help others that wish to promote their writing online.</p>

<p>Oh yeah, and by the way, you can find <a href="https://mastodon.social/@OwenTyme">the social media profile I actually care about on Mastodon</a>.  I quite like Mastodon, because it's not governed by a brainless algorithm and all the posts in the feeds are in (gasp!) <em>chronological order</em>!  What a concept, eh?  It's based on open source software, so just about anyone can setup a server if they've the time, inclination and resources.  Best of all, those servers all talk to each other and share posts back and forth.  Isn't that cool?</p>

<p>I was also quite delighted when I looked at the rules for Mastodon.social (the largest Mastodon server), which are actually human-readable, rather than lawyer-readable.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_social-media.html'>social-media</a>, <a href='tag_social-media-platform-that-shall-remain-nameless.html'>social-media-platform-that-shall-remain-nameless</a></p>






















































































































<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://owentyme.us/blog/shame-on-me-i-guess-part-ii.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/blog/./shame-on-me-i-guess-part-ii.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Owen Tyme</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 22:14:45 -0600</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Shame On Me, I Guess
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>In my last post involving the social-media-platform-that-shall-remain-nameless, I ended by saying, "Fool me once, shame on you, fool me twice..."</p>

<p>Well, apparently, the social-media-platform-that-shall-remain-nameless has once again (automatically) flagged my account for violating their rules, without telling me precisely which rule I've violated.</p>

<p>Honestly, how can the largest social media company in the world be so narrow-minded about people that have pen names, especially since I'm not hiding my true identity in any meaningful way?  I registered the freaking account in my real name and then made the separate page for my pen name, because I'm an honest person.  I suspect they think I'm trying to impersonate my own pen name, again.  Ugh.</p>

<p>I must say, their appeal process is the stupidest thing I've ever seen, consisting entirely of asking the user to upload a photo of themselves.  What is the freaking purpose of that?  Why can't I file a message asking what I did wrong?  Why are the rules of their website (by their own admission) enforced by an algorithm, rather than a human moderator?</p>

<p>So, I'll end the sentence from the previous post by saying, "...shame on me."</p>

<p>Out of sheer morbid curiosity, I've appealed, again.</p>

<p>Oh, I have no intention of making serious use of the social-media-platform-that-shall-remain-nameless from this point on, but if they're going to play stupid games with me, then I want to see just how far the die rolls.  Five minutes of my time every once in a while to file an appeal is no real burden, but you better believe I'm never posting anything there, ever again.</p>

<p>Screw Facebook.  Whoops, did I type that in the clear?</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_social-media.html'>social-media</a>, <a href='tag_social-media-platform-that-shall-remain-nameless.html'>social-media-platform-that-shall-remain-nameless</a></p>























































































































<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://owentyme.us/blog/shame-on-me-i-guess.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/blog/./shame-on-me-i-guess.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Owen Tyme</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 19:34:59 -0600</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Apparently, I'm News
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>On Monday morning a reporter for the local newspaper (The Leader &amp; Times) interviewed me and today, <a href="https://www.liberalfirst.com/local-sports-4/15169-liberal-author-announces-new-books%E2%80%99-releases" title="Liberal author announces new books’ releases">the article was posted online</a>.</p>

<p>I know I was a nervous wreck, but she did a good job of turning my ramblings into a coherent news article.  Never once did I consider the possibility that I might be interviewed by a reporter, but hopefully, this will get the word out to locals, at least.  I know I can definitely use the extra sales and it stands to reason, those that read newspapers are more likely to read books.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_writing.html'>writing</a>, <a href='tag_publishing.html'>publishing</a>, <a href='tag_news.html'>news</a>, <a href='tag_interviews.html'>interviews</a></p>

























































































































<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://owentyme.us/blog/apparently-im-news.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/blog/./apparently-im-news.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Owen Tyme</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 12:45:18 -0600</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Available for Pre-Order: Forgotten Legends!
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>The second volume of <em>The Wizard's Scion</em> series, titled <em>Forgotten Legends</em>, is now available for pre-order as an Ebook.  The print edition should follow, soon.</p>

<p><em>Forgotten Legends</em> releases on November 13, 2023.</p>

<p><a href="https://books2read.com/b/ForgottenLegends" title="Forgotten Legends"><img src="../images/Cover-ForgottenLegends.jpeg" alt="" title="" /></a></p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Levi hated the monster from under the bed as a child, but when he meets the creature as a young adult, he quickly learns nothing will be the same in his life, ever again.  The creature of darkness pleads for his aid in a coming war and the young wizard reluctantly agrees, making it his familiar.</p>

<p>Levi’s family and friends are soon caught up in a galaxy-wide war to decide the fate of humanity and continually come face to face with monsters straight out of myth and legend, including the dreaded Four Horsemen of the Apocalypse! The old gods and monsters humanity revered before the rise of science and reason are angry over being ignored and seek to force humanity to believe in them once more!</p>

<p>The young wizard’s allies find themselves in a unique position to fight the supernatural creatures, since they’re gifted with magical powers of their own, soon sparking a wave of resistance from the governments of the galaxy, as they take the fight to the legends!</p>

<p>However, the battle isn’t easy, because the forgotten legends weren’t idle over the millennia, having built an impressive manufacturing facility that draws matter straight from a star to build warships at an incredible rate, churning them out faster than humanity can deal with! Worse yet, these ships have the very best in weaponry that both magic and science can produce.</p>

<p>Will Levi and his family overcome the endless waves of disposable warships or will the governments of the galaxy be crushed by the Four Horsemen of the Apocalypse, beginning an era of slavery under the heel of their own forgotten legends? The answers lay within this book, but you’ll never know unless you buy it!</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_the-wizards-scion.html'>the-wizards-scion</a>, <a href='tag_novel.html'>novel</a>, <a href='tag_writing.html'>writing</a>, <a href='tag_publishing.html'>publishing</a></p>










































































<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://owentyme.us/blog/forgotten-legends-available-for-pre-order.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/blog/./forgotten-legends-available-for-pre-order.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Owen Tyme</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 14:09:46 -0600</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Coming Soon: Forgotten Legends
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>The artwork for the next volume of The Wizard's Scion is nearly complete, so I'm back in full edit mode, to give the text one final pass of polishing before publishing, since Ryan (the artist) moved far faster than I expected, this time.</p>

<p>Forgotten Legends will likely be released as an Ebook in the next week or two.  The print edition should follow on a short delay, as I intend to upload files and complete the work for both on the same day, this time.</p>

<p>This is really exciting to me, because Forgotten Legends is my favorite of the five books in the series, with lots of fun things related to monsters and mythology.</p>

<p>It also has some mild horror elements written from the perspective of the monsters, which is not within my usual writing wheelhouse, but I'm particularly proud of the first and second chapters, as well as the chapter involving Strangers.</p>

<p>Then there's the chapter involving a Kaiju vs. giant robot fight.  That's just all-around fun and shows the far-reaching consequences of the war.</p>

<p>I also love the book for the chance it gives the protagonist to really grow up.  In Troll Song, Levi was introduced as an immature teen.  In Forgotten Legends, he's forced to face the the harsh realities of war and he'll never be the same, again.</p>

<p>I also love the lasting consequences of the novel, because it perfectly sets the stage for the three to follow, directly leading to the rise of old enemies in the Third Wish, the unexpected redemption of a villain in Dark Moon and the capstone of the series, The Inverted Glass, where Levi faces the greatest of challenges on the path to mastering his wizardly powers, with the fate of everyone he loves at stake.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_writing.html'>writing</a>, <a href='tag_publishing.html'>publishing</a></p>





























































































































<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://owentyme.us/blog/coming-soon-forgotten-legends.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/blog/./coming-soon-forgotten-legends.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Owen Tyme</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 18:43:45 -0600</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Troll Song Author Copies!
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>I finally got my author copies of Troll Song, today.</p>

<p>I wish I had a better camera in my phone, because these look way better than this in real life.</p>

<p>You can get a copy of Troll Song for yourself here: https://books2read.com/b/TrollSong</p>

<p><img src="../images/Books-TrollSong.png" alt="" title="" /></p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_writing.html'>writing</a>, <a href='tag_publishing.html'>publishing</a></p>










































































<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://owentyme.us/blog/troll-song-author-copies.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/blog/./troll-song-author-copies.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Owen Tyme</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 17:02:45 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Building a Blog
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>After a rather frustrating and enraging experience with a particular social-media-platform-that-shall-remain-nameless suspending my account for no apparent reason about ten minutes after I had a page setup for my pen name, on Friday, I wasn't in to the mood to deal with another social media platform.</p>

<p>The biggest alternative, the social-media-platform-formerly-known-as-twitter currently seems to be a huge dumpster fire, so instead, I set my mind to creating a blog to accompany <a href="https://owentyme.us">my author website</a>, because I need some way to communicate with fans.</p>

<h3>Requirements</h3>

<p>I set out to find blog software that met the following requirements:</p>

<ul>
<li>Able to generate static HTML pages</li>
<li>WYSIWYG editing</li>
<li>Can run on my own computer</li>
<li>Simple</li>
<li>Disqus.com comments</li>
</ul>

<h4>Static HTML</h4>

<p><a href="https://owentyme.us">My author website</a> is built on <a href="https://feather.wiki/">Feather Wiki</a>, which is basically a small, self-editing, multi-page HTML file with embedded JavaScript to handle the real work.  It's a fascinatingly simple and easy approach to making a website and once you're ready to publish it, you just turn off the editing features from the settings page, save it and upload.  Ideally, I was looking for the means to setup a blog with a similar piece of software.</p>

<h4>WYSIWYG</h4>

<p>WYSIWYG = What You See Is What You Get.  Ideally, I wanted software that made itself easy to use by allowing me to edit pages like a word processor might edit a document.</p>

<h4>My Own Hardware</h4>

<p>I use Linux, exclusively, so I needed something I could run from my own computer.</p>

<h4>The KISS Principle</h4>

<p>KISS = Keep It Simple, Stupid!  Finally, I want something simple.  Honestly, there's a lot of software out there for making websites, but almost none of it is simple and the install instructions for most are incomprehensible, to say the least.</p>

<p>Open Source developers are awesome, in general, I love them for giving things away for free and I often do the same, but man, they need to learn to write better documentation.  Sorry guys, but you know it just as well as I do!</p>

<p>Sadly, simple software installation is just not something most of them even bother to try and make happen, so we're stuck with installation instructions that are not even close to simple.</p>

<h4>The Comments</h4>

<p>For a previous website, specifically a wiki, I embedded a <a href="http://disqus.com">Disqus</a> widget on each page.  That's a very useful website for adding comments to an otherwise entirely static HTML page, which allows logins from Google, the social-media-platform-that-shall-remain-nameless and the social-media-platform-formerly-known-as-twitter, on top of the usual e-mail and password system most websites use.</p>

<h3>The Solution</h3>

<p>In the end, I stumbled across and opted to use <a href="https://github.com/cfenollosa/bashblog">BashBlog</a>.  BashBlog is dead simple, being nothing more than a shell script (the Linux equivalent to a DOS/Windows batch file, though shell scripts are much more powerful).  Since I've dabbled in generating a static HTML website from a shell script before, this turned out to be ideal.  The script itself is rather elegantly simple and easy to modify.  It also turns out that BashBlog supports Disqus.com comments, with a little easy setup.</p>

<p>So, with a useful tool in hand, I experimented with making a handful of small modifications, like adding the cover image I originally planned to use with the social-media-platform-that-shall-remain-nameless.</p>

<p>So, that just leaves the WYSIWYG editor, which I still lack.  However, I did install a plugin to BashBlog that lets it work with Markdown (a simple text format that interprets various symbols as bold, italics and a whole slew of other, useful things) instead of forcing me to write HTML files, directly.  Then I modified BashBlog to call out to a program called 
<a href="https://ghostwriter.kde.org/">ghostwriter</a>, which just happened to be available for my Linux distribution of choice (Linux Mint).  Ghostwriter allows me to see my Markdown text side-by-side with the rendered text, so it's almost as good as a WYSIWYG editor.</p>

<p>In the end, with this combination of tools, I've got a simple blogging system that allows me to update this website with relative ease and which I'm comfortable customizing to my own needs.</p>

<h3>Conclusion</h3>

<p>So, to recap my earlier points, let's look over my list of requirements and check off a few things:</p>

<ul>
<li>[X] Able to generate static HTML pages</li>
<li>[?] WYSIWYG editing</li>
<li>[X] Can run on my own computer</li>
<li>[X] KISS</li>
<li>[X] Disqus.com comments</li>
</ul>

<p>I almost accomplished all I set out to do and I can accept that one answer that's neither yes or no, for now.  In the future I'll have to experiment with other software that can directly edit HTML files, which I could call from the script (Libreoffice can do this, but the trouble is I need incomplete HTML files without wrapping <code>&lt;body&gt;</code> and <code>&lt;/body&gt;</code> tags), but that's a task for another day.</p>

<p>I hope this helps others in a similar position and I hope this helps others escape the social-media-platform-that-shall-remain-nameless and it's dumpster fire alternative, the social-media-platform-formerly-known-as-twitter.</p>

<h4>Addendum A</h4>

<p>After all that anger, frustration and work to make a blog, a friend of mine mentioned the existence of <a href="https://joinmastodon.org/">Mastodon</a>.  Honestly, I hadn't heard the name in quite some time, but it turned out to be open source (yay!).   The biggest server, <a href="https://mastodon.social/">mastodon.social</a>, has extremely simple rules and a privacy policy that's actually human-readable, though still written in the esoteric tongue of lawyers, demons and demon-lawyers (which only barely qualifies as English).</p>

<p>By comparison, the social-media-platform-that-shall-remain-nameless used an exhaustive set of  legal documents that very carefully spelled out all the ways they were allowed to misuse my personal information for the sake of the bottom dollar, while simultaneously trying to hide that fact in the esoteric tongue of lawyers, demons and demon-lawyers.</p>

<p>So, the end result of Friday's frustration is this blog and <a href="https://mastodon.social/@OwenTyme">my new Mastodon account</a>.</p>

<h4>Addendum B</h4>

<p>In the mean time, the social-media-platform-that-shall-remain-nameless has responded to my appeal to my account getting suspended by restoring it without actually telling me what they think I did wrong.  I find myself wondering, is it worth the frustration?  I'm really not sure and until they give me a clear response to what the heck they think I did wrong, I don't see the point in using the social-media-platform-that-shall-remain-nameless.</p>

<p>Honestly, would you?  Fool me once, shame on you, fool me twice...</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_blog.html'>blog</a>, <a href='tag_html.html'>html</a>, <a href='tag_websites.html'>websites</a>, <a href='tag_shell-script.html'>shell-script</a>, <a href='tag_social-media.html'>social-media</a>, <a href='tag_mastodon.html'>mastodon</a>, <a href='tag_social-media-platform-that-shall-remain-nameless.html'>social-media-platform-that-shall-remain-nameless</a></p>





































































































































<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://owentyme.us/blog/building-a-blog.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/blog/./building-a-blog.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Owen Tyme</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 17:36:42 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Troll Song is Released!
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>The first novel in <em>The Wizard's Scion</em> series, titled <em>Troll Song</em>, is available for purchase in both eBook and paperback forms.  You can find out more by <a href="https://books2read.com/b/TrollSong" title="Troll Song">clicking this link</a> or by clicking on the image, below.</p>

<p><a href="https://books2read.com/b/TrollSong" title="Troll Song"><img src="../images/Cover-TrollSong.jpeg" alt="" title="" /></a></p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Lyra never intended to cause the extinction of the troll race, but when she uses the power of troll song to read the mind of a dwarf, she’s forced to compare her life of abuse to that of a loving family.</p>

<p>Acting for the good of the world, Lyra betrays her family and kills her oldest sister, creating an opportunity for the dwarves to defeat the troll army.</p>

<p>The middle sister, Lyra’s childhood nemesis, Nicole, is furious beyond all rationality and determined to make Lyra pay, no matter the cost! Death would be too good for Lyra, so Nicole seeks to telepathically destroy her mind, instead!</p>

<p>Luring her sister into a trap, Lyra drops an entire mountain of ice on their heads, intent on ending Nicole at the expense of her own life! Waking after thousands of years frozen sleep in a world of wonders both scientific and magical, Nicole steals a powerful star ship and the contest begins anew!</p>

<p>Will Lyra defeat her murderous sister and end the troll threat or will Nicole destroy Lyra’s mind to fulfill her vow of vengeance, followed by raiding and pillaging as she sees fit? Buy this book and find out, today!</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_the-wizards-scion.html'>the-wizards-scion</a>, <a href='tag_novel.html'>novel</a>, <a href='tag_publishing.html'>publishing</a></p>










































































<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://owentyme.us/blog/troll-song-is-released.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/blog/./troll-song-is-released.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Owen Tyme</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2023 12:18:48 -0500</pubDate></item>
</channel></rss>
