<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel><title>Owen Tyme</title><link>https://owentyme.us/blog/index.html</link>
<description>Science Fiction and Fantasy Author</description><language>en</language>
<lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2023 13:26:43 -0500</lastBuildDate>
<pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2023 13:26:43 -0500</pubDate>
<atom:link href="https://owentyme.us/blog/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<item><title>
Troll Song is Released!
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>The first novel in <em>The Wizard's Scion</em> series, titled <em>Troll Song</em>, is available for purchase in both eBook and paperback forms.  You can find out more by <a href="https://books2read.com/b/TrollSong" title="Troll Song">clicking this link</a> or by clicking on the image, below.</p>

<p><a href="https://books2read.com/b/TrollSong" title="Troll Song"><img src="../images/Cover-TrollSong.jpeg" alt="" title="" /></a></p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Lyra never intended to cause the extinction of the troll race, but when she uses the power of troll song to read the mind of a dwarf, she’s forced to compare her life of abuse to that of a loving family.</p>

<p>Acting for the good of the world, Lyra betrays her family and kills her oldest sister, creating an opportunity for the dwarves to defeat the troll army.</p>

<p>The middle sister, Lyra’s childhood nemesis, Nicole, is furious beyond all rationality and determined to make Lyra pay, no matter the cost! Death would be too good for Lyra, so Nicole seeks to telepathically destroy her mind, instead!</p>

<p>Luring her sister into a trap, Lyra drops an entire mountain of ice on their heads, intent on ending Nicole at the expense of her own life! Waking after thousands of years frozen sleep in a world of wonders both scientific and magical, Nicole steals a powerful star ship and the contest begins anew!</p>

<p>Will Lyra defeat her murderous sister and end the troll threat or will Nicole destroy Lyra’s mind to fulfill her vow of vengeance, followed by raiding and pillaging as she sees fit? Buy this book and find out, today!</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_the-wizards-scion.html'>the-wizards-scion</a>, <a href='tag_novel.html'>novel</a>, <a href='tag_releases.html'>releases</a></p>




<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://owentyme.us/blog/troll-song-is-released.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/blog/./troll-song-is-released.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Owen Tyme</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2023 12:18:48 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Introductions
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p><img src="../images/OwenTyme.jpeg" alt="" title="" /></p>

<p>I'm Owen Tyme and I'm a novelist.</p>

<p>I prefers to write action-filled science fantasy, though I sometimes write fantasy or science fiction, when the inspiration takes me there.  I love grounding what I write in science, even when writing about dragons, witches and wizards.</p>

<p>My favorite authors include Terry Pratchett, R. A. Salvatore, Douglas Adams and Isaac Asimov.  More recently, I discovered a liking for Mercedes Lackey, as well.  I loves novels grounded in scientific truth, but also love a little flight of fancy.  I especially loves it when the two work hand-in-hand, as in the works of Pratchett.</p>

<p>Though I currently call Liberal, Kansas home, I was born in the California Bay Area. I've come to enjoy the mild climate of Kansas.  I'm a member of the Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-Day Saints.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_about.html'>about</a></p>






<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://owentyme.us/blog/introductions.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/blog/./introductions.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Owen Tyme</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2023 10:50:10 -0500</pubDate></item>
</channel></rss>
