<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel><title>Tymely News</title><link>https://owentyme.us/blog/index.html</link>
<description>Straight from Owen Tyme's keyboard</description><language>en</language>
<lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 10:17:54 -0600</lastBuildDate>
<pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 10:17:54 -0600</pubDate>
<atom:link href="https://owentyme.us/blog/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<item><title>
Work In Progress #23: Starwitch #6
</title><description><![CDATA[

<blockquote>
  <p>"The distant woman groaned, 'We're not pirates, you idiot!  We’re just new to space travel, so how could we possibly know how we're supposed to mark our ship, to make you think we're friendly?'</p>

<p>Haley growled, 'That's what a pirate would say!'</p>

<p>'It's also what a normal person would say.  Now, if we were pirates, wouldn't we be trying to kill you, instead of talking?' "</p>

<p>&nbsp; – An excerpt from Starwitch.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><span class="book-cover">
<a href="../books/book-of-newts/starwitch.html"><img src="../images/Cover-Starwitch.jpg" alt="" title="" /></a>
</span>
<a href="../books/book-of-newts/starwitch.html">Starwitch</a> is a novel about space-faring witches that I plan to release first as a web series, then for sale in online stores.</p>

<p><a href="https://mastodon.social/@OwenTyme/113483873966306253">You can read short summaries of each day's writing on Mastodon.</a></p>

<div style="clear: both;"></div>

<p>Here's a list of previous blog entries on this work in progress novel, in order from oldest to newest:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="work-in-progress-18-starwitch-1.html">Starwitch #1</a></li>
<li><a href="work-in-progress-19-starwitch-2.html">Starwitch #2</a></li>
<li><a href="work-in-progress-20-starwitch-3.html">Starwitch #3</a></li>
<li><a href="work-in-progress-21-starwitch-4.html">Starwitch #4</a></li>
<li><a href="work-in-progress-22-starwitch-5.html">Starwitch #5</a></li>
</ul>

<h2>Chapter 23: Solar Wind</h2>

<p>Amelia and her sisters stand in the witchpit, while she demonstrates a light sail spell she's cast without assistance from the spell-core.</p>

<p>I did a little research on light sails and discovered that a better approach than reflecting light is to split it with a prism-like sail.  I also considered the sails of <em>Starwitch</em>, in particular, and decided that it's an illusion anchored to the masts, via an enchantment.  I edited the first chapter accordingly, adding a rainbow effect.</p>

<p>The rigging is enchanted to produce musical notes to indicate the level of pressure on the cables inside the masts, ranging from A to G-sharp, but if if goes up an octave, then the rigging is in danger of breaking under the strain, since steel cables can only handle so much.</p>

<p>Reasoning that illusions can affect light, I decided that <em>Starwitch</em> literally uses weightless illusions for sail material.</p>

<p>Amelia's sail is weak, little more than a spider's web of prism-like material, which she has to refresh from one second to the next, because even raw sunlight can scatter her illusions.  Her spell can get the rigging to a C-sharp on one side and a B on the other, based on their angle.</p>

<p>Marta requests and is given an explanation of the basics of the spell.</p>

<p>Iris asks what part the masts play and Amelia explains that they bear enchantments to allow illusions to interact with solid matter, which allows the light pressure from the solar wind to give them thrust.</p>

<p>Iris asks why Amelia didn't just permanently enchant the sail spell into the masts, leading to a discussion of how various materials handle runic enchantments.</p>

<p>The basic idea is that the more types of material go into a crystalline structure like stone or metal, the more runes it can hold, at the cost of reduced power, due to less efficient magic.</p>

<p>I'll quote Amelia's explanation for this:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>"Take granite, for example.  It's basically many types of rock compressed together, which <em>does</em> give it a much greater capacity to store magic, allowing a large collection of runes to work at the same time, but that strength is also its weakness.</p>

<p>"When runes produce an effect from the magic stored in granite, all of those different types of rock each produce their own copy of the spell, all at slightly different frequencies.  When the magic comes together as a cohesive whole, the many competing frequencies interfere with each other and the end result is a weaker spell, plus lots of magic that goes to waste.  In fact, eighty percent of the magic is wasted and simply released into the air.</p>

<p>"Pure metals, on the other hand, have a rather simple structure.  They can hold only three runes, but when those runes have an effect, it tends to be rather powerful, with only five percent waste.</p>

<p>"Steel, on the other hand, occupies the middle ground, able to hold up to seven runes, with reasonably powerful effects and only thirty percent waste, though the details vary by the recipe of the alloy.</p>

<p>"The masts of Starwitch had to be steel, for the sake of strength, which forced me to choose between the sail or the safety spell, plus a spell anchor.  Ultimately, I went with safety."</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Mythril is a bizarre outlier, however, with no known upper limit on the number of runes, plus power beyond that a pure metal should be capable of, due to the extreme density of the metal combined with its magical nature.</p>

<p>There's a brief discussion of the process of diffracting light, which involves Amelia using a prism as a visual aid.</p>

<p>Marta tries her own variation of the spell, which produces solid illusion of glass sails that extend about ten miles in every direction!  This produces enough force for them to feel it and Amelia is quite impressed.</p>

<p>Marta's spell breaks up fairly quickly under the strain of the solar wind and shatters, just like glass.</p>

<p>Iris goes next, experimenting with an illusion of a diamond sail, which produces less force than Marta's, though it lasts longer.  Amelia takes note of this improvement and heads for the spell-core, to produce a sail none of them will have to concentrate to maintain.</p>

<p>Just after Amelia gets a sail setup that extends for a hundred mile radius, Marta notes how clean the air of the room smells and asks why.  Amelia points out the fact that the spell-core's primary function is to clean and refresh the air, which is an important point for the next chapter.</p>

<p>They go back to the witchpit and Amelia settles in to get them on course, while her sisters stare out at the rainbow their ship is producing.</p>

<h2>Chapter 24: The Trouble With Breathing</h2>

<p>Back in the present, Amelia wakes from an unintended nap, with a headache and dizziness, due to too little oxygen and too much carbon-dioxide, because without the spell-core, the air of the ship is going bad.</p>

<p>She's somewhat surprised the mathematical portions of her brain are working at full capacity, which is weird, though she has a difficult time keeping them from wandering all over the place, including calculating how long she can survive without a change in the current situation, coming up short.  Just as quickly, she calculates the number of stars in the universe, then the number of zombies on the Dead Queen's ship.</p>

<p>She once again concludes The Book is enhancing her head for numbers and focuses long enough to run the numbers related to her survival a second time, realizing she has two hours to live, but only if she's unconscious.  Unfortunately, it will be six hours before her attack run on the monolith begins.</p>

<p>Amelia gets out of the pilot's seat of Starwitch and gets herself to crew quarters, where she puts on a pressure suit she built for herself, which is in a high-visibility orange color.  However, because she was in an artistic mood when she made it, it has black tiger stripes and a white belly, to make it look more like the animal.  The helmet resembles a fishbowl.</p>

<p>With the suit on, she turns on her oxygen tank at 70% of normal, which is enough to survive on.  Between her tank and those of her sisters, she calculates she can last for six hours at 70%, then have enough left over for twenty minutes of full mental clarity, which she'll need for her attack on the monolith.</p>

<p>Next, she heads for her workshop, where she grabs an icepick and a rubberized sack.  She opens a steam engine and uses a little magic to freeze the water.  With the sack held to catch the chips, she breaks up the ice.  This is taken to one wall, where there's a system for filling the rear water tank of <em>Starwitch</em>.  She dumps the ice into it, then repeats the process with the next steam engine, because she needs reaction mass to slow down the ship.</p>

<p>As she works, her mind wanders back to the past...</p>

<h2>Chapter 25: Ice Palace Two</h2>

<p>Amelia is again in the pilot's seat, using one of the scrying crystals to zoom in on a distant object, which turns out to be a huge block of ice floating in space, in the shape of a cube.</p>

<p>She calls her sisters into the witchpit to have a look, only for an alarm bell to sound.  Marta demands to know what that is and Amelia says it's an alarm indicating hostile magic.</p>

<p>Amelia starts up the main engines, for the sake of evasive maneuvers, while a huge ball of ice detaches from the ice block and flies their way, but maneuvering does no good, because the ball seems to have a homing spell on it!</p>

<p>After casting a scrying spell, Iris barks orders: "Amelia, face us straight into it!  Marta, on my mark, you shoot a heat spell, the strongest you've got, straight ahead!"</p>

<p>Iris waits until they've nearly collided, then shouts, "Now!"</p>

<p>Marta's heat spell causes the ball to instantly vaporize and they pass though a cloud of hot steam.  It gets rather warm in the ship, but they're fine.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, we switch to the perspective of Port Commander Haley Knotley, a half-dwarf witch that's in charge of the block of ice, which is actually a port (in-book word for a space station).  As it turns out, nearly the entire port is made of ice, though it has a spell-core at the center, like <em>Starwitch</em>.</p>

<p>Haley also has a small, mythril wand, which she uses to cast ice magic, to defend the port.</p>

<p>She mistook <em>Starwitch</em> for a pirate vessel, due to a lack of markings and attacked, to defend the station.</p>

<p>She sees her attack fail, only to be suddenly lifted off the floor by an invisible hand gripping her neck!  This is Iris using remote-touch.  Iris also uses a bone-transduction spell on Haley, so they can talk.</p>

<p>They argue for a moment, because Haley is beyond stubborn and has a hard time changing her mind once she's decided something, which is the very reason she's in charge of such a remote outpost.  Iris eventually gets Haley to calm down and talk.</p>

<p>After accepting the possibility <em>Starwitch</em> might not be a pirate vessel, Haley reluctantly gives them permission to dock.</p>

<p>Iris takes the helm and coordinates with Haley, while Amelia and Marta turn off their light sail spell and retract the masts into the hull.  Iris flies them around the side of the port, to an open bay door.</p>

<p>Inside, some figures in pressure suits scurry about, allowing Amelia to calculate the size of the port, at about two miles wide!  The landing/docking bay is rather big, but there's only a few small ships parked inside.</p>

<p>Iris flies them into it, and some external force takes over, for final landing.  Amelia and Marta are startled, but Iris tells them to relax, because Haley told her it was coming.</p>

<p>They deploy the landing gear of <em>Starwitch</em> and gently touch down.  By the way, Starwitch is designed to land very much like a plane, on a set of tires, while the side masts can be made to function like wings.</p>

<p>As that's happening, one of the figures uses a mythril wand to close the hatch of the landing bay, which is made of ice.  When that's done, another figures rushed to help, spraying water around the gap of the door, while the one with the wand uses it to freeze the water into a seal.</p>

<p>After that, the room begins to pressurize.  Eventually, all three of the docking bay workers remove their helmets.</p>

<p>The sisters exit <em>Starwitch</em> and Amelia gets a look at three other ships that are all smaller than her own.</p>

<p>The first is a red sphere with eight dual-purpose legs that appear able to extend to great length, to serve as masts for sails.</p>

<p>The next is shaped like a white snowflake, with a central body for living spaces and six extensions that possibly serve as masts, despite each of them having windows and living spaces in them.</p>

<p>The last is shaped like a green bug, with six legs and a set of cloth masts that are folded up on top of it, much like wings.</p>

<p>Amelia is immediately confronted by an angry witch, because normal procedure involves a strict schedule for opening and closing the docking bay and they were woken up to let <em>Starwitch</em> in, a waste of water and time.</p>

<p>The angry witch is joined by a polite and friendly witch, who says a few soothing things to get the woman to calm down.</p>

<p>The first apologizes, then introduces herself as Agnes Vixen.  The second says her name is Alice Talbot.  Amelia introduces herself and her sisters.</p>

<p>The figure that manned the hose finishes putting it away, then runs over, introducing himself as Nonar Bonebuster, though he does so rather loudly, because he has hearing issues.</p>

<p>Alice says, "Don’t mind Agnes.  She’s a <em>very</em> serious woman."</p>

<p>Nonar mishears and agrees that Angnes is very spurious.  Agnes smacks him on the back of the head and they begin arguing, while Alice leads the sisters to one side.</p>

<p>She explains that Nonar and Agnes are married and argue all the time.  She suggests with a wink that Nonar starts the arguments in public, so they can make-up in private.</p>

<p>Alice informs them that Haley wishes to see them, that she might apologize, and the sisters follow her.</p>

<h2>Chapter 26: A New Way of Life</h2>

<p>The sisters meet Haley face to face and Amelia accidentally insults Haley, by referring to her as a "little woman".</p>

<p>That's a label the half-dwarf objects to, because "little people" can be born to any race, but the dwarven race is distinct from them, just as elves, fairies, orcs, goblins and gnomes are not human.</p>

<p>Amelia apologizes and she learns about the existence of the other races and it would seem her home moon is entirely inhabited by humans, because she's never before heard of the other races.</p>

<p>As an apology for attacking them, Haley waives docking fees, and even offers to top of the water tanks of <em>Starwitch</em>, for free, a declaration that gets Alice to gasp, because Haley is extremely money-oriented.</p>

<p>Haley and the sisters introduce themselves and Haley asks where they're from.  They tell the truth and Haley asks why they left.</p>

<p>Again, they speak honestly: persecution and forced servitude as living weapons.  Alice is sympathetic to them, as is Haley, and they're assured they're among friends.  They're told most any Ice Palace will openly welcome them.</p>

<p>Amelia asks why the port is made of ice and Haley reveals her money-oriented nature again, by explaining that water is the currency used in space, because everyone needs it.  Her eyes light up as she explains that the place is literally made of money!</p>

<p>Further, Haley explains that the Ice Palace has a spell-core that keeps it at the right temperature and provides gravity.  The port is called <em>Ice Palace Two</em>, though it used to have another name: <em>Breadbasket</em>.</p>

<p>The history of Cakana, the moon below them, is explained by Alice.  Three-thousand years back, the moon was settled by witches and farmers, because it was one of two worlds in Junas orbit that was suitable for massive food production.  After three-hundred years, the farmers objected to the witches "never doing an honest day's work" and rose up in rebellion, using you guessed it: torches and pitchforks.</p>

<p>The witches peacefully backed down and the farmers took over.  This resulted in the witches no longer hauling food into orbit for sale, and most of them left.  Only a few stayed behind, which were the ancestors of the Blackwell sisters.</p>

<p>This change in government of the moon cut them off from the other moons of Junas and led to a shortage of food for everyone else, causing many deaths, over a pointless disagreement.</p>

<p>Haley asks the sisters to consider how they wish to live, because that will determine their allegiance and which markings their ship should bear, to avoid getting killed by non-pirates.</p>

<p>Alice explains a few options:</p>

<ul>
<li>They could become port workers, but the pay is crap and they'd be stuck in place.</li>
<li>They could join a merchant house to stay mobile, but the pay is still crap.</li>
<li>They could become couriers, which pays good, but they'd lack the safety and backing of a merchant house.</li>
<li>They could also become pirate hunters, who kill pirates for a living, a dangerous occupation.</li>
</ul>

<p>Regardless, however, Haley can only help them become couriers, because they're out in the boonies, but once they reach a more important port, they'll have more options.</p>

<p>Alice brings up the subject of navigation tables.  Every Ice Palace provides a free service of storing and sharing navigation tables, which are predetermined courses, including thrust and timing figures for courses guaranteed to be safe, if followed.  At this point, it's revealed that most of the moons of Junas are in orbital resonance, which makes preset navigation possible.</p>

<p>Amelia is surprised no one travels more directly and her comments gets her hosts talking about the "Newt Witches", the mysterious witches that rule the star system, and who rarely interfere in the affairs of others, unless attacked.</p>

<p>The Newt Witches seem to have an innate ability to calculate direct courses in their heads, on top of having incredibly potent weapons and magic.  The Newt Witches are also the group behind colonizing the system.  They own the Ice Palaces (the ports) and dress in red, covering their whole bodies, except their eyes.</p>

<p>Haley shares a story of witnessing a Newt Witch use incredible magic to snuff a pirate ship out of existence, first crushing it, followed by making it grow smaller under the crushing power of her magic, until it vanished.  Hypothetically, she described the formation of a small black hole.  This witch used some form of magic item combined with her own powers to make that happen.</p>

<p>Despite this incredible show of power, the woman was kind to Haley and spend a lot of time chatting with her, because the witch liked children.</p>

<p>Amelia begins to suspect she's a descendant of a Newt Witch and after her sisters ask some pointed question, this is confirmed, because the witches that stayed on Cakana were Newt Witches.</p>

<p>More subtle questions shift the subject to the origin of the Newt Witches and Alice offhandedly mentions a myth about a magic book that taught them to fly through space, which they lost and have been searching for, though this is only one story among many.</p>

<p>Getting uncomfortable and wishing to change the subject, Amelia decides they should become couriers, at least for the time being, and Haley shows them the symbol they need to paint on their ship, which looks like a stylized sailing ship that will basically be the space equivalent to flying a particular flag.</p>

<h2>Chapter 27: Rush Delivery</h2>

<p>Six months later, Iris is busy minding the ship as they launch from Ice Palace Three, which is in orbit of a lush, garden world that lacks seasons, because it's perpetually like spring there.</p>

<p>As she gets <em>Starwitch</em> away from the station, she chats with the Port Commander via a bone transduction spell.  The commander happens to be a fairy that fancies herself as a match-maker.  She's been trying to setup Iris with her brother.  As the subject comes up, Iris shades with embarrassment, but in the end, she decides aloud, "Next time."</p>

<p>She says goodbye to her friend and works the winches to deploy the masts.</p>

<p>After that, she passes into the entry room, which has become a cargo bay for the things they carry from port to port.  Currently, it's full of oranges, which are a gift from the port commander of the local Ice Palace to the commander of another.  This is a display of supreme confidence in the ability of Amelia to plot direct courses, because oranges spoil quickly.</p>

<p>Passing into crew quarters, she finds Amelia asleep, because she was up all night adding new cargo racks, since this shipment is the largest they've ever taken on, with the entry bay crammed from floor to ceiling, with only a narrow passage down the middle.</p>

<p>In the workshop, Iris finds Marta working at a potter's wheel to turn a bowl.  Marta has been making and selling pots with runic enchantments, which are a big money maker, almost as good as their rush delivery service as couriers.  It's revealed that almost no one in the system knows how runes work, aside from the Newt Witches, who don't sell enchantments.</p>

<p>Iris reaches the spell-core and briefly examines the current wheel of cheese the brownies have been eating, noting the fact they slowed down a lot, after the first few weeks.</p>

<p>She activates a sail spell, makes some minor adjustments to the gravity spell to help compensate for a coming engine burn, then heads back to the witchpit, where she pushes the engines to one-fifth power for twenty minutes, because their course requires both the sails and an engine burn, for a particularly speedy arrival.</p>

<p>In the next scene, Marta is minding the ship, in preparation for their last burn of the journey, after a few days travel.  In the rear-view scrying crystal, a red moon looms ever larger.</p>

<p>Amelia pops her head in as Marta begins the burn, asking if she'd like to get some rest.  Marta decides she wants to handle docking maneuvers.</p>

<p>Marta gets the ship inside <em>Ice Palace Sixty-Eight</em> and notices how full the docking bay is.  Most of the ships belong to The Silver Circle, which is the most prominent merchant house, though there's also a great many from The Twilight Flame, another big house.  There's some couriers mixed in, which makes Marta feel right at home.</p>

<p>The sisters have a two hour wait before the bay will pressurize and Marta joins her sisters for breakfast.  Amelia jokes about the dwarf port commander, who's obsessed with oranges, constantly raving about the first time he ate one.  She even does an impression of him: " 'Me was in heaven, it was so juicy and sweet!  Me hardly noticed the skin was still on, because me didn't know better!' "</p>

<p>In the next scene, they present the dwarf with the best crate of oranges, for his personal consumption, while his men work to unload the rest.</p>

<p>The dwarf actually tears up and thanks them for the crate, then Marta informs them they brought <em>ninety</em> crates.  The port commander's face becomes a mess of happy tears and he bites into one of the oranges, sucking the juice from it.  His tears freeze before they even hit the floor.</p>

<p>When he's done draining the orange, he comments, "<em>Sweet, juicy heaven!</em>"</p>

<p>The sisters laugh and turn to leave, but he stops them long enough to hand over a sealed letter, claiming it's a job offer.  The seal in the wax is a pair of crossed cutlasses, a symbol Amelia doesn't recognize.</p>

<p>Amelia opens and reads it, learning the Queen of a kingdom on the surface of Taneas wishes to hire them.  Taneas is the most distant moon of Junas, named after the goddess of commerce.  The moon is in an eccentric orbit that's only in direct contact with other worlds every 300 years, because it isn't in proper resonance with the other moons.</p>

<p>This Queen, named Edwina Rowley, wishes to initially employ the sisters as messengers, but if things go well, then she would like them to calculate courses for entire merchant convoys, promising 5% of all sales.</p>

<p>The sisters are moved with compassion for the people of Taneas and decide to take the job.  Amelia takes them straight to the navigation table of the port, which is a slab of granite mounted in the wall of the main hall.</p>

<p>She examines the figures describing the orbit of Taneas and decides it is possible for them to get there, though it will take three weeks of sailing.</p>

<p>With nothing better to do until the port's bay door opens, they go shopping.</p>

<p>The next scene focuses on a woman in a parka that's been following and observing the sisters, without being noticed, despite the way she's shivering cold.</p>

<p>She uses a bone transduction spell to report: "Captain, the fish have taken the bait, hook, line and sinker.  Looks like our intel was right, because they're real eager to help out ‘Queen Rowley’, <em>may she reign forever</em>.  The youngest sister says they'll arrive in three weeks."</p>

<p>The woman she's contacted laughs at her joke, then says, "Good.  Fishing is always better from a well-stocked pond.  Continue to observe from a safe distance."</p>

<p>The witch in the parka ends her spell, then complains, "Just so long as I don’t freeze to death.  I hate Ice Palaces!"</p>

<h2>Chapter 28: Roaring Rowley</h2>

<p>The Blackwell sisters have arrived in orbit of Taneas and they're above the night side of the moon, noting a bizarre sight: yellow-white dots and lines illuminate the land.</p>

<p>They're confused for a time, before Amelia explains that they're looking at what could only be a huge, sprawling city.  It won't be revealed for some time, but Taneas has rejected magic and embraced technology.  They're currently at about the level of Earth, but they <em>do not</em> look to the stars like we do.</p>

<p>In fact, they know space is full of magic, and anyone that touches their atmosphere will be shot at by multiple nations at once, with surface-to-air missiles.  In effect, this is very much a "look, but don't touch" world.</p>

<p>The sisters aren't sure how to contact Queen Rowley and Amelia suggests they try to locate a suitable landing site, once they roll around to the daytime side.  Failing that, they'll have to wait for the Queen to contact them, because she must employ someone with remote-viewing ability.</p>

<p>In the next scene, Captain Edwina "Roaring" Rowley comments, "You may rest assured in that, Amelia Blackwell."</p>

<p>She's been using remote-viewing magic to observe the sisters for days.</p>

<p>Her ship is made of glass and crystal, which normally gives a view of space, but at the moment, they're hidden by a spell to bend light around the ship, making them invisible.  This makes it impossible to see, however, which is among the reasons Rowley is using scrying magic.</p>

<p>Her observations have turned up an interesting fact: Amelia is the owner of <em>The Book of Newts</em>, which Rowley is quite aware of, because she was a Newt Witch before she turned pirate.</p>

<p>The Book has been lost to the Newt Witches for 2,000 years, not because they misplaced it, but because it ran away.  This isn't explained, but they were using it as a reference, rather than using it to explore the universe, which is why it arranged to be stolen, presumably by manipulating the mind of one of the witches.</p>

<p><em>The Order of Newts</em> is mentioned as the name of the ruling body of witches and it's confirmed that Amelia's mathematical gift is basically what makes someone a Newt Witch, though not a member of the order.  It's also explained that the mathematical gift gives one the ability to see through The Book's illusions, though the real truth is that Amelia's gift is weaker than average and The Book made sure she saw through the illusions, because it liked her mind.</p>

<p>Rowley intends to take The Book for herself, though she plans to act with great precaution, because she expects just about anything to happen.  After all, Amelia has the book.</p>

<p>Rowley gives orders in preparation for an attack, which will happen as soon as they're out of the shadow of Teneas.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_writing.html'>writing</a>, <a href='tag_work-in-progress.html'>work-in-progress</a>, <a href='tag_starwitch.html'>starwitch</a></p>

<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://owentyme.us/blog/work-in-progress-23-starwitch-6.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/blog/./work-in-progress-23-starwitch-6.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Owen Tyme</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 10:09:17 -0600</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Work In Progress #22: Starwitch #5
</title><description><![CDATA[

<blockquote>
  <p><span class="book-cover">
<a href="../books/book-of-newts/starwitch.html"><img src="../images/Cover-Starwitch.jpg" alt="" title="" /></a>
</span></p>

<p>Amelia sobbed, closed her eyes and accepted her impending death, until a glimmer of hope pierced the darkness, a single point of light so intense she saw it through her eyelids!  She opened them and looked, but her vision was blurred from too many tears.</p>

<p>&nbsp; – An excerpt from Starwitch.</p>

<div style="clear: both;"></div>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="../books/book-of-newts/starwitch.html">Starwitch</a> is a novel about space-faring witches that I plan to release first as a web series, then for sale in online stores.</p>

<p><a href="https://mastodon.social/@OwenTyme/113483873966306253">You can read short summaries of each day's writing on Mastodon.</a></p>

<p>Here's a list of previous blog entries on this work in progress novel, in order from oldest to newest:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="work-in-progress-18-starwitch-1.html">Starwitch #1</a></li>
<li><a href="work-in-progress-19-starwitch-2.html">Starwitch #2</a></li>
<li><a href="work-in-progress-20-starwitch-3.html">Starwitch #3</a></li>
<li><a href="work-in-progress-21-starwitch-4.html">Starwitch #4</a></li>
</ul>

<h2>Chapter 19: Sticks, Stones and Words</h2>

<p>Using scrying magic to watch for trouble, Iris informs her sisters, "We've got company: two witches on sticks!"</p>

<p>Marta switches to the rear-facing seat and tells her sisters it's Denholm and Krauss.  Iris reminds Marta to focus on Denholm.</p>

<p>Iris tries to kill Krauss by crushing her heart with remote-touch, but Krauss is able to barely protect herself with blood magic.  She does, however, fall off her stick and injures herself enough to be out of the fight.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Marta uses the rear spring-gonne to shoot at Denholm, very nearly killing her with a spell to make the lead balls target-seeking!</p>

<p>Denholm loses her temper and her eyes glow, followed by her entire body, surrounding her in an angry, red aura, which makes her hair float on end.</p>

<p>Denholm begins a complex incantation that would have ended with the magic word for 'kill', but Iris uses remote-touch to force her mouth shut before she finishes!</p>

<p>Amelia suggests: "If she wants to play with sticks, how about you give her some stones?"</p>

<p>Marta agrees and focuses on a complex incantation, which is a multi-stage spell, including linking syllables held on the tongue to create brief delays before modifying the spell's effect.</p>

<p>Initially, Denholm uses gravity-based telekinesis (Denholm is a gravity witch, as it turns out) to fend off hundreds of boulders Marta ripped out of the ground!  Denholm shatters and deflects boulders, while smaller fragments bounce off her glowing aura!</p>

<p>Denholm thinks she's done with Marta's spell and charges to attack, while Amelia switches on the war wagon's steam-based rocket boosters to get out of the powerful witch's reach.  Yes, Amelia effectively built a rocket-tank.</p>

<p>Marta triggers the next stage of her spell, which causes all the fragments of rock to heat up and continue seeking Denholm.  It all turns into lava and the bristles of Denholm's broom catch fire!</p>

<p>She glances back, sees the incoming attack and focuses entirely on defense as the lava envelopes her!</p>

<p>Marta triggers the third and final stage of her spell, instantly cooling the lava into a big ball of obsidian, three feet thick! Whether she's alive or dead, Denholm rolls off on her own.</p>

<p>The sisters reach their front gate, which Iris blasts with magic and they crash through the gardens of the yard, including a topiary creation that looks like the sisters and a floral clock.</p>

<p>Amelia drives them toward the tower holding <em>Starwitch</em>.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Krauss finishes healing herself and forms a magical link to Denholm, to feed her magic.  Denholm shatters the obsidian sphere holding her and gives Krauss new orders: "We terminate the traitors with extreme prejudice!  I don't care who or what gets in the way!"</p>

<p>In short, they won't be trying to avoid damaging the war wagon after this and will be going all-out.  That may have been the only reason they failed at all.</p>

<h2>Chapter 20: Launch</h2>

<p>The Blackwell sisters load the war wagon into the cargo bay of <em>Starwitch</em>, the open area at the bottom.  They seal it inside, then climb the tower to board the ship.</p>

<p>The boarding plank is kicked out and the door is sealed.  Marta is strapped in, while Iris climbs to the Witchpit, where she straps into the pilot's seat.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Amelia climbs all the way down, to reach the spell-core, which she uses to ignite thermite that's been hidden inside the supports of the tower.  The thermite melts through the steel holding the two halves of the tower together and one whole side falls away, producing a minor quake.</p>

<p>Next, Amelia uses the spell-core to briefly manipulate gravity to point away from <em>Starwitch</em> and most of the rest of the tower breaks free, leaving only a support gantry designed to keep <em>Starwitch</em> from falling over, which is reinforced with steel.  Amelia climbs back up, strapping in beside Marta.</p>

<p>Iris starts the launch engines, which are little more than long pipes running half the length of the vessel, which are absolutely filled with little, metal plates enchanted with runes to make them vaporize water on contact, though they also heat steam.  These pipes are linked to the four rocket nozzles at the tail of the ship.</p>

<p>Steam pours from the vessel and it lurches into the air.  Sacrificial bolts attaching the support gantry to <em>Starwitch</em> snap, which were in turn attached to high-tension cables that were part of what kept the bottom of the gantry stable, while the steam forces the gantry to fall away from the rocket.</p>

<p>Starwitch rises through the air at a leisurely pace at first, because Amelia is concerned that full throttle would kill their servants, an unnecessary loss of life.  The intent is for them to rise to three-thousand feet before going full throttle.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Denholm and Krauss fly on one broomstick, together, landing on top of the mansion as they see the rocket rise.  Denholm tries to destroy the rocket with magic, but she can't directly affect it, because Amelia put some protective enchantments on it.  Likewise, Krauss tries to kill the sisters with blood magic, but also fails.</p>

<p>In the end, Denholm demands, "How much do you weigh?"</p>

<p>Krauss answers honestly, "One-sixty!  Why?"</p>

<p>Denholm begins casting a spell to hurl Krauss into the air, which she begins objecting to, but Denholm pays her words no heed, telekinetically throwing Krauss into the sky!</p>

<p>Krauss screams, of course, but that makes no difference.</p>

<p>Iris sees Krauss on the rise and tells Amelia, who gets out of her seat and requests a reduction in throttle, so she can climb back down to the spell-core.</p>

<p>When she's there, she lays down and puts a hand on the magic device, concentrating first on a scrying spell, so she can see what's going on outside, then an air-manipulation spell, to attack Krauss with blasts of pressurized air.</p>

<p>Amelia nearly beats Krauss senseless, because her attacks have the advantage of being invisible, since they're made of air.  Krauss takes some heavy injuries before enacting a spell that causes her to bleed enough that she can surround herself in a protective shell of blood, which intercepts Amelia's attacks and incidentally helps with air friction.</p>

<p>Amelia is forced on the defensive as Krauss begins firing her own blood like pellets from a huge shotgun!  Amelia blocks most of them with a barrier of air, but a few of Krauss' blood bullets hit the ship.</p>

<p>As Krauss presses the advantage, firing still more blood bullets, Amelia demands to know their altitude and Iris says, "Twenty-five-hundred!"</p>

<p>Amelia shouts back, "Close enough!  Go full-throttle!"</p>

<p>Iris obeys and <em>Starwitch</em> goes from one-third to full throttle!  The sudden increase in volume bursts the eardrums of Krauss and Amelia goes back on offense, managing to knock the witch cold!</p>

<p>Denholm, who's been watching the whole time, to direct the flight of Krauss, gives up and brings her subordinate back to the ground, though she's disappointed.</p>

<p>This marks the escape of the sisters from their home moon.</p>

<p>Denholm gets on her broom and tracks down the carriage driven by Dawkin.  She captures him, but soon discovers he has some papers stuffed into his jacket pocket.</p>

<p>Getting curious, Denholm takes the papers and unfolds them, revealing the plans for <em>Starwitch</em>.  In this moment, she basically vows to track the sisters down, that she might have revenge and justice for her King.  It may take years, but Denholm is not one to give up.  This is an intentional hanging plot thread, which I'll come back to in another book, because Denholm is far too much fun for me to toss her on the garbage heap.</p>

<p>She's so distracted by her find, Dawkin manages to escape.  At the next town, he paints the carriage, ties a canvas tarp over it, to make it look like a junk wagon, then hitches a horse to the front, instead of using the engine, all to make himself look like a junk merchant.  This allows him to escape the country.</p>

<h2>Chapter 21: The Next Horizon</h2>

<p>Iris cuts the engines, presumably since they've left the atmosphere, and Amelia briefly struggles with zero-G.  After fumbling around for a bit, as the wheel of cheese floats about, Amelia figures out how to move around and gets hold of the ladder, "climbing" to the witchpit.</p>

<p>She joins Iris there, who's getting sick.  Amelia takes the pilot's seat and Iris loses her breakfast in the background, using a paper sack to catch it.</p>

<p>Amelia assesses their course, calculating their altitude and velocity in her head, then proceeds to using calculus, which she learned from <em>The Book of Newts</em>, to calculate the details of the engine burn that will get them into a stable orbit.</p>

<p>She begins to worry about her ability to do such complex math in her head.  Her ability to make numbers dance and sing had always been unusual, but from the moment she obtained <em>The Book of Newts</em>, she found if much easier to work even complex calculations in her head.  She isn't certain and it isn't spelled out, but this is a perk of owning The Book.</p>

<p>However, just as she's starting to ask serious questions about what The Book is trying to do, Iris draws her attention to the view through the windows.</p>

<p>Both of them have their breath taken away by the sight and Amelia tears up, with the droplets gathering around her eyes, due to the lack of gravity.</p>

<p>She wipes them away and the sisters stare with awe as the liquid floats free, naturally becoming a series of spheres.  Iris thanks the Gods for their safe escape from the moon they once called home and Amelia also says a quick prayer of thanks.</p>

<p>Shortly after, Amelia gets back to work, because if she doesn't correct their course, they'll fall back into the atmosphere and burn up.</p>

<p>Amelia uses water-based maneuvering thrusters to turn them parallel to the ground, then Iris straps herself in, beside Marta, who's still unconscious.  Amelia watches the second hand of the witchpit's clock as she runs the engines for a precise amount of time, to circularize their course into a proper orbit.</p>

<p>After that, Amelia uses the spell-core to create an artificial gravity field inside the ship, then lays out a mattress on the floor of the crew quarters, shrugs out of her military uniform and gets to sleep, while Iris watches for trouble.</p>

<p>Amelia dreams of flying <em>Starwitch</em> toward the sun, leaving Junas behind.  She argues with her sisters rather often, but can't recall the words or the subject matter.</p>

<p>The sun looms ever larger and a time comes in which Amelia becomes certain they're going to burn up.  However, as she's looking out at it, she sees lines forming on its surface, between six points along the edge.</p>

<p>First, a hexagon forms, then every other point is linked, forming a six-pointed star from two overlapping triangles.  Then the hexagon formed as the center of the star starts the process again, with a new star forming inside it.  The process continues until the details are so small and fine, Amelia can't see them, forming a geometric fractal.</p>

<p>All of this is a magic circle.  At the center, a point of blackness is seen, which quickly expands and <em>Starwitch</em> is drawn into it, causing Amelia to scream in her sleep!</p>

<p>The darkness is far deeper and more terrifying than anything Amelia has ever experienced before, and as it snuffs out the lights of the ship, she succumbs to a mind-numbing depression, curling herself into the fetal position as she gives up all hope.</p>

<p>Just as she's totally given up, intense light interrupts the darkness, and she wakes.</p>

<p>Her sisters look on her with worry, because she was both screaming and crying in her sleep.  Amelia can't remember the dream, but she knows The Book of Newts was trying to show her something, because she recognizes its subtle magic swirling around.</p>

<p>On hearing about this, Amelia's sisters become quite concerned, but Amelia is forced to tell them she doesn't remember the dream.  This is a little foreshadowing for later books, though it should soon spark Amelia to try talking with the book again, probably while she holds a hand on the spell-core.</p>

<p>Amelia dresses in clothes she designed for wearing on the ship, which is basically a custom set of coveralls made just for her, though it has a series of loops and pockets for tools around the waist.  Her sisters have already changed into their own shipboard uniforms and Marta uses her tool loops to hold some jerked meat, so she'll always have a snack on hand.</p>

<p>Amelia fills a canteen with water from a spigot in the wall that's linked to the water tanks and drinks a little, then gets herself some jerky, while they discuss what comes next.</p>

<p>Amelia says there's somewhere nearby that they can sail to, at least according to <em>The Book of Newts</em>, which has detailed maps.</p>

<h2>Chapter 1: Lonely</h2>

<p>I revisited chapter one today, because I thought of an opening scene that would set the main conflict rolling from the first paragraph.</p>

<p>Amelia and her sisters have been captured by the Dead Queen and the zombie soldiers have forced them into a line, according to both height and age.</p>

<p>Marta and Iris both try to fight, but their words are cut short by torture magic that leaves them screaming.</p>

<p>In stark contrast, Amelia begins to cry, because she feels utterly helpless, and the evil, undead witch laughs.</p>

<p>The monstrous woman instructs her soldiers to take Marta away, so the Queen can consume her soul.  Marta begs and pleads, to no avail.</p>

<p>The Queen next decides that Iris is another suitable candidate to consume, but Iris has more fire in her and fights back, only for the Queen to hit her with another torture spell.</p>

<p>Coming to Amelia, the witch thinks aloud, "What to do, what to do?  I've never seen such a weak witch before.  I could consume her soul, but I would probably waste more magic in the act than I would gain…"</p>

<p>The pirate witch paces for a time, before saying, "The other two will enrich my magic for centuries to come, but this fish?  Throw her back, because she’s <em>too weak!</em>  Oh, and drain the water tanks of her little vessel before you release it, but leave her enough to force her to choose between maneuvering and drinking water!"</p>

<p>Amelia is dragged away.</p>

<h2>Chapter 22: Weaponsmith</h2>

<p>Amelia is alone in the workshop of <em>Starwitch</em>, back in the present, the flashback paused for the moment.</p>

<p>She's busy assembling a prototype spring-gonne, which consists of some pipes and clockwork mechanisms, very similar to a pinball launcher, only with much stronger springs, approximately the same power as a crossbow.</p>

<p>Each barrel is six inches long, with a six-inch chamber for the spring mounted behind it.  Each spring chamber has a rod for drawing the spring back sticking out to one side, which hooks into clockwork mechanisms of the pistol, allowing a cocking handle to be drawn back, very similar to some toys that shoot foam darts.</p>

<p>The mechanisms in the handle allow cocking each barrel in turn, then fired individually.  The barrels don't rotate.  Amelia refers to the device as a "hand-gonne".</p>

<p>Amelia considers how deadly it will be once she's done, and her mind is drawn to the past, when she was eight years old.</p>

<p>Her mother caught her experimenting with a grasshopper, by cutting off its back legs, followed by sewing them back on.  Amelia had been effectively trying to do a biology experiment, out of curiosity.</p>

<p>Her mother takes a dim view of this and squashes the poor creature, to put it out of its misery.</p>

<p>They have a discussion about what constitutes animal cruelty and what doesn't, even considering the matter of killing animals to eat them.</p>

<p>Amelia apologizes for hurting the insect and her mother extracts a vow from her that's very similar to the one she got from Marta.</p>

<p>In essence, Amelia promises to never harm a person and only harm animals when necessary.</p>

<p>Back in the present, she considers the harm she did to "Killer" Krauss.  Technically, she violated her vow, but it had been a matter of weighing three lives against one and in truth, Amelia didn't kill Krauss.  She only knocked her cold, an injury Krauss could easily heal with magic, once she woke up.  In short, very little harm was done and all of it was necessary.</p>

<p>Amelia considers how her vow applies to undead and concludes killing them would be a mercy, like unto putting down a rabid dog.  She especially applies that last thought to the Dead Queen, because killing her would end her abominable, undead existence and ultimately save lives.</p>

<p>In short, Amelia has nothing to hold her back in the upcoming fight, though she still feels nothing but regret for dragging her sisters into danger.</p>

<h2>Future Plans</h2>

<p>Now that I've got the sisters in space, my main concern is to set the stage for the end conflict.  On the other hand, however, I'm only halfway through episode 6 and I need to finish the flashbacks by the end of episode 8, so the climax can begin in episode 9.</p>

<h3>Episodes 9+10: The Climax</h3>

<p>My episodes have all been four chapters, so far, and making the climax two parts would involve about eight chapters.  However, I can safely assume the last chapter of the book will be given over to tying up loose ends, but I may add a short epilogue at the end, after episode 10, probably just to tease what's coming in book two.</p>

<p>The epilogue will probably consist of the Dead Queen screaming with rage and getting her monolith on the move, to chase the escaping sisters down.  This will serve almost as a preview of the next season.</p>

<p>In short, that means I need the climax to be 7 chapters, which is reasonable enough.  That leaves me with two chapters for each of my three protagonists, plus one mostly dedicated to the Dead Queen, so we can really learn what motivates her.</p>

<p>I have many details in mind for the climax, which will be more action-packed than anything else in the book.  I could describe it now, but I don't want to spoil the details until I get there.</p>

<h3>The Near Future</h3>

<p>I'm left with a conundrum: what goes into the end of episodes 6 through 8?</p>

<p>I've done the things I planned early on, including establishing the prejudice and strife that propelled the sisters into space and the war Dugaria started was an excellent way to leave the sisters with emotional scars that may never heal, a fact that makes them more interesting to read about.  It also made them strong enough to fight a war, even though they object to violence.</p>

<p>I believe I've covered the necessary growth and scarring of my characters, and I could shorten the season to make it a total of eight episodes, which would probably get the length to around 85,000 words.</p>

<p>This isn't an option I like, however, and I hope you'll bear with me as I consider options, below, as a sort of brainstorming session.</p>

<h3>Episode 6</h3>

<p>The end of episode six (one more chapter) should demonstrate how light sails work, giving me a chance to detail the almost musical chimes the masts produce under load, probably due to the cables inside the masts vibrating under the effects of slight waste magic.  I'll probably include a montage-like scene of Amelia teaching her sisters everything about <em>Starwitch</em> and the magic it uses, to cover the week it takes them to reach their first space station at a leisurely pace.</p>

<p>I also need to make a point of showing Amelia wistfully looking down and thinking about Dawkin, as her sisters try to comfort her.  This is something I'll have to do regularly, through this and the next season, since Amelia's feelings for Dawkin will be a central point of the third.</p>

<p>The sisters will find surprising acceptance at stations, because magic has always been the tool of choice for traveling the stars, whether through runic enchantments, witchcraft or wizardry.</p>

<p>In the novel, I'm likely to refer to space stations as "ports", since that's how chapter one referred to them.  Just about every moon of Junas has at least one, including their own, though they'll soon find it has no connection to the surface, because the people down there are so very backward.</p>

<p>This will also give me a chance to give the names of some moons, in the form of potential places the sisters can visit or should avoid, which are named after the gods of the setting.</p>

<p>For example, Cakana is the name of the moon they orbit, which is the name of the goddess of agriculture and harvests.  Cakana's chief export used to be food, before the locals decided they hated witches for being smarter than them, a story the people of this first port can tell them.  I imagine the story boiling down to the following paragraph:</p>

<p>Farmers were brought to the world by witches, because the land was so good, but after a hundred years, the farmers came to resent being ruled by "smug, know-it-all witches that don't work a day of their lives", a direct quote from the farmers of the time.  They rose up with torches and pitchforks, leading the witches to back down, due to their vows of non-violence.  Aftet that, the farmers ruled themselves, cut themselves off from contact with space (that always required the witches) and over thousands of years, forgot the past.</p>

<p>There will be a variety of little micro-fiction stories about various moons, to explain the more prominent ones, ranging from a single sentence for something amusing, but unimportant, to several paragraphs for those that matter.  I should be able to somewhat explain the setting's pantheon of gods in the process.</p>

<h3>Episode 7</h3>

<p>I think episode 7 will serve to establish how things work in space, probably after a six to twelve month time skip.  I'll get a chance to show how the sisters earn their keep, probably by hauling cargo and building things.</p>

<p>I think one chapter should be dedicated to making an ordinary delivery of metal ingots, followed by a chapter about a visit to their favorite port, which probably orbits a moon inhabited by dwarves.  I might go so far as to make that port an orbital tether, because dwarves always build big.</p>

<p>In these two chapters, I plan to sprinkle in mentions of pirates in the area, with people saying they're grateful the Dead Queen hasn't been seen in Junas orbit for a few years, though her lieutenants still harass everyone for "protection money", with each of them assigned to patrol a particular moon.</p>

<p>My thinking is that the Queen has been on the outskirts of the star system on some long-haul trip to capture a rebellious subordinate, so she can eat the woman's soul.</p>

<p>With the scene in space set, I think the chapter after that will cover the sisters accepting another delivery job, which will take them to a moon they've heard very little about, which is incidentally in neutralterritory, in orbit of a moon that has no contact with space and no port in orbit.</p>

<p>The job turns out to be a ruse to get the sisters out of the network of stations that are current on their "protection" fees, leading to them being attacked by one of the Dead Queen's lieutenants, a powerful witch.  Unlike her boss, this one is alive.</p>

<p>The episode will end on some action and a cliffhanger, in which the sisters look like they might just die, to add some suspense.</p>

<h3>Episode 8</h3>

<p>The episode will begin with a battle between <em>Starwitch</em> and a pirate vessel that's probably made of rune-enchanted stained glass.  The sisters will barely win, but the bottom mast will be badly damaged, which forces them to slow down.</p>

<p>In the next chapter, the witch they defeated will contact her boss, telling the Dead Queen all about the Blackwell sisters and I'll perhaps write something from the villain's perspective.  Meanwhile, Amelia goes on a spacewalk, to make repairs.</p>

<p>Just as she begins addressing the damaged mast as her last repair task, the Dead Queen's monolith will show up and Amelia will lose her concentration just long enough for the broken mast to slip from her hands and drift away, which will lead into a break between chapters.</p>

<p>The third chapter of the episode will come back to Amelia in the present, pausing the flashback for a time.  In this chapter, she'll go on another spacewalk, to adjust the way the war wagon sits inside the cargo bay, because it has technically been upside down, all along.</p>

<p>She'll also work to make the cargo bay hatch into a ramp for the vehicle to drive out of, when <em>Starwitch</em> is landed.  This task will briefly involve Amelia over-taxing herself with magic, to create a bubble of partial atmosphere around the ship, since the cargo bay is pressurized.</p>

<p>Once her work is done, she'll briefly stare out into space and her mind will once more drift to the past.</p>

<p>The last chapter of the episode will show the sisters pulling out all the stops, in an attempt to out-run the Dead Queen's monolith, using all of their magic combined with the spell-core and the launch engines of Starwitch, to produce maximum thrust, but it won't be enough.</p>

<p>Despite the fact the monolith is practically a mountain made of granite, it will be fast enough to gain on them.  In a last-ditch effort, the sisters will try to out-maneuver it, but that will also fail, because the monolith uses a set of powerful, central engines, along with a system to vector superheated steam to any exterior thruster, on any side.  Effectively, the monolith's engines will bear some resemblance to those of a Harrier Jet, only far larger.</p>

<p>I think the sisters will start graying out from acceleration, while the monolith's crew is unaffected, because they're undead.</p>

<p>The episode will end with their capture, which leads directly to the opening scene of the novel, getting the reader fully up to date.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_writing.html'>writing</a>, <a href='tag_work-in-progress.html'>work-in-progress</a>, <a href='tag_starwitch.html'>starwitch</a></p>

<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://owentyme.us/blog/work-in-progress-22-starwitch-5.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/blog/./work-in-progress-22-starwitch-5.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Owen Tyme</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 10:50:04 -0600</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Work In Progress #21: Starwitch #4
</title><description><![CDATA[

<blockquote>
  <p>"Keep in mind that if this test fails, I'm not going to let you live." Her eyes glowed, bathing Amelia's face in red light, before she went on, "I'll get an earful form His Majesty over it, but ultimately, I can argue I acted in his best interest, because you're definitely not."</p>

<p>&nbsp; – Lieutenant Colonel Denholm (An excerpt from Starwitch).</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="../books/starwitch/index.html">Starwitch</a> is a novel about space-faring witches that I plan to release first as a web series, then for sale in online stores.</p>

<p><a href="https://mastodon.social/@OwenTyme/113483873966306253">You can read short summaries of each day's writing on Mastodon.</a></p>

<p>Here's a list of previous blog entries on this work in progress novel, in order from oldest to newest:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="work-in-progress-18-starwitch-1.html">Starwitch #1</a></li>
<li><a href="work-in-progress-19-starwitch-2.html">Starwitch #2</a></li>
<li><a href="work-in-progress-20-starwitch-3.html">Starwitch #3</a></li>
</ul>

<h2>Chapter 13: Marta's Mission</h2>

<p>Five years have passed and Marta is on a mission in the jungles between Dugaria and Skobia, along with a small squad of men that include a Lieutenant and Sergeant.  Marta has been promoted to Corporal.</p>

<p>She's in her accustomed place in line, between the Lieutenant and Sergeant, who put her life above their own, since witches are so few, compared to regular soldiers.</p>

<p>Marta suspects Dugaria's claim that Skobia attacked first is total garbage, because the constitution only allows using witches for defensive purposes.  Hypothetically, the claim that Skobia attacked first and refuses to give up, even though it's one-third the size, is propaganda, to allow using witches for an invasion.</p>

<p>Marta grows depressed and her thoughts follow this pattern:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Five years as a dog of the military.  Five years as an Artillery Witch.  Five years of violating the vow she'd taken as a child, leaving her feeling so dirty, no amount of soap ever made her feel clean.  Five years of looking for a way out, only for no solution to present itself.  She was trapped in the worst kind of nightmare, in which she took the starring role, as the monster that burned men alive.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>She secretly hopes to become numb to that pain, but knows when that day comes, it will be the worst so far, because she'll know she's become nothing more than a mass-murderer.</p>

<p>Her thoughts are interrupted by their quiet and secret arrival at the edge of a clearing that holds an enemy fort.  It's Marta's time to do her job and she begins charging a wide-area fire spell carefully tuned to burn only soldiers.</p>

<p>While she waits for the magic to gather in her spell, she looks on the fort, seeing some men come back from patrols looking tired, with their guard down.  They're all rather young, about sixteen years old, roughly the same age as the private standing beside Marta.</p>

<p>She decides she can't kill them and starts draining the magic from her spell.</p>

<p>She flashes back to when she was thirteen years old and standing in the corner, because her mother had caught her casting a spell to give a boy pimples and boils, an offense that got Marta slapped, even though her mother had never struck her before.</p>

<p>They've been arguing and Marta demands to know why her Mother quietly serves the villagers, when she could use magic to make herself their ruler.</p>

<p>Her Mother's explanation:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>"I love them.  They're my friends and neighbors.  I went to school with them and I deliver their babies.  I agree that they're stupid and ignorant, but that will never change the fact that I love them all, aside from the Mayor, but I make an exception for him, because he's so frustrating, but he's just doing what he feels is right, even if it should be wrong."</p>
</blockquote>

<p>She also points out that if she used magic to take over, then she'd never know another moment's peace and calls politics a thresher for the thumb; better to stay out of it.</p>

<p>Marta is forced to admit her mother has a point.</p>

<p>Her mother asks if Marta remembers the first thing she was taught about doctoring.</p>

<p>"The right way to bandage a wound?" Marta asks.</p>

<p>Her mother answers, "No, before that."</p>

<p>Marta is confused, because bandaging was first.</p>

<p>Still, her mother insists that something came first and Marta thinks it over, finally saying, " 'Do no harm.' "</p>

<p>Mother explains that Marta not only used magic to do harm, but also involved her medical training in the offense, which was the reason she got slapped.</p>

<p>Marta apologizes and her Mother extracts a vow that Marta will never harm anyone with magic again.</p>

<p>Back in the present, the Sergeant sees Marta bleeding off the power in her spell and asks, "Corporal, what's the holdup?"</p>

<p>Marta reasons that if she fights back and refuses to follow orders, then Amelia's plans for escape might be ruined, because Marta will be forced to serve in chains, rather than a uniform.  Marta has no idea what those plans are, because Amelia has kept them to herself and asked Marta to play along with the army.</p>

<p>Marta reluctantly releases her spell on the people in the fort, who die screaming, burned alive.  She feels no remorse and doesn't cry, despite witnessing it with hr own eyes.</p>

<p>Her small squad occupies the large fort, in preparation for reinforcements, who will arrive in five minutes.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Marta is exhausted and dumps the ashes off a chair, so she can sit down.  She realizes for the first time, ever, she didn't cry for those she's killed.  At this point, she cries for the loss of her own remorse.  She begins considering immolating both herself and her squad the next time she's called on to harm anyone, reasoning that will save lives.</p>

<p>Her skull begins vibrating to produce sound only she can hear and the voice of a witch from the WIA (Witch Intelligence Agency) back in Rimestar reaches her ears.  Marta reports the success of the mission (the witch's spell is two-way).</p>

<p>The witch relays word that Marta's next assignment will be back home, due to some demonstration.  Marta reasons that will involve one of Amelia's prototypes.  Marta is glad to hear it, because she wants to have a word with Amelia; if Amelia doesn't get them out of Dugaria soon, then she'll lose her oldest sister.</p>

<p>The WIA witch ends the communication spell and Marta feels the eerie calm of one that's decided to end their life.</p>

<h2>Chapter 14: Iris and Intrigue</h2>

<p>The body of Iris floats in a sensory deprivation tank in one of the remote-viewing rooms of Fort Stand.  At the same time, her mind is far away, at the front lines, where a battle recently concluded.</p>

<p>The area is full of bodies, most of them Skobian soldiers, who wear yellow sashes over their armor.  Iris is overwhelmed by the sight, sounds and smell of the battlefield, bothered by the stench of blood and burnt human flesh.</p>

<p>She hears a soft cry for help and investigates, finding a Skobian soldier, who was blinded by the same explosion that took his legs off and he's blubbering about the war, asking why Dugaria refuses to let Skobia surrender.</p>

<p>Iris is disturbed by the implications, because she has her doubts about the propaganda the government spews out as an excuse for a witch-assisted invasion of a resource-rich neighboring country.</p>

<p>Just as she's considering the soldier's words, another witch steps through Iris' mental projection, briefly making her vision go out of focus, though she had a quick look through the other woman's sinus cavities, showing her mostly red, with lines for bones and blood vessels.</p>

<p>The witch screams, "Shut your lying mouth!" as she claps a hand on his forehead and uses magic to make his head explode!</p>

<p>Iris looks away, but is still disturbed to see blood rain down.</p>

<p>The evil witch rattles off the number 1299, then asks Iris if she'd found any more survivors, because shew wants her kill count to be a nice, round number.  By way of explanation, the two of them are linked with a Bone Transduction spell, similar to the one Marta experienced with a WIA witch.</p>

<p>Iris has seen other survivors, but chooses to lie to Captain "Killer" Krauss, because Krauss is totally gone in the head, far too obsessed with counting her personal kills.  Additionally, standing orders are to always take a few prisoners for interrogation and Iris has no desire to see more death.</p>

<p>Krauss runs off to find another victim and Iris returns to getting an accurate casualty count on both sides, which has been her primary responsibility, so far.</p>

<p>She ends her spells and emerges from the tank, reporting the numbers to her superior officer, who tells her to dry off and head for Room Nine, an infamous room surrounded by ominous rumors.</p>

<p>Iris obeys and knocks on the door.  After identifying herself, she's ushered into a dark room lit by a single, dim candle that doesn't reveal the witches hidden around the edges of the room.</p>

<p>They question her for a time and Iris confirms she can not only remote-view, but also remote-hear and remote-smell while she's at it.</p>

<p>They test her by tricking her into remote-viewing the men's washroom, which makes her go bright red, but she confirms her ability to smell the other room by revealing the men are using lavender soap.</p>

<p>Next, Captain Denholm and a witch general in a black uniform step into the light, beginning a discussion that Iris doesn't quite follow, as they talk about the King of Skobia and his court vizier, a wizard of no small reputation.</p>

<p>The old General orders Iris to remote-view the washroom again and orders her to try picking up a bar of soap.  She does so and much to her surprise, it works.  She lifts it high into the air and the men run screaming from the room, a commotion that can be heard in the halls.</p>

<p>Iris is initially pleased to learn she has the power to remote-touch, which has never been seen before.</p>

<p>She's ordered to rest for the night, because she'll be working rather hard for some new training in the morning.</p>

<p>She asks if she can be told the purpose and Captain Denholm reveals the plan is for Iris to kill King Bayard of Skobia, without going anywhere near him.  She's hopeful Iris will be able to reach into his chest, to crush his heart.</p>

<p>Iris heads home, as ordered, but about halfway there, she begins to cry, totally unable to stop, because they're finally going to force her to kill, against her vows.</p>

<h2>Chapter 15: Amelia Assembles</h2>

<p>Amelia sneaks out of her bedroom using a knotted rope, meeting her chief assistant, Dawkin, on the ground.  Amelia is totally oblivious of the fact, but Dawkin is in love with her.</p>

<p>He tells her Hobard is busy on the other side of the house, dealing with a group of drunks that were anonymously given free beer, a key to the front gate and an invitation to party there.</p>

<p>As it turns out, Amelia has been trying to give Hobard and the house servants the slip for more than a week, because they've gotten really problematic, continually following her around.</p>

<p>When her basic training was complete, Amelia was sent home to work as a military contractor against her will, with the task of producing a horseless, armored war wagon.</p>

<p>Lately, however, Amelia has come to think of the house staff as her enemies, because she doesn't pay them and even if she fires them, they're immediately replaced, all on top of the fact they're effectively spying on nearly every move she makes.</p>

<p>The two of them sneak off to a corner of the property where Amelia had a granite tower of exceptional height built (probably about 70 meters tall and 11 wide), to serve as her private sanctuary, where she supposedly experiments with magic and therefore everyone is supposed to keep out.</p>

<p>Amelia opens the custom combination lock she built and they step inside.  The interior is obviously mortared almost everywhere, except along two tooth-like lines on either side, where the tower is instead joined with steel plates.</p>

<p>Stairs run upward along the interior, but the center of the large, open space is filled with a slightly smaller tower of gleaming, brushed metal, which is <em>Starwitch</em>.  One side toward the bottom and facing the door has a panel off, revealing an empty cavity, which a wooden ramp gives access to.  Inside the cavity, tracks might allow rolling something inside and a hook on a chain dangles, presumably for lifting.</p>

<p>Amelia and Dawkin spend most of the night working, because Starwitch isn't quite ready to launch.  Amelia decides to bring the other apprentices in to finish the project, because there's very little time left before the next demonstration of a prototype war wagon.</p>

<p>Dawkin is sent off with the plans for Starwitch in hand, so the others can study them, before laying hands on the vehicle.</p>

<p>Amelia heads back to her room in the predawn light and hides the rope under the floorboards.  She turns in, hoping to get a couple hours of sleep, but she's woken an hour later.</p>

<p>Apparently, there was a big ruckus in the night (drunks with lots of free beer), but the sheriff is convinced the sisters were being targeted.</p>

<p>Amelia dresses for the day and sends the man off with no extra information, while suppressing laughter.</p>

<p>Iris can read her far better than the servants and questions her in the hall as they head to the dining room.  Amelia reassures her sister that it was just a distraction.</p>

<p>Iris asks to have a private word with Amelia and informs her that Marta wants the same, additionally telling Amelia their sister will be back that afternoon.</p>

<p>Amelia agrees to speak with them both and that's the end of the conversation, though she can tell Iris is extremely upset.</p>

<h2>Chapter 16: Starwitch</h2>

<p>The sisters head to Amelia's tower for their family meeting.  Hobard tries to follow them, but Amelia orders him to leave them alone, going so far as to say he hovers too much.</p>

<p>Their butler looks mildly offended, but obeys, because if he defies their orders, it will give away the fact he's been spying on them, all along.</p>

<p>The sisters enter the tower, then bar the door.</p>

<p>Iris gets things going by asking what <em>Starwitch</em> is.</p>

<p>Amelia names the rocket and explains it's both their method of escape from Dugaria and possibly, their new home.</p>

<p>Marta asks when it will be ready and explains that she plans to immolate herself rather than burning another target for the army.</p>

<p>Her sisters are stunned by her words for a time and Iris goes next, saying she's being trained to kill remote targets with magic, because she has a unique talent for remote-touch, which is an extension of remote-viewing magic.  Her intent is to kill Captain Denholm, then the old general witch if they ever order her to harm someone with magic.  Needless to say, that's not likely to end well and Iris is unlikely to win the fight.</p>

<p>Amelia apologizes for how long her plan has taken and the things her sisters have been forced to endure.  She tells them <em>Starwitch</em> will be ready after one more all-nighter, at least with all her apprentices helping.</p>

<p>However, she'll need a distraction.  Marta decides she'll get drunk and trash the house, a mess no butler or maid could resist dealing with.  This also has the advantage of being somewhat expected, because Marta has been obviously depressed for a long time.</p>

<p>They discuss Hobard and Amelia is told by Iris that he's military, a fact she figured out ages ago, as are the other house servants.  In essence, they've been in a gilded cage all along.</p>

<p>This leads to a discussion of how dense Amelia can be, considering how intelligent she is, and her sisters tease her a bit about Dawkin being in love with her, though she doesn't quite grasp their meaning, because they don't spell it out; they want to see what happens without too much interference.</p>

<p>However, Marta does suggest Amelia look at Dawkin with the eyes of a woman, rather than those of an engineer or witch.</p>

<p>They begin discussing the escape plan and Amelia begins with a tour of <em>Starwitch</em>.</p>

<p>After a scene break, they're in the last of the living spaces, near the bottom of the rocket, where Marta asks why what's obviously supposed to be the floor is currently serving as a wall.</p>

<p>Amelia gives a poor explanation and says they'll have to make their own gravity, in flight. The short version is that the rocket is pointing straight up, just for launch.</p>

<p>Iris interrupts by demanding, "What is this thing?  I can sense incredible magic pouring from it!"</p>

<p>Iris points at a device set into the middle of the wall that currently serves as the floor.  It's made of gleaming metal, with six long rods linking thirty metal plates together.  Each of the plates is crammed full of runes and yes, the whole thing radiates incredible magic.</p>

<p>Amelia begins explaining the "spell-core", as she calls it, trying to leap into a technobabble-filled explanation, though her sisters get her to explain more simply.  It's a runic enchantment designed to cast arbitrary spells based on the imagination of a human that touches the top plate, which has a magic circle etched into it.</p>

<p>The whole thing is made of five pounds of a rare, magic metal called mythril, which continually draws magic into itself from its surroundings. storing it away for future use.  Effectively, the spell-core is a magic battery that will allow even Amelia to cast powerful spells, if needed.</p>

<p>Her sisters are concerned by the very idea and Amelia further explains that she made it to only work for the Blackwell sisters, which reassures them.</p>

<p>With that out of the way, Marta points out a wheel of cheese and some milk sitting in the corner, which appears to have been nibbled by rats.  Amelia quickly kneels beside it and removes the note her sisters hadn't noticed yet, which had been on top of the cheese.</p>

<p>The note reads as:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>"This milk and cheese is an offering to any Brownies that would like a home.  Feel free to eat and drink as much as you like.  I'll get more cheese when it runs out, but won't be able to get you more milk."</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Amelia puts her finger to her lips, calling for silence.  She finds a tiny hand print in the cheese, where a Brownie braced themselves against it, to tear a chunk off.  Amelia does some math based on the size and concludes Brownies are no more than three inches tall.</p>

<p>She silently shows her sisters the hand print and they smile, because they were all aware their home in Daleshade had at least one Brownie, which their mother always fed dairy products to, though no one ever saw it/them.  As a result, their shoes were always in good repair, every morning, regardless of the state they were in at bedtime.</p>

<p>Iris and Marta openly mock Amelia for her strange habit of feeding "rats".  From this point on, when the sisters talk about rats, they'll be talking about the Brownie(s) in code, to avoid offending them, because Brownies won't stay if they're openly talked about.</p>

<p>The sisters begin the long climb back up and out.</p>

<h2>Chapter 17: Final Touches</h2>

<p>Marta spends the night drinking all the wine she can get her hands on, while kept sober by an enchanted necklace Amelia made for her, which features amethysts.</p>

<p>The necklace magically keeps her sober, but also makes her increasingly clumsy, the more she drinks, allowing her to play the part well, without forgetting her job.</p>

<p>She's been smashing furniture, due to her natural strength and the clumsiness, while Hobard has stood ready to refill her glass, though he keeps trying to sneak out of the room.</p>

<p>In the end, Marta demands that he dance with her and he reluctantly joins her atop a table.  Marta whirls him around at high speed, intentionally making herself sick.</p>

<p>As she starts to cough, Marta holds him very tight and vomits down his backside, ruining his uniform and filling his shoes!  She lets him go, stumbles, then falls backwards, which breaks the legs off the table!</p>

<p>Hobard falls into the vomit puddle, then rises, ineffectually wiping himself off.</p>

<p>Marta rises, claiming she feels better, then shouts for more wine!</p>

<p>Before he storms off, Hobard shouts, "I don't care what the military does to me, no one should have to endure this kind of abuse!  <em>I quit!</em>"</p>

<p>Marta is extremely amused that the man broke his cover as she grabs the bottle of wine and heads for a new room, because the one she's in has become a little too dangerous for bare feet.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Amelia and her apprentices are hard at work putting final touches on <em>Starwitch</em>, while they fill the rocket's various water tanks.</p>

<p>As Amelia works in the witchpit to mount the scrying crystals used for viewing outside the rocket, Dawkin reports to her that the tanks will be full in a matter of minutes.</p>

<p>Amelia steps beside him and takes a moment to follow Marta's advice, looking at the man as a woman.</p>

<p>She has a strong desire she doesn't understand, to get closer to him, and as she leans toward him, he closes his eyes and slightly puckers his lips.  Amelia follows suit and leans even closer, curious to learn what her unexplored feelings mean...</p>

<p>The moment is ruined by one of Amelia's female apprentices climbing the ladder, to tell her the water tanks are full.</p>

<p>With the moment ruined, they get back to work.</p>

<p>After a scene break, Amelia gets back to her bedroom and prepares for bed, in the hopes of getting an hour of sleep, despite the fact dawn is happening outside.  Unfortunately, her hopes are dashed by a knock on the door.</p>

<p>The Head of Housekeeping informs her that Hobard quit in the night, along with most of the night staff, due to Hurricane Marta's behavior.  Amelia is occupied dealing with the consequences, until Iris takes over for her, because Amelia has a busy day of work ahead.</p>

<p>Amelia goes to her workshop, where her apprentices work to unpack the crate of tires that just arrived and the war wagon is described.</p>

<p>It's effectively a four-seat car with armored plating that's angled to maximize thickness against projectiles from the front and rear.  Currently, it lacks side armor, because the tires still need mounting and the plates are intended to protect the wheel wells.</p>

<p>It has four "spring-gonnes", which are basically guns that used springs to launch round stone or metal bullets.  Three fire bullets weighing just ounces, while the big one mounted on the roof uses one pound projectiles.  All are cocked by the vehicle's steam engine and they're semi-automatic.</p>

<p>Each seat has a weapon, with the driver's being fixed to face forward, while two face forward and back, able to turn up to 45 degrees to either side.  The big one, however, uses a periscope with a trigger for aiming and firing.  It faces forward, but is able to turn ninety degrees to either side.</p>

<p>Amelia dons some gloves and gets to work.</p>

<h2>Chapter 18: The Demonstration</h2>

<p>Incidentally, in writing this chapter, I decided that Captain Denholm needed to be a Lieutenant Colonel, so she could out-rank Captain Krauss, which required me to edit several previous chapters.</p>

<p>Amelia is unable to sleep, due to nervousness/excitement about the coming day and rises early.  She wastes a little time around the house, checking into preparations for the lunch party the sisters are supposed to host, even though Amelia has no intention of sticking around that long.</p>

<p>Eventually, she heads out to the workshop, where most of her apprentices are finally taking a break, after spending all night putting final touches on the war wagon, because this one isn't destined to explode and it needs to work right on the first try.</p>

<p>Dawkin, on the other hand, is buffing the wagon's armor, to make it shine.</p>

<p>Amelia has another quiet moment with Dawkin and very nearly kisses him, but the same young, female apprentice as last time interrupts.</p>

<p>Amelia thanks them all for her work and asks if they've made the preparations she asked of them.</p>

<p>Dawkin reports that all the plans for Amelia's inventions are secure in the carriage she gave him, which is the same wagon that Amelia's father turned into a mobile house, though Amelia has since made it horseless.</p>

<p>The female apprentice reports that Amelia's old portable workshop has a few of their families crammed into it, along with all the steam engines from the workshop.  They're ready to go.</p>

<p>Another reports they're ready to drive the tractor away, which has been hitched to a large wagon, full of the rest of their families.  He says his sister has the backup copies of Amelia's plans.</p>

<p>Amelia orders them to get on the road.  The intent is for them to get themselves to Skobia, where they'll meet up and offer to build Amelia's war wagon for the other side, because nothing about the war has been just (Dugaria attacked Skobia for resources, then lied about it, to justify using conscripted witches offensively).</p>

<p>Once more, Amelia and Dawkin have a quiet little moment, in which they nearly kiss, but this time, Marta is the one to interrupt, because Colonel Denholm is getting impatient, having sent a messenger.</p>

<p>In the next scene, Dawkin is on a horse, which is hitched to the war wagon.  It can move under its own power, but it's supposed to be publicly tested in front of the top brass.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the Blackwell sisters are inside, talking.</p>

<p>They first discuss the fact that Captain Krauss will be at the demonstration and Iris reacts with naked terror, claiming the woman is a blood witch.</p>

<p>As it turns out, witches with a talent for manipulating blood are the reason witches are feared and reviled, because a blood witch's powers react to their emotions, usually in a violent, explosive manner.  This normally leads a young girl just coming into her magic powers to accidentally kill people, followed by the realization they're to blame.</p>

<p>Most turn their powers inward at that point, due to the emotion of such a thought and tend to self-destruct, but a very few survive.  The rarest of them become healers, but the rest tend to become serial killers.</p>

<p>Krauss just happened to be in a country that's willing to make use of a deranged whack-job whose only talent is murder, or she would have been hunted down and burned at the stake, most likely by other witches.  Aside from that awfulness, Krauss is also fond of fire and probably a pyromaniac.</p>

<p>The fact that should terrify everyone, however, is that Denholm keeps the woman on a short leash, which indicates she's even more powerful, likely capable of killing Krauss with ease.</p>

<p>In the end, Iris decides she'll try to hold off Krauss, while the plan has always been for Marta to hold off Denholm.  Amelia takes the wheel (Iris was originally supposed to drive).</p>

<p>Iris requests, "Remind me why we didn't just launch in the night?  This is starting to sound like a bad plan."</p>

<p>Amelia reminds them that the apprentices have to get to Skobia and the longer the delay, the further away they'll get, quite possibly ahead of rumor.  She also says their Mother would never approve of the way they've probably made things worse, so they have to at least try to help Skobia.</p>

<p>They arrive at the field set aside for the test, which is next to Fort Stand.  Folding chairs are occupied by some rather senior military personnel, including Captain Krauss, Lieutenant Colonel Denholm and the old General that's been training Iris to kill with remote-touch.</p>

<p>While Dawkin removes the hitching mechanism linking the front axle to the horse, Amelia exits the vehicle and salutes her superior officers.  Denholm rises and this scene happens:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>The Lieutenant Colonel returned the salute and gave Amelia an icy glare as she spoke loud enough for the crowd to hear, "This is your last chance, Private Blackwell.  You've been given rather more latitude than I'm comfortable with, due to the potential of the weapon you've promised His Highness, but the King's patience is growing thin." She looked over Amelia's shoulder, to the wagon, "Are you quite certain you need your sisters for this demonstration?  I'm almost certain they're not actually required."</p>

<p>"You weren't here for the previous two tests!" Amelia protested, "Iris is always calm under pressure and quick enough to pull me out if I freeze, and Marta is powerful enough to control the blast if the engine becomes unstable!  I need them both, or I could die!"</p>

<p>"Very well," Denholm nodded, apparently accepting the lies, "but one more catastrophic failure and your new home will feature chains and bars, at the very deepest portion of the King's most vile dungeon."</p>

<p>"I've done my best to please the King," Amelia bowed her head, "but compact steam engines can be quite volatile and difficult to stabilize.  After recent research, however, I think I know what's been going wrong and this one will do…better…" Amelia trailed off in the face of the intense glare the taller woman gave her.</p>

<p>"So you say," Denholm leaned until she towered over Amelia, forcing the small woman to look straight up as Denholm hissed so quietly no one but them might hear the rest of her words, "<em>but I don't believe you</em>.  You think you're always the smartest woman in the room, you <em>smug</em>, little-" Denholm sharply cursed in Amelia's face, spittle landing on her cheeks, "but I'm on to you and the King agrees you've rope enough to hang yourself with, so if you'd like to make any final adjustments, to assure this prototype works, now's the time.  Keep in mind that if this test fails, I'm not going to let you live." Her eyes glowed, bathing Amelia's face in red light, before she went on, "I'll get an earful from His Majesty over it, but ultimately, I can argue I acted in his best interest, because you're definitely not."</p>

<p>Amelia gulped and quietly nodded as she slowly backed away, though their eyes remained locked.  Before Amelia finally dared to look away, Denholm gave her a sick smile that was full of menace and anticipation very like that of a hunter, just before a good kill.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Dawkin drags her attention away from the scary Colonel by asking if she needs anything else.</p>

<p>Feeling close to the edge, emotionally speaking, Amelia grabs Dawkin and kisses him, because it's her last chance, leading to a pair of paragraphs that speak for themselves:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>It was a moment that was both short and sweet, but which also seemed to stretch into a subjective eternity, because it was charged with magic beyond that of anything Amelia had ever experienced, making actual magic feel like a cheap stage magician's trick by comparison, while the kiss she shared with Dawkin felt like the genuine article.</p>

<p>When the kiss ended, Dawkin gave Amelia a huge smile and planted a kiss of his own on her lips, which went on far longer than the first, leaving Amelia feeling absolutely giddy with delight, as if her blood had lost all its weight and become lighter than air, threatening to lift her into the sky.  In short, it was even more magical than the first.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>In the wagon, her sisters are happy Amelia finally figured it out, but sad they can't take Dawkin with them.</p>

<p>Denholm and Krauss, on the other hand, are not amused and also somewhat annoyed, but the witch General seated beside them tells them to lighten up, because if things go wrong with the demonstration, then Amelia will never see the man again and they should give her a little slack, since the King wants her jailed in that case.</p>

<p>Dawkin and Amelia both say, "I love you" and Dawkin rides the horse away.  As soon as he's around the wall, he urges it into a gallop, because he needs to put as much distance between himself and Rimestar as he can.</p>

<p>Amelia gets into the wagon, in tears over the loss of what she only just realized she had.  The sisters discuss the possibility of taking Dawkin with them, but Amelia defeats their arguments with logic she hates: the other apprentices aren't as skilled and they need him to rebuild the war wagon on a reasonable time scale, the only way Skobia might hold their own in the war.</p>

<p>Amelia wipes away her tears and starts the engine.  The wagon runs flawlessly and they demonstrate the smaller weapons on some defenseless wood cutouts of Skobian soldiers.  The big spring-gonne is tested on a small brick wall, which it obliterates.  They make a victory lap around the field at a slow pace, then go round the corner of the fort instead of stopping, then accelerate away!</p>

<p>Seeing them flee, Denholm and Krauss use broomsticks to fly after them and the two decide to kill the Blackwell sisters as traitors, because they're stealing the King's property (the war wagon).  They dive for an attack run!</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_writing.html'>writing</a>, <a href='tag_work-in-progress.html'>work-in-progress</a>, <a href='tag_starwitch.html'>starwitch</a></p>

<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://owentyme.us/blog/work-in-progress-21-starwitch-4.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/blog/./work-in-progress-21-starwitch-4.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Owen Tyme</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 11:57:09 -0600</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Available for Pre-Order: The Inverted Glass
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>The Ebook of the fifth and final volume of <a href="../books/wizards-scion/index.html">The Wizard's Scion</a> is now available for pre-order and will be released on December 13.  Sadly, it took far longer than I originally planned for, but better late than never, I suppose.</p>

<p>In the bad news column, I'm now lacking the services of a professional artist, though I'm waiting on a reply from another I contacted.  In the neutral column, I made this cover myself, by heavily leaning into metaphors for the plot.  I used public domain vector art and a nice nebula image from the James Webb Space Telescope, if I remember correctly.  Someday, the art may be replaced with something better.  In the good news column, the advantage of this new approach is that you'll be seeing my novels published far faster than in the past.</p>

<p>The wraparound cover for the print edition of <a href="../books/wizards-scion/the-inverted-glass.html">The Inverted Glass</a> is my next side project, which I'll probably be able to finish tomorrow.</p>

<p>The omnibus edition of <a href="../books/wizards-scion/index.html">The Wizard's Scion</a> should also be coming soon, but I have to assemble a set of metaphors that work with the art available to me with my admittedly not-great art creations skills.  I'm primarily a cut and paste artist, but I've got a good eye for both visual metaphors and art in general, so it's just a matter of time before I find something that works.</p>

<p>I hope to get through the majority of my backlog of novels in the next couple of months.  In particular, I'll be starting final editing of the prequel series, <a href="../books/sky-children/index.html">Sky Children</a>, later this week, since I already have the artwork done for the first two books.  The second book will follow shortly after.  The third book will have to wait until later, because it's still badly in need of a total rewrite.</p>

<p>In short, keep your eyes peeled and hang onto your seat, because things are about to significantly speed up.</p>

<p>Without further adieu, I present to you:</p>

<h2>The Inverted Glass</h2>

<blockquote>
  <p><span class="book-cover">
<a href="https://books2read.com/TheInvertedGlass"><img src="../images/Cover-TheInvertedGlass.jpg" alt="" title="" /></a> <br />
<a href="https://books2read.com/TheInvertedGlass"><button class="buy" style="display: inline-block; width: 100%; max-width: 200px;">Buy This Book</button></a>
</span>
The Steel Wizard, Captain Levi Jacobs, is woken in the night by his pregnant wife, with happy news their child is coming, but joy becomes tragedy as she dies in childbirth. Reeling from this loss, he vows to raise their daughter to be a strong hero, just like her mother, but even that fleeting comfort is stolen from the bittersweet moment as the poor infant struggles to breathe and dies in his arms!</p>

<p>Reeling at the loss, he staggers from one defeat to the next, slowly losing everything else he cares about.</p>

<p>Finally, after a particularly traumatic defeat at the hands of a new enemy, followed by a prolonged kidnapping involving the forced administration of narcotics to make him complaint, he lies in the infirmary of his ship, grief-stricken and struggling with addiction withdrawal. Just when he’s at an all-time low, he’s offered a ray of unusual hope, reminded that he once witnessed his future self travel through time.</p>

<p>Armed with this memory, he focuses to unlock the secrets of temporal magic, intent on undoing months of terrible events, only to find it’s not so easy, because he has to fight to gain the approval of the Moirai, better known as the Three Fates and speaking with them is no easy task.</p>

<p>Can Levi change history or will all that he loves remain forever lost in the past?</p>

<div style="clear: both;"></div>
</blockquote>

<p>The cover of the novel has multiple meanings:</p>

<p>First, a certain troll swordswoman is back, in the form of both a summoned ghost and an inadvertently summoned demon, one good, the other evil.  That's what the figures in the hourglass are about.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the good one is deeply concerned about the final destination of her soul, because the necromancer, Cha'da, summoned her away from the afterlife during her personal judgment day, just as her heart was being weighed against a feather.</p>

<p>Second, the protagonist, Levi, has a harrowing time trying to get back everything he's lost, using time travel.  The hourglass also serves as a reference to that.  This last of Levi's adventures reveals how he's judged by the Three Fates, all because he tried to change history without first asking permission.  In the end, he somehow has to balance the scales and justify his actions in order to change history.</p>

<p>Both character go through some very rough times along the way, but I find the ending of this one to be the most emotionally satisfying of the series.</p>

<p>I hope you'll enjoy it as much as I have.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_writing.html'>writing</a>, <a href='tag_publishing.html'>publishing</a>, <a href='tag_the-wizards-scion.html'>the-wizards-scion</a></p>

<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://owentyme.us/blog/available-for-pre-order-the-inverted-glass.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/blog/./available-for-pre-order-the-inverted-glass.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Owen Tyme</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 21:35:58 -0600</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Work In Progress #20: Starwitch #3
</title><description><![CDATA[

<blockquote>
  <p>"Do not test me, ladies.  I am the very best war witch this country has ever produced.  I would find it particularly easy to blow this entire house to splinters, followed by telekinetically dragging the three of you away."</p>

<p>&nbsp; – Captain Scarth Denholm, an excerpt from Starwitch.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="../books/starwitch/index.html">Starwitch</a> is a novel about space-faring witches that I plan to release first as a web series, then for sale in online stores.</p>

<p><a href="https://mastodon.social/@OwenTyme/113483873966306253">You can read short summaries of each day's writing on Mastodon.</a></p>

<p>Here's a list of previous blog entries on this work in progress novel, in order from oldest to newest:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="work-in-progress-18-starwitch-1.html">Starwitch #1</a></li>
<li><a href="work-in-progress-19-starwitch-2.html">Starwitch #2</a></li>
</ul>

<h2>Chapter 8: Parting Ways</h2>

<p>Amelia lies in her bed, aching all over.  She's resting to heal, but her mind is quite busy.  She still has no option for cushioning wheels, but an alternative has occurred to her: an airship.</p>

<p>The only trouble with that is her best bet for lifting an airship into the air is 'metal phlogiston', which is better known in the modern world as hydrogen, but she's concerned about the explosive qualities of the gas.</p>

<p>After a knock at the door, Mrs. Maccle enters.  She expresses her concern for Amelia's health, but when Amelia tells her it's just bruises, her expression doesn't change.</p>

<p>Mrs. Maccle explains that Amelia has been accused of witchcraft.  The older woman also reveals that she's a witch, though even weaker than Amelia.  This admission earns the older woman even greater trust from Amelia.  As it turns out, the mayor's wife has been subtly guiding the locals toward greater tolerant, but this backfired with Amelia, because it was too much, too soon.</p>

<p>Mrs. Maccle says she'll delay things as much as she can and her husband will investigate the accusation, but ultimately find Amelia and her sisters innocent, though they both know that won't be enough.  However, it will be plenty of time for the Blackwell family to pack up and leave, before a mob can take action.</p>

<p>Mrs. Maccle tells Amelia of a far off country to the west, beyond the ominously named mountain range known as 'The Burning Slopes', which is presumably volcanically active.</p>

<p>Dugaria, as the nation is named, is (in)famous for publicly accepting witches, though she knows nothing more about it.  The journey will take months if they cross the volcanic range or as much as a year, if they go around.</p>

<p>Mrs. Maccle wishes there was more she could do for them and Amelia smiles, because she's gotten an idea, suggesting the mayor's wife can help them some more by buying a bit more time.</p>

<p>In the next scene, Marta is on the roof of Amelia's warehouse/workshop, surreptitiously watching a mob that's gathered by the front door to protest the presence of an accused witch.</p>

<p>Marta heads back inside after reading their signs and hearing them shout about burning witches.  She joins Amelia, Iris, their Father and Mrs. Maccle in working on a crude airship that's little more than a big, flat platform with a railing and a building in the middle, though there's enough room for the family's vehicles at either end.</p>

<p>The whole thing is on wheels and has a steam engine that can drive it on the ground or run a pair of propellors.</p>

<p>They finish structurally reinforcing it and Amelia asks Mrs. Maccle to open the back doors.</p>

<p>The ship is rolled outside and Iris ties it off to prepared stakes, while Amelia gets the process of filling the gas bag started.  Marta and their father prepare to catch the bag as it unfolds, to avoid punctures, since they've only got one shot at this.</p>

<p>Mrs. Maccle heads off to join her husband, the sheriff and eight of his largest men on the other side of the building.</p>

<p>To serve as a distraction, the sheriff approaches the mob and demands to see their permit for the public gathering.  The conversation with the leader of the mob (a lawyer, by the way) implies they don't have one and as they go back and forth about the current situation, people from the mob begin sneaking away.</p>

<p>They argue the merits of whether Amelia is a witch or not, because "Oh my, she flew!"  The mayor tosses a paper airplane (they would probably call it a paper bird) through the air and makes a rather logical argument that what Amelia did was a scaled up version of the same.  He even insists there was no magic, just science.</p>

<p>There's more arguing as, in the background, the gas bag inflates and Amelia does some work on the control fins attached to it, though the mob is fortunately to distracted to notice.</p>

<p>Again, the matter of the permit is raised by the sheriff, including a threat to arrest everyone.  More of the crowd peels off, while the sheriff's men start circling the crowd.</p>

<p>The leader of the mob accuses the mayor and the sheriff of a conspiracy to help a witch (amusingly, this is quite true), but he makes the mistake of jabbing the sheriff with a finger.</p>

<p>She sheriff turns that finger into a serious point of pain and arrests the man for a variety of charges: assaulting an officer of the watch, disturbing the peace, incitement to riot and conspiracy to murder an innocent woman, a circumvention of justice.</p>

<p>The sheriff's men arrest what little remains of the mob.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the airship takes to the air, flying west.  The mayor asks his wife if she knows where they're headed.  She tells him they're going to Dugaria, where they hope they'll be accepted, and he groans.</p>

<p>Mrs. Maccle loses some confidence as she asks, "Witches are accepted in Dugaria, aren't they?"</p>

<p>Her husband's response is chilling: "Only because the government uses them as weapons!"</p>

<p>Sadly, Mrs. Maccle hadn't heard that part of the rumors.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, it's far too late to warn the Blackwell family.</p>

<h2>Chapter 9: Burning Slopes</h2>

<p>Amelia's airship, <em>Airwitch</em>, has been in the air for about two and a half days and with Amelia at the helm at dawn, she finally spots The Burning Slopes, which live up to their name.</p>

<p>The mountain range is a line of volcanoes, which are currently not violently erupting, though lava pours down the sides of some.  I think of this similar to the volcanoes of Hawaii, which have been mildly active for generations.</p>

<p>Amelia is concerned about the danger of going over them in an airship that's lifted by explosive hydrogen gas, though the alternative of going around will take at least a month, if not longer, because they'll have to fight against the west-blowing prevailing wind they've been riding so far, if they turn.</p>

<p>They have a family meeting in which Amelia explains her concerns and calls for a vote.  She votes to go around the mountains.</p>

<p>Their father abstains from voting, to avoid a potential tie.  As a male born to a family of witches, Tim is quite used to letting the women in his life take charge.</p>

<p>Marta votes to go over, because their map shows no civilization anywhere nearby (too many volcanoes, which can be far more active on the moon of a gas giant, compared to Earth) and they only have a month's rations.</p>

<p>Iris agrees, because while they could theoretically forage for food, their mother trained them in a totally different kind of terrain than they've been flying over.</p>

<p>Amelia doesn't like the decision, but accepts it and pushes the engine to maximum power, because she wants to get over the volcanoes as fast as possible, even at the cost of wasting water.  She aims them between a pair of volcanoes that seem less active than the others, to maximize safety.</p>

<p>As <em>Airwitch</em> passes between a pair of volcanoes, one of them begins to erupt, but it's too late for Amelia to turn aside, lest she crash the airship into one of them!</p>

<p>Lava pours down the side and pools in the valley beneath <em>Airwitch</em>, producing a powerful updraft that carries them to a dangerous altitude that threatens to make the gas bag brittle enough to burst, because it's only cotton fabric coated and sealed with rubber.</p>

<p>Iris takes the helm, while Marta starts climbing a knotted rope to reach the top of the gas bag, where an emergency valve can be used to release some of the hydrogen, which would reduce their buoyancy.  Amelia heads inside, in preparation to refill the gas bag, once they're out of danger.</p>

<p>As it turns out, their father, Tim, hasn't been taking a turn at the helm, because he's scared of all the controls, too nervous to ever touch them.  Amelia has been taking his turns, despite the fact she has so much work to do on the ship.</p>

<p>Due to this fact, the system designed to re-compress the hydrogen for later reuse isn't done, forcing this crazy emergency procedure.  Thus, he feels responsible.</p>

<p>Tim punches Marta, leaving her lying on the deck with a dislocated jaw (Tim doesn't know his own strength and that was definitely unintended).  He climbs in her place and releases some of the hydrogen, while Iris shouts to direct him, though she thinks she's talking to Marta.  They lose most of their altitude, until they're just hundreds of feet above the treetops of a jungle.</p>

<p>During his climb back down, Iris and Amelia begin refilling the gas bag and the sudden change in acceleration causes Tim loses his grip on the rope!  As he falls to his death, he says a final prayer to the Gods for the safety of his daughters, feeling content his final act in life was saving their lives.</p>

<p>Amelia emerges from the interior, finding Marta lying on the deck, unable to speak. Amelia takes the place of Iris at the helm and Iris treats Marta's injury with a mixture of doctoring and a healing potion.  Naturally, putting Marta's jaw back in place produces a scream of agony.</p>

<p>Marta explains what happened and Amelia despairs, because she knows the fall wasn't survivable.</p>

<p>Iris runs to the back of the ship and looks the way they came, hoping to see her father, desperate for a chance to rescue him, but the volcano's eruption has gotten worse and the jungle is aflame.  It would not be safe to go back, forcing them to leave their father behind.</p>

<p>Iris collapses and sobs.  Marta scoops Iris up in her arms (remember, she's a big woman, built like a lumberjack) and carries her to the front of <em>Airwitch</em>, where the sisters mourn together.</p>

<h2>Chapter 10: The Welcome Village</h2>

<p>After a day's travel and almost 700 miles crossed, the sisters come to a small village and tether <em>Airwitch</em> to some trees, via a grappling hook.</p>

<p>The villagers stare up as Amelia looks down and one of them asks, "Are you a witch?"</p>

<p>She initially says "No, I'm an engineer!", but the man's wife says they like witches and when Amelia's sisters join her at the railing, they vote to be honest and Amelia admits they're witches.</p>

<p>The villagers were initially nervous about the airship, but the moment Amelia admits she's a witch, they go back to their business, as if women flying around in airships was normal.</p>

<p>They're invited to a lunch of fish and something akin to spinach in the tiny hovel that serves as the couple's home.  The man is named Davit and he's the village administrator.  He turns out to be very friendly and eager to convince the sisters to settle in the village, because they've been looking for a witch for years.</p>

<p>He shows them the house the villagers have built for their future witch and it turns out to be a rather wonderful home, a small mansion, in fact.  His people have been living as paupers, so they can afford to make some lucky witch exceptionally comfortable.</p>

<p>He claims the "humble home" is the best they can do, but it's larger than the one the sisters grew up in!</p>

<p>Amelia questions him about this and he claims the sisters are likely to find far better living arrangements in a larger city.</p>

<p>They ask why Davit's people would put themselves out for a witch like this and he explains:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>"When a witch is needed, but there isn't one available, people suffer.  Witches heal and brew potions.  They help others, because that’s what witches do." Davit bowed his head, "With a witch in the village, we would prosper and know great peace.  Witches are a blessing from the Gods."</p>
</blockquote>

<p>After a few days to relax and mourn the loss of their father, Amelia and her sisters move on, intent on traveling Dugaria to find a good place to settle down (the village is nice, but too poor for their liking).</p>

<p>Davit gives them a map of the nation to help them on their way.</p>

<h2>Chapter 11: A New Home</h2>

<p>Six months later, Amelia wakes and walks the halls of the mansion she bought in Rimestar, the capitol of Dugaria.  Servants greet her in the halls and she has breakfast with her sisters, while waited on by their butler.</p>

<p>Amelia had no need for such a large house, but bought it for the 40 aches of fenced yard and the location, outside the city, though still within easy reach.</p>

<p>She also had no need for servants, but their salaries (aside from the gardeners) are paid for by the city, as an added incentive for witches to settle in the city.</p>

<p>Her sisters have been working in a local hospital, as doctors/healers.  There was a big accident and tending to the injured kept them up all night, so once they're done eating, they head off to bed, for some long-overdue sleep.</p>

<p>Amelia heads out to her workshop, which is on the land she bought.  She checks over the construction work taking place at one end.  The place is ready to be used, but not finished, since Amelia wants enough room to work on rockets intended to get her to orbit.</p>

<p>She briefly checks on her apprentices, who work on small devices intended for sale in the local market, then heads for the corner dedicated to her current project: <em>Blackbird II</em>.  The aircraft is nearly finished and the custom tires arrived the night before.</p>

<p>Vulcanized rubber is the big innovation of Dugaria, something Amelia has been studying, though she's not quite up to the level of the local craftsman that made the tires for her plane.</p>

<p>She cracks open the crate holding the tires and checks them over, quite pleased.  She begins working mount them.</p>

<p>Amelia is happy and content to be accepted and beloved by the locals.  She's also happy to have so many amazing resources available to her.  She reflects on the fact her sisters are also doing well, both of whom have been getting attention from men.</p>

<p>Amelia has also been catching the eye of hopeful young men, but she's always too lost in thought to notice.</p>

<p>However, despite how much Amelia loves Dugaria, she's been cautious about her greatest secrets, including runic enchantments, though that's is mostly a matter of her life-long habit of hiding her magic.</p>

<p>Amelia's work is interrupted by Hobard, the chief butler, who informs her that she and her sisters have guests that insisted on seeing all three of them.</p>

<h2>Chapter 12: Assignments</h2>

<p>Amelia goes with Hobard and is led to the sitting room.</p>

<p>One of the couches is occupied by a woman in a dark green army uniform and a matching pointed hat, marking her as both a soldier and a witch.  Her collar bears a captain's insignia, with the addition of a little, pointed hat, because a witch always has greater authority than any non-witch of the same rank.</p>

<p>Seated opposite the woman are Iris and Marta, who were woken for the meeting.  Amelia sits between them.</p>

<p>The military witch introduces herself as Captain Scarth Denholm.  She goes on to tell them Dugaria is now at war.  By law and declaration of the King, all citizen witches have been conscripted into the army.</p>

<p>Iris objects, saying they've taken a vow of non-violence.</p>

<p>Amelia claims they never agreed to that and the Captain hands her a copy of the constitution of Dugaria.  Amelaia reads and learns that they automatically became citizens when they became home/land owners.  This is the reason Dugaria gives free homes and land to witches.  Amelia reads further, learning the King does have the right to conscript witches, whenever needed for the protection of Dugaria.</p>

<p>Marta demands to know what happens if they refuse, leading to a scene that speaks for itself:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>The military woman leaned forward and her hat produced a looming shadow over her face as her eyes glowed like those of a demon, a deep, red shade, like glowing blood, "<em>Do not</em> test me, ladies." Her icy tone was heavy with the promise of dangerous icebergs that could sink a ship, "I am the very best war witch this country has <em>ever</em> produced.  I would find it particularly easy to blow this entire house to splinters, followed by telekinetically dragging the three of you away." Her eyes stopped glowing and she leaned back in the couch, "However, that would be tedious," she glanced around herself, eyeing the fine furniture and the many paintings on the walls, "and an insult to the many witches that lived in this house before the three of you.</p>

<p>"Oh, and even if you think you might be able to overpower me with your combined magic, keep this little tidbit in mind: outside, the other six witches of my coven stand ready to support me and each of them is at least two-thirds as powerful as I am, all of them military trained for battle.  No little hedge witch could possibly win such a fight, and three would fare no better."</p>

<p>Amelia's eyes narrowed with anger, "So we're to be dogs of the military, whether we like it or not?"</p>

<p>The captain sighed, "Ladies, this isn't much different from the men of this country, many of whom are having a similar conversation, right now, though that's determined by random chance.  To make up for the fact that all witches are being conscripted, the King is offering commensurate rewards.  The pay is excellent and you'll have whatever materials you desire for personal magical research.  Just about anything can be within reach for a military witch.  We have but to ask, especially since we're going to war."</p>

<p>"But we have to be the King's magical assassins, right?" Iris glared, her voice filling with contempt.</p>

<p>"If that's where your talents lie." Captain Denholm stood and went on, "So, ladies, what will it be?  Do you come quietly, or do we brawl?" Again, her eyes glowed and she smiled, revealing a wild expression that hinted the woman was secretly hoping for a fight.</p>

<p>Waves of murderous intent carried by magic charged the air and the men behind her took a couple steps back.</p>

<p>Marta stood and hung her head, "It would seem we have no choice."</p>

<p>"What about our vow of non-violence?" Iris also stood, but remained slightly defiant.</p>

<p>Denholm shrugged, "Another casualty of war, I suppose, but you'll serve, either way.  Go quietly and you won’t have to wear chains."</p>
</blockquote>

<p>In the end, the sisters go quietly, because it's obvious they're no match for Captain Denholm.  She leads them to Fort Stand, a military post just outside the city, where their magical talents will be tested and they'll receive their assignments.</p>

<p>While the sisters are busy being tested, Captain Denholm returns to their property and Hobard is revealed to be a secret military spy, as are the rest of the house servants.</p>

<p>Hobard leads her to Amelia's airship, inside the workshop, and it's taken away, for study and to ensure the main characters don't fly away.  Little does Denholm know, the steam engines have all been removed to power the machines of the workshop (Denholm doesn't even know what a steam engine is) and the canisters of hydrogen have been emptied for the sake of safety, making it totally useless.</p>

<p>The sisters finish testing totally soaked in sweat, because they were pushed to their absolute limits.  They're lined up along with six other witches, to hear the results and receive assignments.</p>

<p>Marta's greatest magical talents lie in Fire and Earth magic.  Her assignment is to become a front-line Artillery Witch.</p>

<p>Iris has talents for long-range Sensory and Communication magic.  Her assignment can't be spoken publicly, implying she'll be doing something secretive, perhaps intelligence work.  The other witches glare at Iris with envy, because whatever her assignment will be, they think it's going to be a cushy one.</p>

<p>Amelia is declared to basically have no particular talent for magic and lacks power, a fact she already knew.</p>

<p>Denholm doesn't quite know what to do with her and asks, "What talents besides magic do you possess?"</p>

<p>Amelia answers honestly, by saying she's an engineer, a builder of machines, particularly vehicles, like her airship.</p>

<p>Denholm is shocked by this and briefly loses her composure.</p>

<p>They discuss her airship and Amelia points out the fact she used science to make it fly, rather than magic.</p>

<p>The Captain is quiet for a time, before she assigns Amelia to the basic physical training every War Witch receives, saying she'll have to discuss Amelia's final assignment with her superiors.</p>

<p>Amelia quietly makes up her mind to escape Dugaria, but since they're in the center of the country and will surely be watched, that will not be easy.  She hopes to distract people with technobabble and accomplish her true goals behind the backs of those watching her.</p>

<h2>Current Progress</h2>

<p><em>Starwitch</em> is about one-quarter finished, with the first three episodes of material in a rough draft state.  So far, I'm averaging about one episode a week.  I've written about 33,000 words, so far.</p>

<p>This piece will probably end up at 120,000 words or less.  Early chapters were heavy with descriptive detail and I was forced to write longer chapters (3,000+ words), due to how intricate everything Amelia builds is, but now that things are starting to move along with more action and slightly less science/engineering, the chapters are slimming down to my more typical average (2,000-2,500 words).</p>

<h2>Future Plans</h2>

<p>Episode four will begin with a five year skip forward, during which the sisters have been working for the army.  My intent with the episode is to produce a lot of character growth for the main characters.</p>

<p>Marta and Iris will get their own chapters dedicated to them, to show how much they've changed and how difficult their circumstances are.</p>

<p>Marta will be shown in the field, using her magic to destroy entire fortifications, while her conscience stings her for harming others with magic.</p>

<p>Iris will be seen using scrying magic (think CIA remote-viewing programs, only far more effective) to get instant results from distant battlefields, so her superiors can make better decisions.  I will probably end that chapter with Iris' superiors using her unit of black-ops witches to assassinate high-ranking officers of the enemy army, with extreme-range magic.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, in her own chapter, Amelia will be seen squirreling away resources for a secret project, while Hobard tries very hard to find out what she's up to.  During the skip forward, she'll have been working as a government contractor, tasked with designing a horseless, armored "war wagon", a project Amelia has been delaying for years, intentionally detonating prototype after prototype, with the explanation that "steam engines are very hard to stabilize, a design flaw I hope to fix, soon."</p>

<p>The last chapter of the episode will bring them back together, because Amelia insists she needs her sisters on hand, claiming Iris is the best driver and Marta's magic is strong enough to control the blast if the prototype explodes.</p>

<p>They'll drive the new war wagon and go on the run across Amelia's land, toward a tower she's built, while Captain Denholm gives chase, via broomstick.  When they arrive, Marta will hold off the other War Witch, while Amelia and Iris blow one whole side off the tower, revealing the hidden shape of <em>Starwitch</em>, while the other half of the tower serves as the rocket's support gantry.</p>

<p>Marta will lose her fight with Denholm, but will have bought just enough time for her sisters to load the war wagon inside the base of the rocket and the three of them will blast off.  Denholm will probably try to follow, but she'll be unable to chase them out of the atmosphere.</p>

<p>After that, all future episodes will take place in space.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_writing.html'>writing</a>, <a href='tag_work-in-progress.html'>work-in-progress</a>, <a href='tag_starwitch.html'>starwitch</a></p>

<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://owentyme.us/blog/work-in-progress-20-starwitch-3.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/blog/./work-in-progress-20-starwitch-3.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Owen Tyme</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 08:08:02 -0600</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Work In Progress #19: Starwitch #2
</title><description><![CDATA[

<blockquote>
  <p>"I declare to all: if any of you ever harms so much as one hair on the heads of my daughters, I <em>will</em> return as a vengeful spirit, with bloody intention to wipe out this entire village, guilty and innocent alike, <em>because evil triumphs when good men do nothing!</em>"</p>

<p>&nbsp; – Erika Blackwell, the mother of Amelia, an Excerpt from Starwitch.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="../books/starwitch/index.html">Starwitch</a> is a novel about space-faring witches that I plan to release first as a web series, then for sale in online stores.</p>

<p><a href="https://mastodon.social/@OwenTyme/113483873966306253">You can read short summaries of each day's writing on Mastodon.</a></p>

<p>Here's a list of previous blog entries on this work in progress novel, in order from oldest to newest:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="work-in-progress-18-starwitch-1.html">Starwitch #1</a></li>
</ul>

<h2>Chapter 3: Steam Without Flame</h2>

<p>Most of this chapter was descriptive details on Amelia's projects, to slowly demonstrate what she can do, despite her primitive surroundings.</p>

<p>Amelia is 14 in this chapter and now has a small shack to work in.  She pays for things by making and selling high-quality steel ingots to the village smith.</p>

<p>She's working on parts for a steam engine that lacks a firebox, a series of metal plates she's chiseling runes into, including the runes for 'metal', 'boil' and 'water'.</p>

<p>She finishes her work, assembles the plates with some rods to form something reminiscent of a heat sink, though with larger gaps between the plate.  She pours some water on it, which boils off as if the metal was hot, though it's cool to the touch.</p>

<p>I imagine the runes to be the written form of the language of magic, which just about anyone can use, though they need the right knowledge to make use of it: only runes marking metal and stone will work, because metal and stone act as mediums in which magic condenses.</p>

<p>Any previously living material, like wood or paper, will fail, because dead things strive to live again and use up the magic in that attempt.  Effectively, this means dead wood is very slightly zombie (maybe about 0.001%).</p>

<p>Marta (Amelia's oldest sister) joins her, curious to see what she's working on and they have a brief discussion of runes covering the above information.  It's stated that Marta's husband died around the time Amelia was four years old.  She's 12 years older than Amelia.  Marta is a rather large woman and built like a lumberjack, but she's not unattractive.</p>

<p>After they're done talking, Amelia puts the enchanted device inside the little engine's steam chamber and seals it.  She fills it with water and the belt wheel on the side spins, demonstrating that it works. Thus, Amelia is capable of making extremely compact steam engines with a level of power that rivals that of a modern gasoline engine.</p>

<p>Marta asks what's next and Amelia says she needs a carriage.  Marta is confused, because they don't even own a horse, but Amelia insists she needs only the carriage.</p>

<p>In the next scene, months have passed and Amelia has heavily modified a carriage into a horseless carriage and her sisters help her mount a heavy, magic-powered steam engine to the frame.</p>

<p>Amelia's Sister, Iris, is described.  She's a little taller than their mother, who's average height.  She's also exceptionally beautiful.  Her personal history is briefly illuminated as part of her description.</p>

<p>She'd been engaged to the mayor's son, but just days after they announced this to the whole village, he was murdered.  It isn't entirely clear how he died, though he was tied to a tree and wolves got him.  It isn't stated whether the wolves killed him or just ate him.</p>

<p>Iris has been very sad for the past three years, due to losing her betrothed.</p>

<p>With the work done, their mother gives them a picnic basket of food and the three of them head off for a test drive, with Iris in the driver's seat.  She turns out to be a crazy speed-demon and smiles for the first time in years.</p>

<p>Unknown to our main characters, the local smith and his son, both named Rolf Mossflaw (senior and junior, to be clear), were sneaking onto their land while they drove off.  The two of them witness the horseless carriage and Rolf senior concludes that it's witchcraft, despite multiple attempts to justify it as non-magical.</p>

<p>Eventually, the lack of smoke from the steam engine's firebox (it doesn't even have one, but he doesn't know that) forces him to accept the idea it's magic.</p>

<p>The smith and his son head back to the village, to "do the right thing" and tell the mayor, even though they don't want to.</p>

<h2>Chapter 4: A Terrible Choice</h2>

<p>Erika, Amelia's mother, is at home, working to prepare ingredients for potions, since healing potions are how the family made their money before Amelia started making steel.</p>

<p>Her husband, Tim, is a woodcutter, but it's a weekend and he's taken a day off to spend time with his wife, though he's fallen asleep in a rocking chair.</p>

<p>There's a heavy knock on the door, far too loud to be a social visit and Erika concludes the mayor is back to accuse her of being a witch, for the sixteenth time, even though it has been more than a decade since he last accused her.</p>

<p>The mayor once witnessed her using magic while he was drunk and has never let the subject go.</p>

<p>Tim wakes and offers to beat the man, but Erika decides another round of intellectual jousting will be enough to take care of the problem, so he sits down again.  In other words, she decides to handle it herself, since the mayor is an idiot and she normally runs mental circles around him.</p>

<p>She opens the door and Mayor Godfrey Rumblecleaver points the accusatory finger, saying, "She's a witch!  I've seen it with my own eyes!  This woman, Erika Blackwell, has had congress with the devil!  I saw her dance in the forest, naked, alongside a demon!"</p>

<p>He has an entire lynch mob with him, including his deputy.  The mayor is, by ignorant and stupid tradition (according to Erika's internal monologue) also sheriff and judge, though he's bound by law to follow certain procedures.</p>

<p>This involves giving the accused witch a chance to refute his claims.</p>

<p>As an avid reader, Amelia has both read and understood the village's entire law book, having committed it to memory, consequently making the mayor look like a fool once already.  She also taught her mother something: the law book says accusations require two or three witnesses.</p>

<p>Erika points this out, so the mayor provides another witness: the village moonshiner and local drunkard, who claims he saw Erika dance naked with a goat-horned demon!</p>

<p>Erika remembers the only occasion she saw him that week, in which he was drunk off his butt and likely hallucinating, so she isn't surprised he imagined her naked and a passing goat as a demon.</p>

<p>She asks the crowd to raise their hands if they believe the man to be a reliable witness when he's drunk, which is basically whenever he's awake.  No one raises a hand.</p>

<p>Likewise, she refutes the mayor's claim, because everyone knows how drunk he was the night in question, which was when Erika was 15.  She's now 42.</p>

<p>The incident took place during a harvest festival and moonshine had been freely available.  The young man that later became the mayor had been drinking heavily, despite the fact he'd never had any alcohol before.</p>

<p>The smith, Rolf, steps up next, reluctantly telling the tale of seeing Erika's daughters drive a bewitched carriage.  They argue for a time and he presents his irrefutable, expert opinion that it could only have been magically-powered.</p>

<p>Erika demands a second witness and Rolf junior confirms the story.</p>

<p>Seeing he's caught Erika in a situation she can't talk her way out of, the mayor offers a pair of awful alternatives: either Erika's daughters burn as witches, or she does in their place, because the law says a parent can pay for the crimes of a child.</p>

<p>He even goes on to call it a good bargain.  Meanwhile, his face is full of sick glee, because he's finally caught the witch he's chased most of his life.  If Erika agrees, then all she has to do is say out loud that she's a witch.</p>

<p>She says, "I'm a witch" so softly, no one but Tim hears and he rushes to attack the mayor, only to get shot in the shoulder with a crossbow bolt from the deputy.</p>

<p>Erika patches him up and he passes out.</p>

<p>Absolutely reveling in her torment, the mayor says he didn't hear her and she needs to speak up.</p>

<p>Erika speaks louder, but he still isn't satisfied, demanding that she speak loud enough for everyone to hear.</p>

<p>Finally, she shouts her true feelings to the world, including how proud she is to be a witch, making a verbal list of all the good things she's done for the villagers, much of it with secret magic.</p>

<p>She finishes by saying magic isn't evil, but the mayor is, having persecuted her over nothing, for decades.</p>

<p>As her hands are bound by the deputy, she considers torching her accusers with magic, but remembers her grandmother's words on the matter, which were basically, "Do no harm with magic."</p>

<p>She follows the vow of pacifism she made to her grandmother, going quietly to the pile of wood and the stake, to be tied to it, while moonshine is dumped all over the wood to make it burn better.</p>

<p>Before she's lit aflame, the mayor whispers to her, "I had to kill my own son, because one of your whore-of-the-devil daughters bewitched him, just like I did with that poor fool that married Marta!  I'm glad I finally get to see you burn for what you took from me!"</p>

<p>Finally seeing the depth of the man's depravity, Erika speaks her final words:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>She spoke at a volume comparable to a megaphone, her voice magically enhanced to ensure all ears present would take notice, "Know this day, Mayor Godfrey Rumblecleaver, that your sins will follow you to your very last day, while the gates of the infernal realm gape open and ready to take your soul!</p>

<p>"I declare to all: if any of you ever harms so much as one hair on the heads of my daughters, I <em>will</em> return as a vengeful spirit, with bloody intention to wipe out this entire village, guilty and innocent alike, <em>because evil triumphs when good men do nothing!</em>" Erika gave Rolf and his son a particularly scathing glare, before she looked once more at the now cowering mayor, to speak so softly only he should have heard her final words, though the magic still took them far and wide, "With my last, dying breath, I curse you to never know peace!"</p>
</blockquote>

<p>All of that was just words to mess with everyone's heads, but who knows, maybe the last words of a witch have power beyond mere magic?</p>

<p>Erika uses magic to light the pyre herself, to take control out of his hands of the mob and steal from the mayor the option to believe he killed her.</p>

<p>Shortly after, her daughters arrive, just as a wagon full of men departs.  Marta is driving, barely managing to stop the carriage before succumbing to a numb and helpless silence, while Amelia sputters.</p>

<p>Iris, on the other hand, rushes to the aid of their mother, using magic to part the flame and loosen the ropes, so she can haul Erika free of the blaze, but it's all for naught, because she's already dead.</p>

<h2>Chapter 5: Salt in the Wound</h2>

<p>While Amelia's family are reeling at the loss of their wife/mother, a few days pass and the town crier shows up with a proclamation from the mayor: all property of the confessed witch is to be forfeit to the village and auctioned to pay for the firewood used.</p>

<p>The auction is scheduled for the next day at dawn, though they will have four full days to actually willingly give up the land or make arguments that they should be allowed to keep it.</p>

<p>Amelia's father produces a stack of old wills from her ancestors and she reads them all, discovering that every one of the Blackwell women for the past few centuries has used the same wording in their last will and testament.</p>

<p>The essence of it is that the home and land were given to a specific individual, but everything else became the collective property of their female progeny.</p>

<p>In essence, they foresaw the issue of being discovered as witches and had a strong legal defense in mind to dodge the seizure of property.  They would have done the same with the land and house, but local law forbids joint ownership of real estate, to prevent family arguments from spilling into court.</p>

<p>Amelia attends the auction and makes an attempt to buy their land back, but the mayor out-bids her, paying double the actual value of the land.  Amelia make herself publicly weep by thinking about her mother, but smiles on her way out of the courthouse, because the auction went just the way she planned.</p>

<p>Over the next few days, wagon loads of salt, alchemical waste and lye arrive at the Blackwell family home and their father directs the work of poisoning the land, to make it worthless to the mayor.  At night, the sisters use magic to summon rains storms, so the contamination will sink into the soil.</p>

<p>Their last day on the land, they pack up their belongings and Iris uses fire magic to burn the house's thatch, followed by Marta employing earth magic to make the mortar and stones of the walls crumble.  Last of all, Amelia jams the pressure relief valves of a small steam engine and activates it inside her workshop, before they all run away to avoid the explosion.</p>

<p>Effectively, there's nothing of value left behind.  They stay in a tent that night, but no one can sleep and their father goes out.</p>

<p>He visits the village smith and brow-beats the man into joining him.  They gather others that hate the mayor.</p>

<p>Together, the group throws a blanket over the mayor's head and haul him out of his house for the beating of his life, but before they get going, they tell him why, including among the accusation both everything they know and suspect.  He's warned that if he ever twists the law again, they'll come back to seek vengeance for the three people he's killed (Erika, his own son Conrad, and Marta's husband, Zayne).</p>

<p>In the morning, the mayor fails to show up for the deed to the Blackwell family's land and the subject of where their father went in the night is raised.  He admits nothing, but promises the man is still alive, followed by this little gem: "On those cold, winter nights, I imagine his knee will really ache and I hope he'll be reminded of all the bad things he’s done."</p>

<p>The sisters decide they can live with that and, in fact, it makes them feel slightly better.</p>

<p>They leave the deed to the land under a rock and depart for what they hope will be a land without persecution and prejudice.</p>

<h2>Chapter 6: The Stuff of Dreams</h2>

<p>After two years of off-and-on travel, Amelia and her family are near the city of Macclesfield, a prosperous farming community, where they've been camping long-term, to rest from their travels.</p>

<p>Amelia has built herself a horseless portable workshop in a wagon/shack similar to the one Mr. Pinewater lived in.  Inside, she's built herself a lathe that she's been using to make table legs, because no one in the city has ever seen the results of a lathe before.</p>

<p>Her table legs are all the rage in town with wealthy ladies, even though Amelia thinks the existing legs are better, but she's not going to argue with wealthy people giving her their money to do a job.</p>

<p>Amelia is depressed, because she wants a more permanent home and a much larger workshop, but most towns won't let them buy real estate, because they're outsiders.  Even worse, in the few towns that did, rumor reached all the way from the prejudice-filled village they left behind, causing them to flee for their lives, lest the Blackwell sisters be burned at the stake.</p>

<p>As she works on an order, Amelia reflects that she has wealth, but what she may actually need is influence, to change a few minds, that she might buy land, since she believes she's now beyond the reach of the rumors; it's been eight months since she last heard rumors about her family.</p>

<p>She finishes work and heads for town.</p>

<p>While she's there, she waives her fees in exchange for the the wives of the three members of the city council speaking to their husbands on her behalf, to make an exception to city law, so she can buy land.</p>

<p>It works and she even becomes friends with the mayor's wife, Mrs. Maccle, who has very forward-thinking views of women and thinks Amelia will be just the thing she needs to shake things up, in a good way.  It's never quite stated that way, but Mrs. Maccle is a feminist.</p>

<p>In the next scene, Amelia is shown a huge, disused warehouse, one option among many properties she might buy and she's soon seeing all the possibilities the place holds for her.  It even has an office area that could easily be converted into a comfortable home for her family, solving both issues.</p>

<p>She's soon lost in imaginary visions of what could be, eventually seeing in her mind not just the flying machines she been wanting to experiment with, but airships and eventually, a steel tower rising through the air on a column of super-heated steam!</p>

<p>The tower pierces the heavens and then turns at the apogee of it's flight, producing another burst of steam that carries if forward, until it's falling all the way around the world, always dropping, but never hitting ground, an orbit.</p>

<p>The word 'orbit' sticks in her mind, because she's never heard it before and she realizes the imaginary vision she just had wasn't her own.</p>

<p>She haggles over the price and buys the warehouse, before heading back to her little workshop, where she looks at <em>The Book of Newts</em> and asks, "What are you?"</p>

<p>The book flips of its own accord to the last page, which is blank.  Next, it flips to a page showing a diagram of the solar system.  Finally, it shows her star charts, and she finally realizes the sun the gas giant her little moon orbits is one star among many thousands of named stars, which are mapped in meticulous detail in the book.</p>

<p>She doesn't understand what it's telling her, but she feels exhausted, because the book has been manipulating the magic her body produces to flip it's pages, a feat that has left her with a headache, because her magic is rather weak.  It isn't able to finish what it was telling her, because she doesn't have the magic required for it to finish.</p>

<p>She recognizes the book has some kind of dream or desire, which mostly lines up with her own dreams, though it clearly thinks on a larger scale than she does.  She questions whether she should trust the book, since that was so very strange. It has never harmed her, so she decides to continue on her current path.</p>

<p>She also reasons that perhaps she owes it something for the knowledge shared, deciding to try and fulfill the book's dream of flying to the stars.</p>

<p>At this point, I finally named the gas giant Amelia's moon orbits: Junas.  Amelia believes it's the home of her world's gods, a much bigger world for giant, divine people.  By the way, it looks a lot like Jupiter, but let me make it clear: it isn't.  Junas is orbited by many worlds the size of Earth, plus lots of little ice moons.</p>

<h2>Chapter 7: Wings</h2>

<p>Amelia and her sisters work to haul her first full-size flying machine out of Macclesfield, while townsfolk look on, in wonder.</p>

<p><em>Blackbird</em>, as Amelia named it, is a fixed-wing aircraft with a single propellor, using another of her enchanted steam engines.  Amelia jokingly refers to the cockpit as a 'the witchpit', which is where the term was originally coined.  The aircraft is black and Amelia compares it to a raven.</p>

<p>It's winter and the ground is covered in snow, because Amelia hasn't yet learned about vulcanized rubber and didn't want to deal with metal or wood wheels at such high velocity, thinking the ride would be dangerously bumpy.</p>

<p>Marta drives the plane out into a farm field using another of Amelia's recent inventions, a steam-powered vehicle designed for heavy hauling, a tractor.</p>

<p>When they're ready, Amelia and Iris act as pilot and co-pilot, taking <em>Blackbird</em> into the air!  It's an exhilarating moment as they lift off the ground and Amelia cautiously gets them some altitude in a slow circle around the city, before turning control over to Iris, who does some crazy dives and sharp turns, until Amelia is sick.</p>

<p>Amelia takes them down for a landing, which is the part she's most nervous about, because she expects to crash the first time.</p>

<p>The landing goes smoothly, right up to the point they hit a boulder hidden by the snow!  Since everything is white, Amelia never saw it.</p>

<p>The prop smashes on it, then the engine hits it, producing a spray of hot water and steam, followed by the belly of <em>Blackbird</em> getting torn to shreds on it, while one of the skis is torn right off.  They're briefly forced back into the air, because the boulder somewhat acts like a ramp.</p>

<p>When they come back down, the left wing dips into the snow, due to the missing ski, lurching them to the side, until the wing rips off.  Next, the right wing does much the same, a whiplash-inducing sudden shift from twisting one direction to the other!</p>

<p>The wing also tears off, then the other ski breaks, leaving snow, ice and dirt spraying all over them through the torn bottom of the witchpit.</p>

<p>Amelia pukes, while Iris laughs hysterically and sobs at the same time.</p>

<p>Marta drives up to check on them, but fortunately, the only injuries they've got are lots of bruises and Amelia is motion sick.</p>

<p>There's some discussion of what went wrong and Amelia decides wheels are a must, after all, so she'll be seeking a way to cushion them.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_writing.html'>writing</a>, <a href='tag_work-in-progress.html'>work-in-progress</a>, <a href='tag_starwitch.html'>starwitch</a></p>

<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://owentyme.us/blog/work-in-progress-19-starwitch-2.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/blog/./work-in-progress-19-starwitch-2.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Owen Tyme</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2024 09:55:17 -0600</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Work In Progress #18: Starwitch #1
</title><description><![CDATA[

<blockquote>
  <p>"Needs must, when evil, dead witches drive…"</p>

<p>&nbsp; – Excerpt from Starwitch.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="../books/starwitch/index.html">Starwitch</a> is a novel about space-faring witches that I plan to release first as a web series, then for sale in online stores.</p>

<p><a href="https://mastodon.social/@OwenTyme/113483873966306253">You can read short summaries of each day's writing on Mastodon.</a></p>

<h2>About Starwitch</h2>

<p><em>Starwitch</em> is about three sisters that launch themselves into space with magic.  The novel has been named for their ship.  The setting will be primarily fantasy, though with some minor scientific elements, mostly in the form of mathematics, orbital dynamics and steam-powered machines.</p>

<p>I intend to publish this first as an episodic web series, then as a novel, so keep an eye on <a href="../books/starwitch/index.html">the webpage for Starwitch</a> for more details.</p>

<h2>Chapter 1: Lonely</h2>

<p>The light sail ship, <em>Starwitch</em>, is sixty meters in length, with a tube-like hull similar to a rocket, though each side has aerodynamic lines that come to a peak and the tail includes control fins for atmospheric flight.</p>

<p>Out of those peaks, as well as the top and bottom, four masts can be extended and various types of spells can be strung between them for any purpose a witch could imagine.  Most often, they'll be used for a light sail that catches light to produce thrust from the solar wind of a star.</p>

<p>The side masts can also be extended and magically enhanced to function as wings during atmospheric flight.</p>

<p>Most of the interior is taken up by water tanks, both for drinking water and use as reaction mass for maneuvering thrusters, though the water can also be used as rocket propellant in combination with magic to heat it, since there's something akin to rocket nozzles at the back.</p>

<p>The entire ship is mechanical in nature, with the most complex non-magical device on board being a clock.  Everything else is based on enchantments or the magic of the witches that fly the ship.</p>

<p><em>Starwitch</em> has to be flown entirely manually, with a set of winches inside the 'witchpit' (cockpit) used to control the angle of the four masts.</p>

<p>As the story begins, the youngest of the sisters, Amelia, is alone and she's had only two hours sleep in three days.  She's hot on the heels of a far larger ship owned by the infamous pirate, the Dead Queen.  The other ship is a massive block of granite floating in space, which Amelia refers to as a monolith, since it's all one piece of rock.</p>

<p><em>Starwitch</em> was attacked by the monolith and the Dead Queen stole the enchanted mythril spell-core of <em>Starwitch</em> that allows even a weak witch like Amelia to perform high-intensity magic.  The Queen also kidnapped Amelia's sisters, to consume their magic and their souls, that she might extend her undead existence.</p>

<p>Amelia was intentionally left for dead, with just enough resources to follow the monolith, but not enough to reach safety, a sort of sport the Dead Queen has engaged in for centuries, just to see what a desperate and weak witch might do.</p>

<p>Amelia watches the monolith entering orbit of an icy moon, presumably to take on water for propellant, and she takes a somewhat different path, heading for a polar orbit.</p>

<p>She intends to meet the monolith on the other side of the moon, where she'll attack.</p>

<p>As she awaits her moment, which is days away, Amelia looks back on her memories with regret.  It all started so innocently, with a book...</p>

<h2>Chapter 2: The Book of Newts</h2>

<p>Amelia is ten years old and practically vibrates with excitement.  She's read every book available in the house and her mother has promised her that when Mr. Pinewater next visits, she'll get a book of her very own.</p>

<p>The old man comes to visit her family and in exchange for a healing potion from Amelia's mother, Mr. Pinewater allows Amelia to select a book from the collection he keeps in his wagon, which is basically a shack on wheels.</p>

<p>While the old guy digs for books on magic to entice her with, Amelia is asked to temporarily hold an old tome titled <em>The Book of Newts</em>.  Initially, it appears to be a book all about the water-dwelling amphibians, but for one brief instant, it shows its true nature to her.  The title is actually 'Newton's Mechanics'.  She blinks and it goes back to being <em>The Book of Newts</em>.</p>

<p>The old guy tries to get her to look at the books on magic, but Amelia decides she'd rather have a magical book, than a book about magic.  In fact, she insists, despite his every attempt to guide her to one of his books on magic, mimicking a very witchy tone of command her mother uses (Amelia's mother is also a witch).</p>

<p>She leaves the wagon/shack and the old guy drops his illusion.  He's still old, but no longer disheveled and his clothes become the fine, black robes of a wizard, while his hat turns pointy and black.</p>

<p>For a time, he worries he's done the wrong thing, because the book will raise Amelia to the stars, where a dangerous enemy lurks, but having seen the girl's insatiable thirst for knowledge, he decides it would be far more cruel to stifle the girl's potential, because he considers her a prodigy.  After all, she's already smarter than he is.</p>

<p>He's confident the child will succeed where he failed, though he's uncomfortable about the path he's set her on.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_writing.html'>writing</a>, <a href='tag_work-in-progress.html'>work-in-progress</a>, <a href='tag_starwitch.html'>starwitch</a></p>

<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://owentyme.us/blog/work-in-progress-18-starwitch-1.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/blog/./work-in-progress-18-starwitch-1.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Owen Tyme</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 07:53:30 -0600</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Work In Progress #17: She Seeks Peace #9 (November 4-7)
</title><description><![CDATA[

<blockquote>
  <p>As soon as her head was down, she was snoring and Artemis smiled, because Verda had finally found somewhere she could sleep soundly.  It wasn't a permanent solution to her battle with post-traumatic stress, but it was hard to make progress without decent rest.</p>

<p>&nbsp; – Excerpt from She Seeks Peace.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><em>She Seeks Peace</em> is volume 4 of <a href="../books/ashen-blades/index.html">Ashen Blades</a>.</p>

<p>You can read a short description of <a href="../books.html#she-seeks-peace">She Seeks Peace</a> to learn more or you can read <a href="https://mastodon.social/@OwenTyme/113125105515055779">short summaries of each day's writing on Mastodon</a></p>

<p>Here's links to the rest of my blog entries on <a href="../books.html#she-seeks-peace">She Seeks Peace</a>, in chronological order:</p>

<ol>
<li><a href="work-in-progress-9-she-seeks-peace-1-september-12-13.html">September 12-13</a></li>
<li><a href="work-in-progress-10-she-seeks-peace-2-september-16-20.html">September 16-20</a></li>
<li><a href="work-in-progress-11-she-seeks-peace-3-september-23-26.html">September 23-26</a></li>
<li><a href="work-in-progress-12-she-seeks-peace-4-september-30-october-4.html">September 30-October 4</a></li>
<li><a href="work-in-progress-13-she-seeks-peace-5-october-7-11.html">October 7-11</a></li>
<li><a href="work-in-progress-14-she-seeks-peace-6-october-21-25.html">October 14-18</a></li>
<li><a href="work-in-progress-15-she-seeks-peace-7-october-21-25.html">October 21-25</a></li>
<li><a href="work-in-progress-16-she-seeks-peace-8-october-28-november-1.html">October 28-November 1</a></li>
</ol>

<h2>Chapter 42: Pale Imitations</h2>

<p>This chapter opens with Lara entering the mine Wrath is using as his base on Earth.  She uses Mashu'ra's nose to smell out the situation, realizing all seven arch-demons are inside.</p>

<p>She asks, "You ready to go down in a blaze of glory, Masher?  I don’t think we’ll survive the day, but I’m game if you are."</p>

<p>Mashu'ra's response is straight to the point: "They took the boss.  She’s always been a key part of Vogerath’s plan to open a portal to Hell, because he can’t stabilize it without a half-demon.  So, this is bigger than us.  I’d sacrifice myself to save the world, any day of the week, because that’s what the boss would do."</p>

<p>With that confirmation of commitment, Lara heads deeper into the mine.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Insanity is happy to be free of the Hunter's head, with a physical body of her own.  She feels a little short on energy, but looks around at the seven arches, seeing the equivalent of a buffet.</p>

<p>As he backs away, Insanity screams, "I’m The Eighth Deadly Sin, Willful Insanity!  All of you demons are pale imitations of me, because people would have to be crazy to sin!  You have one chance to survive: bow down to me and pledge your eternal servitude or I’ll eat you all!"</p>

<p>Wrath is about to put the cursed wedding band made by Lust on Insanity's finger, but she points out the fact she's not in a binding circle.  Wrath looses his cool and real terror crosses his face!</p>

<p>One of the three bodies Pride showed up in changes form to a little garden snake and sneaks off, while Lust and Greed make their way toward the exit.  The other arches stand together, as a unified front, because they've all been challenged, though Sloth yawns.</p>

<p>Insanity considers Sogliun, the moon demon, to be the only real threat in the room, but he chickens out and flows downward, into the floor, while no one is looking.</p>

<p>Pride speaks for all: "We won’t serve you, but might be persuaded to allow you to join our ranks.  Though a few examples of the eighth arch demon have existed in the past, each was a dangerous, rogue element, definitely not a team player.  Will you be the same, or will you join us?"</p>

<p>Insanity's answer is to head-butt Wrath, while she impales both of Pride's bodies on her claws.  Wrath is hit so hard, his head goes rolling away.  Insanity eats both of Pride's bodies, somewhat refilling her energy reserves.</p>

<p>Still conscious, Wrath's head rolls to a stop near the third copy of Pride.</p>

<p>Wrath asks for help and Pride eats him, which was according to Pride's plan, all along, because he intends to eat all of the arches and then eat their boss, the Void.</p>

<p>Alice looks on as Insanity deals with the arches, bothered by the fact that the Hunter seems to be dying.  After some magical analysis, she realizes the Hunter is missing human genetics that she requires to survive on her own and with the demon separated from her mind and body, she can't gather the magic she'd been using to sustain herself.</p>

<p>Alice clasps the Hunter's forearm and begins feeding her magic, though it's only a stop-gap measure, that will buy half an hour.</p>

<p>Envy tries to escape, but Insanity crushes her to death with the thrown corpse of Wrath.</p>

<p>Gluttony is scared, rightly afraid she's about to be eaten, while her bodyguards abandon her, aside from one.</p>

<p>Her last bodyguard turns out to be a regular fairy that's been bound to serve Gluttony by some bargain the two of them made.  He takes the form of a humanoid turtle made of diamond.  Gluttony is smashed with the body of her last bodyguard, thrown like a projectile.  I just wanted to do a little foreshadowing for a later book.</p>

<p>Insanity turns her attention on Lust and Greed.  There's a brief argument and Insanity decides to slay Lust, but can't, stopping a fraction of an inch from the kill.  She tries again, but same results.</p>

<p>Lust reiterates the bargain she made with the Hunter in the previous book: She must protect Lust and Lust will answer any question the Hunter asks.  Insanity was part of the Hunter at the time, so she's bound by the agreement.</p>

<p>Insanity screams in her face, "There’s nothing I want to ask!"</p>

<p>Insanity kills Greed and his guards, then grabs Lust.  She warns the arch-demon that she'll keep her 'safe' and 'alive', but that Lust may not like her definition of those words, if she presses her luck.</p>

<p>Turning to Sloth, Insanity asks, "What about you, Sticky?"  I like this little nickname, because Sloth is a living goo monster.</p>

<p>Sloth just wants to go home, without a fight.</p>

<p>Insanity punches him, splattering him all over the walls.</p>

<p>She thinks he's dead and turns away, but he speaks again, "It isn’t that easy."</p>

<p>Sloth tries sleep magic, because he's famed for it, and everyone present falls asleep, except himself and Insanity, because "Madness never sleeps."</p>

<p>She tries to swallow Sloth whole, but Sloth explodes into mist.  She thinks it's a self-destruct spell designed to prevent him from being eaten, but Sloth was never truly there.  He only showed up by dream-walking, more or less a variation of astral projection.</p>

<p>Insanity looks on Alice and the Hunter and decides to eat them, since with the Hunter out of her head, she no longer has any sense of fair play.</p>

<p>Alice wakes in time to see the gaping maw of Insanity and has just enough time to manifest the torn mushroom cap that allows her to grow larger, cramming the whole thing in her mouth!</p>

<p>At the same time, Lara arrives, just in time to see, but not understand the resulting explosion, as Alice grows so fast, she smashes her way through the roof of the cave!</p>

<h2>Chapter 43: Remorse of Conscience</h2>

<p>Alice's transformation leaves her standing in a hole in the ceiling, as the light of dawn filters through her dress, bathing the room in blue light.  Each of her feet (in boots, of course) is six feet long!</p>

<p>During the collapse cause by Alice's actions, Insanity rushed to the side of Lust, to deflect falling boulders.</p>

<p>Alice bellows, "How dare you try to kill our sister?"</p>

<p>Alice steps back (the ground shakes as she walks) and peers down into the hole.  She reaches to pick up the Hunter, to keep her safe, but Insanity screams, "She's mine!"</p>

<p>Insanity attack's Alice's hand with her claws and Alice tries to punch her, much the way a human might try to smash a mouse!  Insanity flops on her back and accepts the strick, so she can use all four sets of claws, latching onto Alice's hand!</p>

<p>Alice hauls her hand back out of the hole, taking Insanity away, though she stumbles off, causing another quake.</p>

<p>Lara drops her invisibility spell and rushes to the Hunter's side, asking what happened.</p>

<p>Lust actually takes responsibility, actually in tears over the guilt she feels.  She even apologizes.</p>

<p>Lust explains everything, including why she did it (revenge), but now she feels awful about it.</p>

<p>Lara turns her into a Tommy gun and points it right in Lust's face, to demand, "Give me one good reason I shouldn't kill you right here and now!"</p>

<p>Lust explains what needs to happen to reintegrate the Hunter: her three personalities need to willingly merge.  Alternatively, the giant can eat Insanity, then merge.</p>

<p>Lust begins to feel remorse for every single wrong thing she's ever done, which isn't a short list, with sins darker and more bloody than the worst serial killer, because her conscience is finally working properly, as a result of her recent religious reading habits.</p>

<p>Lara decides to let Lust live, but only of she signs an unconditional contract to answer Lara's questions.  Lara hands over a sheet of paper and Lust writes, 'I promise to answer the questions of Lara Simmons.'  She bites her thumb and stamps the page with her bloody fingerprint, sealing the bargain.</p>

<p>The Hunter calls attention to herself, because she's a hair away from death, so Lara uses a little magic to transfer Mashu'ra into the girl's body.  Mashu'ra gets her back on her feet and in fighting form, at the cost of great pain, but the Hunter reasons a little pain is a small price to pay to save the world.</p>

<p>After all, with Insanity running loose, every human in the world is in danger.</p>

<p>Lara returns her hat and asks, "You ready to rock and roll?"</p>

<p>The Hunter nods, so Lara turns into an M1911 pistol, which the Hunter catches out of the air.</p>

<p>She steps over to Lust and points it right in her face.  For a tense moment, Lust believes she's about to die, based on the idea of the Hunter pointing the gun as a mere threat, while the imp (Mashu'ra) pulls the trigger.  She closes her eyes and accepts her fate.</p>

<p>The Hunter fires, putting a bullet through Lust's ear, because she's beyond pissed.  Lust opens her eyes just in time to be pistol-whipped!</p>

<p>Lara orders her to stay put and threatens a fate worse than death if she isn't there when they come back, claiming she just put a tracking curse on Lust, with that bullet.</p>

<p>The Hunter screams in Lust's face, then flies out of the hole in the ceiling.</p>

<h2>Chapter 44: Rock and Roll</h2>

<p>Alice struggles with Insanity, discovering her giant size has some serious disadvantages: it slows her regenerative powers and makes her a big target, despite giving her incredible strength.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Insanity winds her way up and around Alice's arm, cutting her all the way to the bone!  Alice tries to scrape her off, but Insanity dodges.</p>

<p>Getting desperate, Alice calls DRINK ME into her hand and downs the entire bottle!  She explosively shrinks down to the size of an ant and brags hold of Insanity's fur, with the intent of reaching the ear, where such a tiny figure might do some serious damage.</p>

<p>The Hunter flies into the air, seeing Insanity fall as Alice vanishes.</p>

<p>Lara turns into a Barret M107 anti-material rifle and the Hunter puts a round through Insanity's head, causing it to explode!</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Alice has reached the spot between Insanity's shoulder blades, where she decided to take a short breather.  She's really grateful she took the breather, because otherwise, she might have been hit.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, Insanity is beyond the power of the average demon and manages to regenerate her head, a feat no other demon can match!</p>

<p>Alice continues her climb.</p>

<p>Knowing the situation is too hot for Lara, who might easily be killed in the mayhem, the Hunter leaves her behind and charges into battle.</p>

<p>Lara is upset by this, but decides to find a hiding place, so she can still contribute, by sniping.</p>

<p>The Hunter and Insanity roll through the Outback like a pair of angry, giant cats, but while the hunter gets stronger the more damage she takes, she also gets more stupid, the same issue Simmons always dealt with in cat-man form!</p>

<p>She lets go and kicks Insanity away, so she can think.  She concludes brute strength is not the answer and none of her armored forms would work, either.</p>

<p>She wants to try grenades, but realizes she can't reach any of her gear inside her hat, without her demon powers.</p>

<p>She's also somewhat worried her mother's magic isn't protecting her, but her mother's power was split three ways and she's become ineffectual as a result.</p>

<p>She has Wood, Water, Air and Fire magic, so she combines the first three to rapidly grow trees to snare Insanity in a web of wood.  Insanity is so strong, however, that she immediately starts to break free, so the Hunter adds some Fire magic, using the wood for fuel, while she produces pure oxygen with Air magic!  The flame gets so hot, it burns blue!</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Alice is in Insanity's ear and worries she's about to be burned to death.  She magically produces the mushroom cap and eats the whole thing in one bite!</p>

<p>Alice violently explodes out of Insanity's head, then starts punching the demon with her full, gigantic strength!</p>

<p>Insanity produces a painful telepathic scream of rage that sends Alice stumbling away, before she falls to the ground, causing an earthquake!  Likewise, the Hunter is stunned, while Insanity gets back to her feet!</p>

<p>Lara opens fire, once again exploding the demon's head!</p>

<p>We switch to the perspective of Lust, who's guilt in this matter stirs her to action, because she can sense our heroes are losing the fight.</p>

<p>She feels she must help, so she flies out to join them.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Lara empties her magazine, repeatedly blowing Insanity's head off, though she grows back faster each time.  On the other hand, Lara has always laced her rounds with either poison or disease and Insanity does slow down a bit.</p>

<p>Once Lara's all out of ammunition (it takes her a while to magically produce .50-cal rounds, since they're so large), Insanity picks up the Hunter, in preparation to eat her, once and for all.</p>

<p>Lust arrives and pours on every bit of charm magic she can, slowing Insanity down with multiple tempting offers that match Lust's nature.  Her words make Alice and the Hunter both blush.</p>

<p>While Insanity is distracted, the Metal Spirit, which killed Simmons, shows up and whispers to the Hunter.  As usual, it does so in poetic rhymes of four lines.</p>

<p>It uses flowery words to apologize for killing Simmons, then explains its nature as having been forged from earth using fire, air and water, hinting that it's a child of all four of the basic elements.  The rhyme also implies that humanity made it what it is.  I like this as an explanation for why it's so strong, probably the most powerful elemental spirit, aside from Life and the Void.</p>

<p>Therefore, it decides to serve the Hunter willingly, that she might save humanity.</p>

<p>There's a brief scene inside the Hunter's head, in which it bows to her, offers up a token (a cast-iron and steel bracelet) and the Hunter collars it, much like she did with the Water and Air spirits in previous books.</p>

<p>Coming back to the real world, Insanity once more picks up the Hunter, then opens her mouth extra wide, to eat her.  The Hunter hears Vogerath/Pride screaming, amused by the sound.</p>

<p>The chapter comes to a close as the Hunter focuses her mind to use Metal magic for the first time, while the bracelet tinkles on her wrist, since those tokens are both metaphors and real objects.</p>

<h2>Chapter 45: (Re)forging Bonds</h2>

<p>Insanity snaps her jaws shut on the Hunter, only to break some of her teeth!  Letting go and stepping back, she sees the Hunter's clothes have produced metal plates, just like a suit of armor!</p>

<p>This metal-shrouded transformation is much like the iron wood armor she got from subjugating the Jungle Spirit, but instead of some rather heavy wood, the metal spirit has given her armor plates composed of layered titanium and tungsten, producing something with properties of both.</p>

<p>Insanity throws a temper tantrum, slamming her fists into the ground, producing brief earthquakes!</p>

<p>In the background, Alice drinks her potion, returning to normal size, mostly so she can heal.</p>

<p>The Hunter looks Insanity in the eye and raises a hand, then pretends with the other she's turning a crack attached to the first, seemingly resulting in her middle finger popping up.</p>

<p>Insanity is actually amused, saying, "I like that gesture.  It fits the Robocop thing you've got going."</p>

<p>But having seen her greatest desire frustrated, Insanity is done with the fight and decides to walk away, though she promises to return to eat the Hunter, followed by every one of her sheep (meaning the human race).  She plans to force the Hunter to watch as she wipes out everyone.</p>

<p>The Hunter screams at her, but Insanity ignores her.</p>

<p>Working with Mashu'ra, the Hunter produces a wall of fire to block Insanity's way, which curves around all three of them, in a huge circle.</p>

<p>Insanity turns back to point out the futility of continuing to fight, while the symbols required to bind a demon begin appearing in the flames, thanks to Mashu'ra, while seven more fiery binding circles forming.</p>

<p>When the first circle closes, Mashu'ra is significantly weakened, but the Hunter picks up the slack and maintains the magic long enough for Mashu'ra to finish shaping all the binding symbols.  He falls unconscious and ends up on her shoulder.</p>

<p>Having lost Mashu'ra's power, the Hunter collapses, but gives the demon double middle fingers, before she falls over.</p>

<p>Insanity screams and charges, but runs out of power before she reaches the Hunter, because her demonic powers have been sealed.  She scrabbles to get closer, but lacks the strength to move and throws another temper-tantrum, demonstrating how immature she is, without the Hunter.</p>

<p>She's horribly upset and complaining about how 'unfair' the situation is.</p>

<p>Aliget gets up, bites into her mushroom cap and grows back to giant size.  She picks up the helpless demon and eats her, though she does say something soothing, to try and make Insanity feel slightly better about it.</p>

<p>Alice takes a swig of DRINK ME and returns to normal size.  She lays down next to the Hunter and asks, "Can we be friends?"</p>

<p>As far as the Hunter is concerned, they already are, and even better, they're sisters, so she nods agreement.</p>

<p>Alice vanishes, re-absorbed by the Hunter.</p>

<p>The Hunter puts Mashu'ra in her hat.</p>

<p>The hunter enters her mindscape, finding Alice has made a little corner of it her own, with a small patch of gigantic grass, a tiny little sun for some light and a huge mushroom, on which Alice sits.  Beside that are a record player producing psychedelic rock and a little apple tree with grenades instead of apples.</p>

<p>Alice is smoking form the Caterpillar's hookah, while the Caterpillar has been put in a specialized straight-jacket designed to keep it's very many arms under control.  It's mouth is gagged, but it soon gets that loose and growls in the voice of Insanity.</p>

<p>“Quit harshing my buzz and relax for once!” Alice complains and shoves the stem of the hookah in the demon’s mouth.</p>

<p>Insanity inhales, but doesn't like it, spitting it out, before another torrent of complaints come form the Caterpillar's mouth.</p>

<p>The response of Alice is to slap Insanity, followed by telling her to shut up.</p>

<p>The Hunter falls over laughing, because this is something hilarious she never expected to see!</p>

<p>Lara finds the Hunter rolling in the dirt, laughing until she cries.  Concerned, she calls the Hunter by name, calling her Artemis.</p>

<p>She stops laughing and considers that name, which was given by Simmons.  She still sad she's lost him, but she's ready to accept that name as part of moving forward.  From this point on, she starts referring to herself as Artemis.</p>

<p>Lara helps her up and together, they seek out Lust, finding her stuck in the dirt, unable to free herself, because she hit the ground that hard, when Insanity backhanded her.</p>

<p>They help her out and Lara thinks her for helping. Lust doesn't accept her gratitude, because she doesn't feel she deserves it and apologizes to Artemis for everything she's done wrong.</p>

<p>Lara asks Artemis if she can handle transportation and she puts Lust in her hat.  Lara turns into a pistol, for ease of carrying, and Artemis vanishes into a puff of smoke.</p>

<h2>Chapter 46: Hemming the Fray</h2>

<p>Artemis reappears far above <em>The Cauldron of the Elements</em> (Macie's home valley).</p>

<p>She enjoys the view as she falls, in Australia, dawn was just over, but here, dusk is about to begin.</p>

<p>And yes, that does finally pin down the timezone of the place, likely putting it somewhere in the Appalachian mountain range, but I'm not going any further than that.  It's a fictional place, so don't go looking for it.  And now that I've started a conspiracy theory, let's get back to the story.</p>

<p>From above, it looks desolate and dead, because the interior is masked by an illusion spell, to keep it safe.  Artemis passes through this, revealing the forest and blue lake.</p>

<p>She takes control of her fall and flies down to Macie's house, where she knocks on the door, then flies out of sight three times, messing with Macie's head as she answers.</p>

<p>Lara ends the game by speaking and Macie invites them in.</p>

<p>Hours later, James and Lara have fallen asleep on the couch, leaving a lovely scene of mother and son.</p>

<p>Artemis and Macie sneak out quietly, to avoid waking them, and head for the old amphitheater and stage.  There, Macie begins teaching Artemis to dance and juggle, which are both important components of <em>The Dance of Fire and Autumn</em>.</p>

<p>Decades earlier, when Artemis met the Fire Spirit, it promised to willingly serve her, if she could subjugate the Metal Spirit, then summon the Fire Spirit via the dance.  Having gotten the Metal Spirit under control, thanks to Simmons, she now wishes to summon the Fire Spirit, because she's convinced it will be useful in combat.</p>

<p>Artemis has trouble with dancing, tripping over her own feet, but picks up juggling fairly quickly.</p>

<h2>Epilogue</h2>

<p>Lust is back in a cell, reflecting on how much she's changed and how far she has to go.  Lara and Verda just finished an interrogation session, which Lust fully cooperated with.</p>

<p>Cooperation has led to improvements in Lust's living arrangements, including a soft bed and a chair for her to relax in, as well as more choice in food selection, but Lust doesn't think she deserves any of it.</p>

<p>Each such session leaves her wanting to die, because she's wracked with guilt for her many, many dark deeds, but she staves off such thoughts by reading The Book of Mormon.</p>

<p>After reading for a time, she prays.  She isn't certain if God is real or not, but knows that praying certainly makes her feel better.</p>

<p>I'm not entirely sure where I'm going with Lust's journey, but I'm planning to span it over the course of several more novels.  However, part of it is clear: Lust's journey to redemption demonstrates the fact that the "demons" aren't actually what they claim to be, further emphasizing the fact they're dark fairies, because they can change.</p>

<p>Switching to Artemis, we find her putting James in his crib after a meal and some cartoons, because he fell asleep on the couch and she's been babysitting for Lara.</p>

<p>Lara and Verda enter the apartment.  Lara starts a meal, while Verda sits on the couch and Artemis sit opposite her, in a chair.  They acknowledge each other, before Verda falls asleep on the couch.</p>

<p>After all, with both Lara and Artemis in the place, who have both defeated Wrath, Verda feels totally safe and can sleep peacefully.  It isn't a permanent solution to her post-traumatic stress, but quality rest is required for proper mental healing.</p>

<p>Artemis reflects on the fact they had been grieving the loss of Simmons separately, but ironically, Wrath somehow managed to bring them together.</p>

<p>She also reflects on the valuable lesson Evie and Simmons taught her: Artemis will always value the time she has with her friends, short though it may be.  However, she will never stop fighting to keep them safe.</p>

<h2>The Editing Process</h2>

<p>With the Epilogue finished, I've completed the rough draft of <a href="../books.html#she-seeks-peace">She Seeks Peace</a>.</p>

<p>This work-in-progress log will pause until I begin a new project, so I can do a pass of editing on <em>She Seeks Peace</em>.  With the way I've been using text to speech software for my daily editing, I've been finding my typos and spelling mistakes earlier on, so I'm likely to only do one editing pass, mostly a matter of looking at the plot.  I'll do more when it comes time to publish, but I'm eager to get to my next project.</p>

<p>I'm likely to add some scenes in which the Metal Spirit comes to Artemis/the Hunter, looking to apologize, because its appearance at the end was a bit abrupt.  That will give me the opportunity to add a couple of funny places our heroine can seek peace.</p>

<p>One of the scenes I had in mind, but never used, was to have her hide among a herd of black and white cows.  Her magic clothes will give her camouflage, to fit in with them.  My thinking is there will be lots of metal fencing near the cows, justifying the presence of the Metal Spirit.</p>

<p>I think I need to come up with two more little scenes like that, just to subtly introduce the idea of it's presence for the final fight, though I need to be careful about when and where I insert them.  I think they would work best early on in the novel.</p>

<p>I mentally justify its presence in Australia with the fact the final battle took place near an old, abandoned mine (it wasn't quite as played-out as the owner thought), on top of the fact Australia exports a lot of mined metals.  Perhaps I need to throw another four line block into its rhymes, to serve as a sort of explanation:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Metal, Metal everywhere,<br/>
Under feet, here and there.<br/>
Metal made from Metal ore,<br/>
Man ever digs, such a chore.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>That would also fit with previous appearances, because it usually makes reference to metal Artemis didn't realize was present.</p>

<p>Other than that, the only other thing I'll need to do is add some descriptive details, which I always do during editing.</p>

<h2>What's Next?</h2>

<p>There's two possibilities looming for my next project, the first a short story, the other a novel.</p>

<h3>The Recruit (Working Title)</h3>

<p><em>The Recruit</em> will be a short story centering around Detective Shime Yasu, who readers may recall from <a href="../books/ashen-blades/demon-for-president.html">Demon for President!</a></p>

<p>You might remember that she was given a special card to use, which had a number for her to call when she's "ready to open her eyes".  The story will begin with Yasuy lying awake, unable to sleep, because her mind is too busy with the bizarre things she saw in the body cam videos of Ulmoch and Artemis in action.</p>

<p>She'll call the number and the story will show a glimpse into the recruiting and training process for the Order of Ash and Smoke.  Artemis, Lara and Verda will work together for training.</p>

<p>Yasu will be one among many local recruits, but the story will center around disabusing the group of all misconceptions about demons, because all of them brought weapons they thought would be effective, including crosses, holy water and some dumb fool got confused, so he brought a wooden stake.</p>

<p>It will be a simple story, in which Artemis captures a demon for training purposes, while Lara tests all of the things the recruits brought, once more hammering home the point that they're not actually demons, because the crosses do nothing, the holy water just gets him wet and hammering the stake into his heart just gets him to make creepy comments (Ulmoch has always been a masochist, so he enjoys people hurting him).</p>

<p>Finally, Yasu will ask, "So, what does work?"</p>

<p>Lara will transform into an M1911 and Artemis will shoot Ulmoch in the head, while Lara delivers the punchline: ".45 rounds are good."</p>

<p>Yep, the whole story is just setup for a joke, though I think ending it with Yasu sleeping soundly would be a nice touch.</p>

<p>I've had this story in mind since I wrote the bits involving Detective Yasu, but had to get past <em>She Seeks Peace</em> to know the mental state of my characters, since the ending of <a href="../books/ashen-blades/demon-for-president.html">Demon for President!</a> was a big, dangling plot thread.</p>

<h3>Star Witch</h3>

<p>The other project I'm eager to get to is tentatively titled <em>Star Witch</em>.  This will be about a trio of witches and sisters that used magic to launch themselves into space.</p>

<p>The story will focus on one of the sisters, who's named Amelia.  She's the enchanter and engineer that built the light-sail ship, named <em>Star Witch</em>, but lacks talent for other forms of magic, barely able to operate the ship on her own power.</p>

<p>Most of the details are foggy to me, but I know it begins with Amelia alone aboard <em>Star Witch</em>, aside from the house brownies that serve as the ship's repair crew, though she's never seen them.</p>

<p>Amelia is extremely exhausted at this point, because she's been operating the ship around the clock with minimal breaks for sleep, when it was designed to be operated in shifts or left to its own devices for long periods of time.</p>

<p>Amelia's sisters were kidnapped several days earlier and <em>Star Witch</em> was left badly damaged, all by order of the villain, the Dead Queen.</p>

<p>Amelia has been following the Dead Queen's monolith (a huge, granite slab with tunnels cut through it, which serves as her star ship), using the bigger ship's wake of waste magic to barely keep her own light sails functional.</p>

<p>My plan is to do a series of flashbacks on the lives of the three sisters building and launching <em>Star Witch</em>, followed by docking at a space station, where they'll hear tales of the Dead Queen, a powerful witch that drains the life and magic from other witches, to extend her own life.</p>

<p>Eventually, the story will culminate in the monolith moving into parking orbit above an icy moon in the present (they've stopped to take on water, which is required for various processes aboard the big ship, despite the crew being undead), while Amelia goes around the moon the other way.</p>

<p>Amelia's intent is to surprise the monolith from the front, rather than attacking from behind, the last thing the Dead Queen might expect.  Amelia has no other choice: she's dead without either the stolen mythril core of her ship or the backup of her sisters; she's the weakest of the three witches, barely able to get <em>Star Witch</em> moving on her own.</p>

<p>The truth is, the Dead Queen setup the entire situation for the sake of entertainment, a sort of sport she's played with smaller ships for centuries.  She takes the strongest witches to extend her life and leaves the very weakest with a barely functional vessel, eager to learn what a desperate witch might do.</p>

<p>However, she didn't know and didn't count on <em>Star Witch</em> being full of house brownies, which can repair the ship, even in the absence of proper supplies, nor did she count on Amelia's exceptional skill with mathematics and engineering, which will be the lesser witch's greatest weapons.</p>

<p>I'm not entirely sure how Amelia will get her sisters back, but I do know she'll intentionally crash <em>Star Witch</em> into the monolith, so she can board the pirate vessel.  This might involve crashing into a docking bay, but thinking about it, the bridge would be far more fun, a combination of destroying command and control functionality, followed by a desperate rescue mission, while the house brownies hold the line against the Dead Queen's soldiers.</p>

<p>I'm going to use Amelia's lonely tale as a framing story for the novel, to add tension and foreshadowing for the climax, coming back to it at the start and close of each part of the novel.</p>

<h2>Thank You!</h2>

<p>Thank you for following along as I write.</p>

<p>I don't get much feedback about these work-in-progress posts, but people like and boost them on Mastodon, which is encouraging.</p>

<p>Have a great day!  You'll probably see my next post in this series the week after next.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_writing.html'>writing</a>, <a href='tag_work-in-progress.html'>work-in-progress</a>, <a href='tag_ashen-blades.html'>ashen-blades</a></p>

<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://owentyme.us/blog/work-in-progress-17-she-seeks-peace-9-october-28-november-1.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/blog/./work-in-progress-17-she-seeks-peace-9-october-28-november-1.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Owen Tyme</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 08:07:16 -0600</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Demon for President!
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p><a href="https://books2read.com/DemonForPresident"><img src="../images/Flyer-DemonForPresident.jpg" alt="" title="" /></a></p>

<p>Today, November 5, 2024, is a very special and strange day, at least in the United States, where I live.  The current election and division between the Republicans and Democrats really inspired me to pay attention during the first republican debate, last year.</p>

<p>I've never voted, since politics has always literally given me a splitting headache, because there's too many lies to really uncover the truth.  Cynically, I sometimes wonder if there's any truth to be found, at all.</p>

<p>Still, I wasn't paying attention to the politics, but rather to the behavior of political candidates, because I'd had a bizarre, fun and timely idea for a novel: what would happen if a demon ran for President of the United States?</p>

<p>So, I watched and continually found material that could be twisted into political satire, all the while unsure if I had the skill to make the novel work.  I got it published in June, just in time for the current election to really heat up.</p>

<p>With voting happening today, I've been thinking about that novel, which is titled <a href="../books/ashen-blades/demon-for-president.html">Demon for President!</a></p>

<p>I ran the election and potential twists through my head many times during the writing process, but never did I expect so many parallels between fiction and the real world.</p>

<p>In my novel, the demonic villain, Otto Vogerath, was shot at by a sniper while cutting the ribbon for a store.  On July 13, Former President Trump became the target of a sniper, an event that chilled me to the bone, because reality became eerily like something I'd written.</p>

<p>For another example, I wrote about the President bowing out of the election to make way for another candidate, so it really caught my attention when that happened!</p>

<p>There are other parallels, but none so shocking as those two, or which I would care to discuss, because I'm not here to draw connections between real people and fictional characters that really aren't connected.</p>

<p>I wrote the novel early this year and published it in June, <em>before</em> these events took place, but all I can think is this: art imitates life and life imitates art.  There is truth to that old adage, after all.</p>

<p>I found the experience of writing political satire to be fun, educational and even intellectually stimulating, but at the same time, it made me nervous to see my fiction come true in such unsettling ways.  I can't say I found that part of the experience enjoyable, which may be why I haven't discussed this novel as much as others.</p>

<p>I meant it all in fun, as a way to point out how silly and funny politicians can be, but I think I cut this piece too close to reality.  It surprises me, the things I see without comprehending, which can so easily become a part of my work.</p>

<p>So much of my writing process is a subconscious black box, which I don't even pretend to understand, a gift that must be fed for me to retain it, but which sometimes produces things that leave me speechless for the most unusual reasons.</p>

<p>I'm not sure I can take any more parallels with my novel, but hopefully, our next president won't open a portal to Hell, so endless legions of demons can march forth to conquer the Earth.  That would be one bit of straw too many for this particular camel.</p>

<p>Still, once the dust of this election clears, why not read about what could have been, if we'd gotten a <a href="../books/ashen-blades/demon-for-president.html">Demon for President?</a></p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_ashen-blades.html'>ashen-blades</a>, <a href='tag_writing.html'>writing</a></p>

<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://owentyme.us/blog/demon-for-president.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/blog/./demon-for-president.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Owen Tyme</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 19:00:15 -0600</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Work In Progress #16: She Seeks Peace #8 (October 28-November 1)
</title><description><![CDATA[

<blockquote>
  <p>"She felt very strange, as if her memories weren't her own, because they were a swarm of ants crawling around inside her skull, their skittering feet tickling her every synapse, making her laugh out loud, her voice echoing around her.</p>

<p>She wasn't sure what her name was, but knew it definitely wasn't 'The Hunter'.  It most certainly wasn't 'The Eighth Deadly Sin, Willful Insanity', either."</p>

<p>&nbsp; – Excerpt from She Seeks Peace.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><em>She Seeks Peace</em> is volume 4 of <a href="../books/ashen-blades/index.html">Ashen Blades</a>.</p>

<p>You can read a short description of <a href="../books.html#she-seeks-peace">She Seeks Peace</a> to learn more or you can read <a href="https://mastodon.social/@OwenTyme/113125105515055779">short summaries of each day's writing on Mastodon</a></p>

<p>Here's links to the rest of my blog entries on <a href="../books.html#she-seeks-peace">She Seeks Peace</a>, in chronological order:</p>

<ol>
<li><a href="work-in-progress-9-she-seeks-peace-1-september-12-13.html">September 12-13</a></li>
<li><a href="work-in-progress-10-she-seeks-peace-2-september-16-20.html">September 16-20</a></li>
<li><a href="work-in-progress-11-she-seeks-peace-3-september-23-26.html">September 23-26</a></li>
<li><a href="work-in-progress-12-she-seeks-peace-4-september-30-october-4.html">September 30-October 4</a></li>
<li><a href="work-in-progress-13-she-seeks-peace-5-october-7-11.html">October 7-11</a></li>
<li><a href="work-in-progress-14-she-seeks-peace-6-october-21-25.html">October 14-18</a></li>
<li><a href="work-in-progress-15-she-seeks-peace-7-october-21-25.html">October 21-25</a></li>
</ol>

<h2>Chapter 38: Letting Go</h2>

<p>Evie spends all morning and afternoon speaking with the spirits of her dead friends.  It gets pretty emotional for her, because she's doing her best to let them go, so they can pass on.</p>

<p>The Hunter holds her hand and Evie squeezes it pretty hard with each tearful goodbye.  She grows a little older with each, until she's about thirty years old.</p>

<p>Last of all, she talks with her grandmother, but Evelyn asks to speak with the Hunter and Evie makes her visible.</p>

<p>Evelyn explains that she watched the world with magic for a very long time, looking for a champion to take Evie to her family.  She'd heard of the Hunter, but couldn't see her, because the hunter is effectively invisible to most forms of detection magic.</p>

<p>In August (around the same time the Hunter went back in time, during the previous book), the Fates appeared to her in a vision, telling her the Hunter was on the way, to take Evie to family.</p>

<p>She asks if the Fates can be trusted and the Hunter somewhat reluctantly agrees, because she at least trusts them to help her against Vogerath.  That reassures Evelyn she did the right thing and she passes on, vanishing from sight.</p>

<p>The Hunter comforts Evie for a time, before the rapidly-aging woman says she's tired and lonely.  The Hunter pats her back and Riley steps in, for a group hug.</p>

<p>He reminds Evie, "You're not alone."</p>

<p>After that, Evie asks to be left alone, for a nap.  She also corrects her accent mid-sentence, finally figuring out how to pronounce the letter L, promising to make Simmons visible, once she's rested.</p>

<p>As Riley and the Hunter leave the bedroom, Riley expresses his worry that Evie might not stop growing older, because she's now in her mid-forties!</p>

<p>There's a brief scene in which Evie is alone with her thoughts and she briefly considers suicide, that she might be with her friends.  The first of the monks that died was a woman with depression issues, who took her own life, though Evie hadn't understood that at the time.  Having seen how that didn't solve anything, she decides against suicide.</p>

<p>She doesn't realize it, but she's growing older by the moment and she's already rapidly headed toward a death by natural causes, though her aging slows as she falls asleep.</p>

<p>Some time later, Evie calls out for help.  Riley and the Hunter rush in, finding Evie on the floor: she fell out of bed and can't get up, because she's now over ninety years old!</p>

<p>They help her back into bed.  She offers to make Simmons visible and the Hunter prepares by hauling Mashu'ra out of her hat.</p>

<p>Simmons appears and thanks Mashu'ra for giving him the chance to fight demons.  Next, he tells them both he loves them and admits this is going to be goodbye for a long time, though he'll wait until the end of time to see the Hunter again, if required.</p>

<p>He also discusses the fact that he knows neither of them will let go of life until the demon threat is permanently solved.</p>

<p>Finally, he addresses the elephant in the room, asking the Hunter to let him go, because she's been dragging him through life like a boat anchor.  He isn't angry, because she had no idea her magic had responded to her emotions by binding his spirit to her, but he <em>is</em> upset that he can't pass on.</p>

<p>Last of all he says: "Go ahead and treasure the time we had together, but don’t hold onto me so tight."</p>

<p>The Hunter enters her internal mindscape, like the way she fought Sogliun, seeking the deepest, darkest corner of her mind, where she buries things she doesn't want to deal with.</p>

<p>This turns out to be a steel-lined corridor, along which hangs paintings, each of which is a different traumatic memory.  Two examples are the death of her parents and Reggie's death.  She takes the painting of Reggie's final moments off the wall and puts it under her arm as she goes deeper, seeking the darkest corner of the place.</p>

<p>She ends up at a dead end dominated by a piece of raw canvas that's been riveted to the wall, which displays the death of Simmons on an eternal loop.</p>

<p>She goes off somewhere else for a ladder and drill of the old hand-cranked variety.  She sets up the ladder and manually drills out every last rivet, taking the canvas down, though that leaves the wall bleeding.  She rolls up the canvas and carries it away.</p>

<p>She returns to the usual corner of her mindscape and as an experiment, she sets the painting of Reggie's final moments on fire, with magic.  It turns into smoke that fills the shadows surrounding her, which are actually her memories.  The return of that buried memory is painful, but it brings with it a flood of good memories that she'd been forced to bury with it, because they were connected.  She's finally able to look back on her time with Reggie, feeling joy.</p>

<p>She next lights the bloody canvas aflame, releasing the full pain of loss into her mind.  It really hurts, but she's ready to really deal with it and find a way forward.</p>

<p>Her inner demon (The Eighth Deadly Sin, Willful Insanity, or Insanity for short) hugs her in a surprising turn of events, because Insanity was born from the Hunter's Id, which is all about emotion.</p>

<p>Back in the real world, she tries to say, "I love you", though it comes out as "It's a secret."</p>

<p>Simmons responds, "I love you, too."</p>

<p>Mashu'ra also says goodbye and Simmons fades away.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Evie has grown translucent, because she's also fading!</p>

<p>Riley is upset, because he basically gained a daughter and now she's dying, in less than a day's time.</p>

<p>Evie tells them what she just realized: She didn't understand it at the time, but she's been dead for a great many years.  When she faced the demon that killed the monks, she blasted him with such a potent burst of life magic, she erased the demon magic in both her own body and that of the demon, killing them both.</p>

<p>Due to the nature of fairies (which is technically what the beings calling themselves demons in these novels are), Evie rose again in the same way Lara did in the previous book.</p>

<p>In the end, it hardly made a difference, because she'd never understood, until that morning, and the nature of her Spirit powers allowed her to freely cross the divide between the living and dead.</p>

<p>With her attachment to life fading, Evie is now ready to pass on.</p>

<p>Before she goes, she tells Riley something Evelyn told her: the woman he's been carrying a torch for feels the same, so he should marry her and have lots of kids.  He promised he'll soon have a daughter again.</p>

<p>He thanks her for that message.</p>

<p>The Hunter is sad, of course, because she'd been looking forward to visiting Evie from time to time, thinking they would be friends for thousands of years to come.</p>

<p>She tries and fails to express herself, saying, "It's a secret."</p>

<p>Evie smiles and slips back into her Chinese accent, "I ruv you, too."</p>

<p>She fades from sight, leaving a set of empty clothes behind.</p>

<p>After a scene break, the Hunter steps outside, in tears, mourning both Simmons and Evie, finally understanding the meaning of 'bittersweet'.  Looking back on her time with Reggie, however, she feels nothing but joy at having known him and the pain is gone, giving her confidence that she'll someday feel the same about Simmons.</p>

<p>Too distracted to pay attention, she bumps into a huge man in a biker's leather jacket and looks up at a squirrel's head!</p>

<h2>Part Four: Grounded</h2>

<p>Chapter 38 marks the end of Part Three and Chapter 39 will begin Part Four.</p>

<p>This part will cover the climax, in which the Hunter will face Ulmoch, leading to her capture, followed by a battle with Wrath and his arch demon wedding guests.</p>

<h2>Chapter 39: Chasing the Rabbit</h2>

<p>Ulmoch starts to tell the Hunter he's set a bomb on a timer, which will go off if she doesn't face him, only to realize, mid-sentence, he forgot to set the timer.  He tries to excuse himself, to go set it.</p>

<p>Naturally, the Hunter cuts his head off with her sword, intending to threaten him until he tells her where to find the bomb, but she's momentarily forgotten the fact such a wound won't disable Ulmoch's body (on her personal timeline, the last time she fought him was a couple years ago).</p>

<p>Ulmoch catches his head and runs off, while the Hunter gives chase.  He briefly trips on a bicycle (his head was facing the wrong way, because he was too busy talking), but loses no momentum, rolling down the sidewalk for a time.  Once his head is reattached, he leaps from one residential roof to another, while the Hunter flies after him.</p>

<p>Ulmoch uses hairpin turns to avoid her, while subtly navigating his way toward a low-rent area of Alice Springs.  He's more dexterous than she is and able to stay out of reach.  She tries using fire magic from her hands to turn better and starts to catch up, only for Ulmoch to accelerate, as if he's intentionally staying just out of reach.</p>

<p>Finally, he goes in a straight line and the Hunter thinks she's got him, only for him to drop between houses and enter one. She overshoots and smashes her way in through the front window, sending a hail of sharp fragments into Ulmoch!</p>

<p>He rolls sideways and ends up next to an old, hand-cranked record player, which is ready to go.  He starts it up and it crackles in the background as the Hunter catches him by the neck and slams him into the wall, putting her sword very near his eye.</p>

<p>She's so angry, her eyes glow an intense, blue shade.</p>

<p>Ulmoch surrenders and says he'll show her where the bomb is, if she'll let go of him.</p>

<p>She puts him down and he instead reaches into his jacket at high speed, yelling, "Psych!"</p>

<p>He produces the jar of liquid he's been saying he got as a present for her and throws it at the ceiling, where it smashes, causing the liquid to spatter down on the both of them!  It's LSD, by the way.  Nearly a whole pint of the stuff.</p>

<p>While Ulmoch sort of just accepts the high with pleasure, the Hunter stumbles around as the room becomes more colorful and spins around her, as if her head were mounted on a swivel.</p>

<p>She mutters, "It's a secret?" followed by her inner demon using her lips, "What the-" she finishes by cursing.</p>

<p>The next scene is inside the Hunters mindscape, where rainbows pieces the perpetual smoky shadows, chasing them away, while the sun shines from under the feet of the Hunter and Insanity.</p>

<p>Years of carefully maintained self-control by the Hunter erodes under the onslaught of the drugs, forcefully drawing her two halves together, where they splash and merge, like droplets of molten metal, reforming as a single individual.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Sogliun has been watching the house from the other side of the street and is really surprised to see it melting like wax, while every color of light shines from within.  He analyzes the magic of the air, finding nearly every form of it he recognizes, though Void and Life magic are most prevalent.</p>

<p>He growls, "Ulmoch, what did you do?"</p>

<p>We switch back to the young woman having her first drug experience, but I pointedly don't refer to her as the Hunter.  In fact, she struggles with the very question of who she is.</p>

<p>She stands in a sunny field of grass and flowers, with rainbows flying like birds, surrounded by a landscape that's singing along to the song <em>White Rabbit</em>, by Jefferson Airplane.  The flowers sing soprano, the sun and rainbows are tenors, the stars of the sky sing alto and the ground itself produces a pleasant bass.  She initially thinks the cartoonish landscape is beautiful.</p>

<p>The song refers to Alice from <em>Alice's Adventures in Wonderland</em> and she comes to believe her name is Alice and the story her mother read to her as a child is her own story, while the memories that crawl around inside her skull, like ants, obviously are not her own (memories of the Hunter and Insanity).  That's a little hint that Alice is a brand-new personality, brought on by a drug overdose.</p>

<p>Having solved the identity issue, she looks at her magic clothes, which have gone absolutely berserk in response to her thoughts and feelings, unable to settle on a style or color.</p>

<p>She says, "Stop that" and her clothes settle on a long, blue dress with a white apron, a pair of fingerless, elbow-length gloves and a blue, silk top hat, while her hair turns blond and hangs loose.</p>

<p>She finally notices a pair of items in either hand, including a bit torn from a white mushroom cap and a bottle of dark liquid, labeled, 'DRINK ME'.</p>

<p>Feeling an urge to eat, Alice goes with the flow and bites into the mushroom.  As a result, she grows quite large.</p>

<p>From Sogliun's perspective, the house explodes into melted droplets as Alice shoots through the roof and the reality-warping power she's manifested rolls outward, spreading her reality-warping physical hallucination to the neighborhood!</p>

<p>Humans run in every direction and even Sogliun seeks distance, because he doesn't want to be caught up in it.</p>

<p>Naturally, he blames Ulmoch.</p>

<p>Alice decides she doesn't like being large and takes a swig of 'DRINK ME'.  It tastes mostly of fruit, but she can pick out a little turkey dinner mixed in.  She shrinks just as fast as she grew, ending up shorter than the grass, beside a caterpillar smoking from a hookah.</p>

<p>The Ulmoch-become-caterpillar asks, "How high am I?  This is like nothing I've ever seen!  Is this real or is reality as high I am?"</p>

<p>Realizing she overshot, Alice nibbles on the mushroom and returns to approximately normal size, finding herself standing beside a small apple tree covered in green apples, with a golden one near the top.</p>

<p>The dream-like beauty fades as the landscape turns hostile (the LSD is finally getting through her skin and her trip is turning bad, as a result) and the flowers grow fangs, trying to bite her ankles, though that doesn't matter, because she's wearing boots.</p>

<p>The rainbows, on the other hand, become a deadly problem as they swoop at her, their edges cutting her like razor blades!  Seeking to defend herself, she calls up the Hunter's wakizashi and deflects them.</p>

<p>As she fights, the landscape changes to a chess board on which a battle between the red and white armies takes place!  She realizes the rainbows were actually the men fighting and they only cut her by mistake.</p>

<p>The Red Queen screams, "Off with their heads!" to encourage her men and Alice, being in a drug-induced suggestible state, swings her sword as she spins like a ballerina.</p>

<p>The Ulmoch/caterpillar has apparently changed size along with her and loses his head to her twirl, complaining, "Oh, come on!  I thought we were finally getting along!"</p>

<p>She grabs Ulmoch's caterpillar head out of the air before he can catch it and hauls it out of reach.</p>

<p>The song reaches the last line and she takes it as an instruction.  Looking on the severed caterpillar head, she finds herself looking into the eyes of her own severed head.  She grabs the golden apple from the tree and forcefully rams it into the head's mouth, incidentally shattering teeth in the process.  With the stem facing toward her, she plucks it off and hurls the head away, because instinct tells her something energetic is about to happen.</p>

<p>Ulmoch's head sails out of the reality distortion and returns to normal.  So does the high-explosive anti-personnel grenade she called up from the Hunter's arsenal, which is inside his mouth.  It explodes and Ulmoch is sent home, where it takes him weeks to heal properly.  It was such a bad trip for him, he stays sober for three full months.</p>

<p>Feeling sick, Alice pukes, while the LSD dribbles form her clothes as they magically self-clean.  She finally lays down, to sleep off the high.</p>

<p>Solgiun notes the unreality bubble reversing course and it eventually vanishes, leaving most everything as it was before it appeared.  He reluctantly enters the house and finds Wrath's intended out cold, so he calls for pickup, quite surprised that Ulmoch actually succeeded in knocking her out.</p>

<h2>Chapter 40: Final Preparations</h2>

<p>Alice is captured by Wrath's minions, but in the process of getting her on a pallet with a binding circle on it, her hat falls off.  One of the demons tries to pick it up.  The hat eats them, both as the means to defend itself, but also to gain some extra energy.</p>

<p>Under normal circumstances, the Hunter's father, Jake, gets the energy he needs to maintain the pocket dimension inside the hat from the Hunter, but when the hat is separated from her, he's on his own, so he uses the traces of demonic magic available to him to consume any demon that dares to touch it.</p>

<p>He needs the extra energy, lest he be forced to start discarding things stored inside, as he once did in 1972, throwing out dinner rolls to maintain sufficient energy.</p>

<p>In the next scene, Lara arrives at Riley's home, who tells her the Hunter left an hour earlier.</p>

<p>Lara summons Mashu'ra and he directs her toward the hat.</p>

<p>Alice arrives (still unconscious and captured) at Wrath's abandoned mine base, where Lust gets to work positioning the pallet holding her, in preparation to separate her human and demon sides.</p>

<p>In the background, Gluttony prepares the wedding feast (summoned imps), while a trussed-up justice of the peace awaits being of service, probably followed by being eaten.</p>

<p>Wrath makes arrangements for the other arches to be summoned and the wedding dress is brought in.  Lust tries to remove Alice's clothes, but fails, complaining that they must be glued on. Wrath gives it a go, literally trying to tear them off her, but only tears a small portion, which rapidly repairs itself.</p>

<p>Seeing the magic clothes at work, Lust suggests leaving them be (magic clothes aren't easy to make and can be very useful).  Wrath asks her to put the wedding dress on Alice over them.</p>

<p>Wrath heads off to get dressed and get his hair done, for the first time, ever.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Lara arrives at the old wrecked house and puts on the Hunter's hat, surprised by the fact it has turned blue.</p>

<p>She uses the tracking curse Verda put on the Hunter and her hat in 1972 to learn the direction and distance to Alice.  Next, Lara grows bat wings and flies off (with Mashu'ra in her body, the animal forms she can use are limited to mammals).</p>

<h2>Chapter 41: Three for the Price of Two</h2>

<p>Alice finally wakes and looks around at the room, which has all seven arch demons in it.  She tries to leave, because it isn't her kind of scene, only to burn herself on the interior of the one-way force field produced by the binding circle.</p>

<p>She looks down and sees the wedding dress, but doesn't quite make the connection that she's the bride.  She's a little slow on the uptake, like a stoner normally is.</p>

<p>She notes the tuxedo Wrath is wearing and finally realizes she's at a wedding.  She looks down again and realizes she's supposed to be the bride.  The arches laugh at her exclamation of frustration.</p>

<p>She tries to escape with magic, but she's unable to accomplish anything.</p>

<p>Wrath orders her to hold out her left hand and she reasons she can't win, so she goes with the flow and obeys.</p>

<p>Wrath puts the enchanted engagement ring Lust made on her finger, resulting in Alice exploding into a cloud of black smoke.</p>

<p>Switching to Lust's perspective, she's surprised to see not two figures forming from the smoke, but three.  She's also somewhat bothered by her slowly-growing conscience, because she helped put her jailer (the Hunter/Alice) in this position.</p>

<p>Her calculations are all wrong and with three personalities instead of two, none of them will end up inside a binding circle.  She decides that with the plan so far off the rails, it's time to leave, but as she heads toward the exit, Gluttony sends three of her bodyguards after Lust, presumably to kill her.</p>

<p>Seeing no better option for survival, Lust plays into the desires of Greed, who's always had a thing for her, and buddies up to him, using a considerable share of charm magic to wrap him around her little finger.  It's a game she doesn't want to play, but it's better than the alternatives; Greed wishes to possess her, but the others likely want her dead for political reasons.</p>

<p>Nonetheless, manipulating the feelings of a man doesn't sit well with her, because she actually feels guilty about it.</p>

<p>The three figures solidify at the corners of a triangle, free, rather than on the two binding circle pallets that stood ready to catch them.</p>

<p>One is the mutated cat form of Insanity at full-strength, wearing the wedding dress, as planned.  The Hunter's human form is next, but she immediately collapses.  The last is Alice.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_writing.html'>writing</a>, <a href='tag_work-in-progress.html'>work-in-progress</a>, <a href='tag_ashen-blades.html'>ashen-blades</a></p>

<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://owentyme.us/blog/work-in-progress-16-she-seeks-peace-8-october-28-november-1.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/blog/./work-in-progress-16-she-seeks-peace-8-october-28-november-1.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Owen Tyme</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 05:50:52 -0500</pubDate></item>
</channel></rss>
