<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel><title>Tymely News</title><link>https://owentyme.us/blog/index.html</link>
<description>Straight from Owen Tyme's keyboard</description><language>en</language>
<lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 15:54:34 -0500</lastBuildDate>
<pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 15:54:34 -0500</pubDate>
<atom:link href="https://owentyme.us/blog/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<item><title>
Shame On Me, I Guess, Part III
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>Despite my earlier posts regarding how much I dislike the social-media-platform-that-shall-remain-nameless, I got used to using it as an additional platform on which to toot my horn and gain some fans.</p>

<p>I had hoped to reach a larger audience, but now regret my choice to use that website for more than just an experiment.</p>

<h2>What Happened?</h2>

<p>I released <a href="../books/ashen-blades/demon-for-president.html">Demon for President!</a>, which is a political satire piece, in which a demon runs for President of the United States.</p>

<p>I posted about it a few times via a science-fiction and fantasy group that I'd taken a liking to, which requires <strong>manual approval</strong> for all posts before they're shown publicly.  The group admin had no issue with what I was doing and approved.  He often hit like on my posts in the past, as well.  Not that one, but political satire isn't everyone's cup of tea, so fair enough.</p>

<p>Then yesterday, the social-media-platform-that-shall-remain-nameless pulled every last one of my posts to the group over a supposed rule violation for "fraud and deceptive practices".  The group admin was absolutely mystified by this, because he knew as well as I that I wasn't deceiving anyone.  Any human being that read my posts would have come to the same conclusion.</p>

<p>The software (probably AI) that the social-media-platform-that-shall-remain-nameless uses to moderate literally cannot tell the difference between language related to selling a political satire book and an attempt to get people to vote for a non-existent demon that's running for president.</p>

<p>The absurdity of this is actually quite astonishing to me.</p>

<p>Based on the message that was shoved in my face over this unjust enforcement of their rules, they literally claim the rules for their website are not just enforced by software, but that no human being was even involved in checking the software's work.  I have no option to appeal and no opportunity to seek for this to be made right.</p>

<p>In short, they must have fired their human moderators and replaced them with software as a result of their worship of the almighty dollar and desire to cut costs all the way to the bone.</p>

<p>Yes, companies exist to make a profit, but long-term profits have never been found by tying up the end-user, so they can't resist (monopolistic practices), dropping drawers and squatting down on the end user's face (disrespecting the user), followed by defecating into their screaming, open mouth (expecting them to take whatever is dished out, no matter how vile).</p>

<p>That is a disgusting state of affairs, which can only lead to further injustice and it's simply bad business.  Period.</p>

<p>It's also a matter of squashing people's right to voice themselves.  Yeah, I know, the first amendment doesn't apply, because they own the website, not the government, but squashing people's rights has never been a good business decision in the long run, because the users will leave like rats bailing from a sinking ship, sooner or later.</p>

<h2>What Now?</h2>

<p>I will never use the social-media-platform-that-shall-remain-nameless again, not even for an experiment.  My page there will remain up for another month or two, just to give the people I'm leaving behind a chance to see what happened and point the way to greener pastures.</p>

<p>I doubt they'll follow, but I'll at least have the satisfaction of knowing I've done the right thing by trying to raise the warning flag.</p>

<h2>Alternatives?</h2>

<p><a href="https://joinmastodon.org/">Mastodon</a> is a wonderful social media platform that I can't praise enough, which mimics the interface of the social-media-platform-formerly-known-as-twitter.  I've been welcomed by the people that use it, the platform itself treats me with respect and the rules for the server I use are really quite short and straight to the point.  I've been using it about the same amount of time as the social-media-platform-that-shall-remain-nameless, but I've had far more success there.</p>

<p><a href="https://mastodon.social/@OwenTyme">Here's my Mastodon profile, in case you're interested.</a></p>

<p>I've also recently discovered <a href="https://join-lemmy.org/">Lemmy</a>, which is a decentralized forum system that operates similar to Mastodon, based on the same underlying technology (<a href="https://activitypub.rocks/">ActivityPub</a>).  I'll probably be using this in the future, but I've also been considering using <a href="https://www.reddit.com/">Reddit</a>, because it has a larger user-base.</p>

<h2>Pulling Back the Curtain...</h2>

<p>The social-media-platform-that-shall-remain-nameless is Facebook, by the way.  It's been said before and I'm sure it will be said many times more, but the company isn't worth trusting.  Their business practices are atrocious and the only reason they haven't failed is because they're so huge, with so many users, no one can stand the idea of leaving their family and friends behind, even though they'd like to stop using that website.</p>

<p>My suggestion: it's time to walk away.  Sometimes, you just have to cross the bridge and then burn it down before the vicious wolves nipping at your heels can reach you.</p>

<p>I should have stuck to my original opinion and never bothered with Facebook, but that's where the people are and I was just trying to promote my novels.</p>

<p>From now on, I'll remember this lesson and hopefully this article series won't get a fourth entry, because that really would be embarrassing for me.  "Shame on me", indeed.</p>

<h2>What I'll be Doing</h2>

<p>Facebook effectively tried to censor one of my books, so would anyone be interested in reading <a href="../books/ashen-blades/demon-for-president.html">"The Novel Facebook Tried to Silence!"</a>  Somehow, I suspect that's a line that will sell books...</p>

<h2>Evidence and What I Left Behind</h2>

<p>I wish I had screenshots of the posts Facebook removed, but I've got nothing left of most of them due to Facebook wiping them out.</p>

<p>Facebook wiped out at least three promotional group posts (once again, I remind you that these <strong>required</strong> admin approval to be shown) related to <a href="../books/ashen-blades/demon-for-president.html">Demon for President!</a>.  First was a short post with just the cover and a description of the book, mostly word for word copied from the back cover text, along with the book's cover</p>

<p>Second, I used my ad flyer, which shows off the Republican and Democrat personas of the villain of the book, along with I believe more or less the same text as the previous post.  I may have added a little blurb to describe the series, but I'm not sure.</p>

<p>Last of all was a post offering free Ebooks in exchange for honest reviews.  It was only tangentially related to <a href="../books/ashen-blades/demon-for-president.html">Demon for President!</a>, in that it displayed the cover of it.</p>

<p>There was no act of fraud and no intent to deceive anyone in any of this, despite Facebook's unjust claims of such.  I was just trying to promote my most recently published novel and get some much-needed reviews, as any self-published author would.</p>

<h3>Post #1: Reconstructed Book Announcement</h3>

<p>This is as close as I can get to the original text of the post I made announcing the publishing of <a href="../books/ashen-blades/demon-for-president.html">Demon for President!</a>.  I can't guarantee the text is 100% as it was, but this should be quite close, because most of it was a copy+paste from the same sources and it was just a re-arranged and expanded version of one of my Mastodon posts:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Book #3 of Ashen Blades, Demon for President! is now available for pre-order, coming to online bookstores June 10, 2024: <a href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/demon-for-president.html">https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/demon-for-president.html</a></p>

<p>When a snake demon in an expensive, tailored suit takes an irreverent stab at American Presidential politics, the Hunter is literally forced to take a stab at him, to save the USA from getting a Demon for President!</p>

<p>The Hunter’s demonic arch-nemesis, Vogerath, returns to Earth once more, but this time, he’s running for President of the United States, on the 2024 ballot! Worse yet, the demon’s unique power to be in multiple places at once allows him to convincingly pretend to be identical twins, running as both a Republican and Democrat!</p>

<p>The other candidates all drop out of the race under mysterious circumstances and with his best competition being himself, he’s practically assured a win!</p>

<p>Soon, the American people are lapping up the snake-in-a-suit’s every word as if it were ambrosia, calling out his name at every turn, magically charmed to believe he’s the best thing since sliced bread, despite the checkered, criminal history of his “family.”</p>

<p>Hard pressed to get rid of him, the half-demon Hunter and her allies kill him repeatedly, but he pops back up like a bad weed, making all of his appointments on time, photogenically kissing babies, cutting the ribbons of stores and donating laundered blood-money to charitable causes.</p>

<p>Will the hunter manage to end the demon’s presidential campaign before election day? If she doesn’t, the USA may just get a Demon for President! Buy this book today and find out for yourself!</p>

<p><img src="../images/Cover-Full-DemonForPresident.jpg" alt="" title="" /></p>
</blockquote>

<h3>Post #2: The Flyer</h3>

<p>Days later, I finally came up with a proper flyer for the book, along with some ad text I was happy with.  I can't recall the text for this one, but I think it was nearly identical to the previous post, because I was rather tired at the time and in a lazy mood.  I think it was posted on June 8th, but it might have been the 9th.  I'm not sure.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><img src="../images/Flyer-DemonForPresident.jpg" alt="" title="" /></p>
</blockquote>

<h3>Post #3: The Review Request</h3>

<p>I'm lucky I saved the text of the last of my censored posts, because I intended to use it elsewhere (and yes, that giveaway code is still good):</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>FREE Ebooks!  Use the code 'P6YFQ' via this link to get free Ebooks of my novels: https://www.smashwords.com/profile/view/OwenTyme</p>

<p>If you use this code, then please write an honest review as soon as you've read each book.  The truth is I really do need the reviews, just to prime the pump a bit.  After all, almost no one will take a chance on a book with no reviews.</p>

<p>Please post reviews to the sites you usually buy from, because most online book sellers, including Amazon and Barnes and Noble, will allow you to post a review without making a purchase.</p>

<p>All of my currently published novels are available to you, including Troll Song, Forgotten Legends, The Third Wish, She Hunts Demons, She Goes to War and Demon for President!  My always free short stories are also available, including Emergent Consequences and She Goes to Summer Camp.  So, yes, my entire catalog of works are free to you through June 30th, after which the code expires.</p>

<p>Here are some examples of sites on which you can write reviews (each link should point to a list of my published works):</p>

<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?i=digital-text&amp;rh=p_27%3AOwen+Tyme&amp;s=relevancerank&amp;text=Owen+Tyme">https://www.amazon.com/s?i=digital-text&amp;rh=p_27%3AOwen+Tyme&amp;s=relevancerank&amp;text=Owen+Tyme</a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/45452178.Owen_Tyme">https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/45452178.Owen_Tyme</a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.barnesandnoble.com/s/%22Owen%20Tyme%22">https://www.barnesandnoble.com/s/%22Owen%20Tyme%22</a></p>

<p><a href="https://fable.co/author/owen-tyme">https://fable.co/author/owen-tyme</a></p>

<p><img src="../images/special/review-request-june-2024.jpg" alt="" title="" /></p>
</blockquote>

<h3>What the Admin Posted</h3>

<p>You can find the post from the admin of the group here: <a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/scififan/permalink/8044035455647552/">https://www.facebook.com/groups/scififan/permalink/8044035455647552/</a></p>

<p>And because I want as much of the evidence out of Facebook's hands as possible, here's a screenshot of the message, including the screenshot he posted and was confused over, along with my comment:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><img src="../images/special/what-the-admin-said.jpg" alt="" title="" /></p>
</blockquote>

<p>Note the other comment: another witness of the awful over-reaching of the rules, along with willful ignorance of other infractions.</p>

<p>To summarize: no one asked for this unjust enforcement of rules, no one is happy about it and even the admin of the group is mystified about why it happened!</p>

<h3>What the Admin Asked Me</h3>

<p>The admin also reached out to me.  Here's a screenshot of our brief conversation on the matter:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><img src="../images/special/what-the-admin-asked-me.jpg" alt="" title="" /></p>
</blockquote>

<p>At the time he reached out, I was only aware my review request post had been taken down (I suspected it was because of the use of "we" in the image), but after answering him I dug a little deeper, finding three or possibly four of my posts were gone, all related to the political satire piece, so I think that was the real cause.</p>

<h3>Post #4: The Goodbye Post From My Facebook Page</h3>

<p>Finally, here's a quote from my last post on Facebook, for the sake of preservation, in case it gets censored just like my group posts about my novel:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I'm done with this social media platform.  I don't like the way they enforce their rules (all done with software, with no human to review what the software does, plus no one can appeal to a human over unjust rule enforcement by that software).</p>

<p>They've unjustly applied their rules to me on multiple occasions, sometimes due to over-zealous software that can't grasp the subtleties of human communication and other times because of a literal bug in their software that got me slapped with rule violations for an ad I didn't even run, the form for which was auto-populated by their own software.</p>

<p>Yes, I'm serious: the software filled the form and then punished me for the content of it, before I could even change it.
I'm tired of how broken this website is.  Period.
So, I won't be posting here anymore.  I'll leave the page up for now, to get the word out, but when I'm ready (probably in a month or two), it will come down.</p>

<p>If you still want to follow my work on a social media platform, try my Mastodon profile, which is where I'm most active: <a href="https://mastodon.social/@OwenTyme">https://mastodon.social/@OwenTyme</a></p>

<p>Alternatively, you can bookmark my website and visit from time to time, because I update it often: <a href="https://owentyme.us">https://owentyme.us</a>
My website includes a blog you can subscribe to with an RSS reader: <a href="https://owentyme.us/blog/">https://owentyme.us/blog/</a></p>

<p>Finally, if you just want to chat with me, my E-mail address has always been public: <a href="&#109;&#x61;&#105;&#x6C;&#x74;&#x6F;:o&#119;&#x65;&#x6E;&#116;&#x79;&#x6D;&#x65;&#64;&#111;&#x77;&#101;&#110;&#x74;&#x79;&#109;&#101;&#46;&#117;&#x73;">o&#119;&#x65;&#x6E;&#116;&#x79;&#x6D;&#x65;&#64;&#111;&#x77;&#101;&#110;&#x74;&#x79;&#109;&#101;&#46;&#117;&#x73;</a></p>

<p>Good luck to all of you that are staying behind.  I'm sure the rule-enforcement bots are coming for you next, since we apparently live in a dystopian future ruled by robots.</p>
</blockquote>

<h2>Final Thoughts</h2>

<p>Sorry this post is far longer than my typical blog entry, but I wanted to both express my feelings and set aside some evidence of Facebook's shameful behavior for the sake of warning others.</p>

<p>I hope you learned something of value from my experience, because perhaps that would make it all worth it.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_social-media.html'>social-media</a>, <a href='tag_social-media-platform-that-shall-remain-nameless.html'>social-media-platform-that-shall-remain-nameless</a></p>

<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://owentyme.us/blog/shame-on-me-i-guess-part-iii.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/blog/./shame-on-me-i-guess-part-iii.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Owen Tyme</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 15:42:03 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
New Release: Demon for President!
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>I'm delighted to announce the release of a new book!  The third volume of <a href="../books.html#ashen-blades">Ashen Blades</a>, <em>Demon for President!</em> is now available as an Ebook!</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><span class="book-cover">
<a href="https://books2read.com/DemonForPresident"><img src="../images/Cover-DemonForPresident.jpg" alt="" title="" /></a> <br />
<a href="https://books2read.com/DemonForPresident"><button class="buy" style="display: inline-block; width: 100%; max-width: 200px;">Buy This Book</button></a>
</span>
The Hunter's demonic arch-nemesis, Vogerath, returns to Earth once more, but this time, he's running for President of the United States, on the 2024 ballot! Worse yet, the demon’s unique power to be in multiple places at once allows him to convincingly pretend to be identical twins, running as both a Republican and Democrat!</p>

<p>The other candidates all drop out of the race under mysterious circumstances and with his best competition being himself, he's practically assured a win!</p>

<p>Soon, the American people are lapping up the snake-in-a-suit’s every word as if it were ambrosia, calling out his name at every turn, magically charmed to believe he’s the best thing since sliced bread, despite the checkered, criminal history of his “family.”</p>

<p>Hard pressed to get rid of him, the half-demon Hunter and her allies kill him repeatedly, but he pops back up like a bad weed, making all of his appointments on time, photogenically kissing babies, cutting the ribbons of stores and donating laundered blood-money to charitable causes.</p>

<p>Will the hunter manage to end the demon's presidential campaign before election day? If she doesn’t, the USA may just get a Demon for President! Buy this book today and find out for yourself!</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="../books/ashen-blades/demon-for-president.html">There's also a promotional page for this book, which includes links to political pins you can buy.</a></p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_ashen-blades.html'>ashen-blades</a>, <a href='tag_novel.html'>novel</a>, <a href='tag_publishing.html'>publishing</a></p>

<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://owentyme.us/blog/new-release-demon-for-president.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/blog/./new-release-demon-for-president.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Owen Tyme</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 08:05:12 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Stickers of the Hunter
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p><span class="book-cover"><a href="https://rajohns.work/product/little-miss-secret-lms-die-cut-stickers-3-per-sheet/"><img src="../images/stickers/the-hunter.jpg" alt="" title="" /></a> <br />
<a href="https://rajohns.work/product/little-miss-secret-lms-die-cut-stickers-3-per-sheet/"><button class="buy" style="display: inline-block; width: 100%; max-width: 329px;">Buy a Sticker</button></a>
</span></p>

<p>Ryan Johnson, the artist that does my book covers, sometimes also does little tie-in products that can be picked up from <a href="https://rajohns.work/shop/">his store page</a>, like the prototype sticker imaged here, which he kindly sent to me so I could see how they'd turn out.</p>

<p>The currently sold version omits the text and just shows the Hunter/Little Miss Secret/LMS.</p>

<p>Personally, I hope to see other artistic tie-ins to my work in the future.  I even get a little money from each sale, since they're based on my writing.</p>

<div style="clear: both;"></div>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_ashen-blades.html'>ashen-blades</a></p>

<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://owentyme.us/blog/stickers-of-the-hunter.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/blog/./stickers-of-the-hunter.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Owen Tyme</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 18:31:21 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
The Third Wish, in Ebook and Print!
</title><description><![CDATA[

<blockquote>
  <p><span class="book-cover">
<a href="https://books2read.com/b/TheThirdWish"><img src="../images/Cover-TheThirdWish.jpg" alt="" title="" /></a> <br />
<a href="https://books2read.com/TheThirdWish"><button class="buy" style="display: inline-block; width: 100%; max-width: 200px;">Buy This Book</button></a>
</span>
Plagued by horrific nightmares, the consequences of war and reeling from the loss of his family, the Steel Wizard, Levi Jacobs copes by throwing himself into work, but old enemies gain the power to travel through time, refusing to give him a moment to grieve. Making matters worse, an impatient and violent alien pirate lurks in orbit.</p>

<p>Far from friendly, the alien pirate is boiling with rage over several massive blows to his pride at the hands of humanoids. Unable to kill those responsible, instead he plots revenge on their child, Levi, and everyone around him, to regain face in the eyes of his own kind, for whom personal pride is literally everything, including social ranking and the right to rule.</p>

<p>While Levi's busy dealing with the pirate, a deposed prince scours history for allies, putting together a frightening misfit team of spies, dangerous trolls and wizards that all have a grudge to settle with Levi and his family. Intent on changing history to suit themselves, they strike at the foundations of the present, threatening to kill Levi's father at a pivotal moment on which the history of the galaxy hangs.</p>

<p>Will Levi solve this mess and move forward with his life or will he buckle under the responsibility of protecting both what he has and what he's lost?</p>
</blockquote>

<p>I'm very pleased to announce that book three of <a href="../books.html#wizards-scion">The Wizard's Scion</a>, <a href="../books.html#the-third-wish">The Third Wish</a> is now available for 3.99 in Ebook or 18.99 in paperback (US dollars).</p>

<p>I hope you'll enjoy it as much as I did!</p>

<p><a href="https://books2read.com/TheThirdWish"><img src="../images/Flyer-TheThirdWish.jpg" alt="" title="" /></a>  </p>

<div style="clear: both;"></div>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_ashen-blades.html'>ashen-blades</a>, <a href='tag_novel.html'>novel</a>, <a href='tag_publishing.html'>publishing</a></p>

<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://owentyme.us/blog/the-third-wish-in-ebook-and-print.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/blog/./the-third-wish-in-ebook-and-print.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Owen Tyme</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 18:55:20 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
New Stores For My Books!
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>There's recently been some interesting developments for me in regards to where fans can find my novels and short stories online.</p>

<h2>Bookshop.org</h2>

<p>I recently learned my print books are for sale on <a href="https://bookshop.org/contributors/owen-tyme">bookshop.org</a> at the prices I set, which is a rare thing to see (most online stores carrying my books mark them up to insane prices).  After asking on Mastodon about it, I learned its a reputable online store, so I've added it to my multi-store book links.</p>

<p>I quite like the site, because not only is it extremely highly rated, but it also helps support small book stores by sharing the profits of online sales with them.</p>

<p>Due to how much people seem to love the site, I've moved it to the head of the list of reputable stores where you can buy my books.</p>

<p><a href="https://bookshop.org/contributors/owen-tyme">Bookshop.org</a> is now my favored online store for purchasing print copies of my books.</p>

<h2>Fable.co</h2>

<p>Draft2Digital (the platform I publish through) recently added a new online Ebook store for distribution that looks absolutely amazing to me, because it's a combination of an Ebook store and an online book club host.</p>

<p><a href="https://fable.co/author/owen-tyme">Fable.co</a> is a site I'm seriously thinking of giving a whirl, because it looks like I could setup a book club centered around my own novels.</p>

<p>Sadly, Fable doesn't yet show up in my multi-store links, but I'm hoping Draft2Digital will update their system to allow this, soon.</p>

<p>Still, it's another interesting online destination and a very promising-looking site.</p>

<h2>In Conclusion</h2>

<p>I would now suggest you pick-up print copies of my books from <a href="https://bookshop.org/contributors/owen-tyme">bookshop.org</a>, because some of the money filters down to local book stores.</p>

<p>Despite the wonderful addition of Fable to the mix, my favorite store for Ebooks is still <a href="https://www.smashwords.com/profile/view/OwenTyme">Smashwords</a>, because the Ebooks they sell can be used on any device of your choosing and I happen to get fatter profits from sales there (the parent company of Smashwards is Draft2Digital, so there's only the one middleman).</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_publishing.html'>publishing</a></p>

<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://owentyme.us/blog/new-stores-for-my-books.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/blog/./new-stores-for-my-books.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Owen Tyme</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 18:06:44 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
She Goes to War, Now in Print!
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>The second volume of the <em>Ashen Blades</em> series, titled <em>She Goes to War</em>, is available in print!  In addition, <em>She Goes to Summer Camp</em>, the short story included in <em>She Goes to War</em>, is available both as a free Ebook and in print.</p>

<p>If you want to own both, buy the novel.  If you want to get a free taste of the Ashen Blades series, claim your free copy of <em>She Goes to Summer Camp</em> today!</p>

<h2>She Goes to War</h2>

<blockquote>
  <p><span class="book-cover">
<a href="https://books2read.com/b/SheGoesToWar"><img src="../images/Cover-SheGoesToWar.jpg" alt="" title="" /></a> <br />
<a href="https://books2read.com/SheGoesToWar"><button class="buy" style="display: inline-block; width: 100%; max-width: 200px;">Buy This Book</button></a>
</span>
The Hunter never wanted to go to war, but in 1972, she senses the return of her demonic arch-nemesis, Vogerath, to the world. Following his magic like a bloodhound, she finds herself inexplicably drawn to Vietnam, a war zone.</p>

<p>With a pressing need to kill Vogerath, who claims to be the serpent from the Garden of Eden, the half-demon Hunter is joined by her detective partner, Clayton Simmons, and a powerful witch, Verda Bagley.</p>

<p>It was meant to be a simple search and destroy mission, but nothing in the jungles of Vietnam is ever simple and their plans go off the rails the moment the Hunter sets foot on the ground. She’s overcome by the magic of the jungle, which causes her to forget her humanity and transform into a great, black cat with blue eyes!</p>

<p>Her team are forced to subdue her, to bring her back to her senses, but the consequences of her instinct-driven actions leave them troubled, because she killed a demon disguised as an American soldier and his best friend wants revenge! As this fresh, unwanted conflict comes to a close, the Hunter’s hands are reluctantly stained with human blood.</p>

<p>Vogerath’s jungle hideout is surrounded by soldiers and the raid begins, but the Hunter’s plan continues to go wrong. After a unit of tanks is overrun, the US military throws everything they’ve got at the demons, inadvertently playing into Vogerath’s hands! The demon grows stronger with each attack and awaits the power of a nuclear strike, planning to use it to open a portal to Hell, so endless legions of demons can march forth to conquer the Earth!</p>

<p>Will the Hunter and her friends stop Vogerath in time or will the world be conquered by demons? Buy this book today and find out!</p>

<p>Includes a bonus novella: She Goes to Summer Camp, in which the Hunter faces the most unthinkable and horrifying of challenges: teenagers.</p>
</blockquote>

<h2>She Goes to Summer Camp</h2>

<blockquote>
  <p><span class="book-cover">
<a href="https://books2read.com/b/SheGoesToSummerCamp"><img src="../images/Cover-SheGoesToSummerCamp.jpg" alt="" title="" /></a> <br />
<a href="https://books2read.com/SheGoesToSummerCamp"><button class="buy" style="display: inline-block; width: 100%; max-width: 200px;">Free Story</button></a>
</span>
Camp Sapphire Friendship, a summer camp for teens, was the last place the Hunter wanted to go, but she'd made a vow to protect humanity from demons, no matter where they appeared and in 1986, her team of demon-slaying experts is called on to investigate. However, to make things even worse, the Hunter's team leader sends her into the camp as an undercover operative, under the guise of a regular teen, despite the fact that the half-demon girl being old enough to be the grandmother of the kids at camp.</p>

<p>She's soon caught up in the daily minutiae of camp, learning a few new things along the way, while followed around like a puppy by a new "friend", a motor-mouthed girl that never shuts up. On the very first day, she also acquires a trio of teenage foes in the form of some valley-girl sisters from Los Angeles, who take every opportunity to insult and plays pranks on her.</p>

<p>However, despite the innocent look of the place, danger lurks around every corner, because the owner of the camp, Miss Macie Weber, is an untrained witch, whose unknowing, haywire magic threatens to kill everyone by summoning powerful and vengeful nature spirits, on top of the demons already lurking among the humans at camp!</p>

<p>Will the Hunter find and slay the the demons or will the nature spirits take offense at her mere presence, because she's had the Jungle Spirit stuck inside her head since 1972?</p>

<p>Download today and find out!</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_ashen-blades.html'>ashen-blades</a>, <a href='tag_novel.html'>novel</a>, <a href='tag_publishing.html'>publishing</a></p>

<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://owentyme.us/blog/she-goes-to-war-now-in-print.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/blog/./she-goes-to-war-now-in-print.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Owen Tyme</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 17:20:42 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
She Goes to War, Coming April 5th!
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>The second volume of the <em>Ashen Blades</em> series, titled <em>She Goes to War</em>, is now available for pre-order as an Ebook.  The print edition still has a few details to work out, but should be available soon.</p>

<p><em>She Goes to War</em> will be available on April 5th, 2024!</p>

<p>This one is special to me, because a friend of mine that fought in Vietnam talked me into writing it and then served as my primary source of information on the jungles of Vietnam.  According to him, I hit the nail on the head and the details of the setting are as close to perfect as they can be.</p>

<p>I hope you'll enjoy it!</p>

<p>Due to how serious and emotionally difficult this novel was to write, I decided to pair it with a rather humorous bonus novella, <em>She Goes to Summer Camp</em>, in which our stalwart heroine goes undercover at a summer camp where teens have gone missing four years in a row, in search of the demon responsible, but nothing could have prepared her for the horrors of dealing with teenagers.</p>

<p>When final arrangements for art are complete, <em>She Goes to Summer Camp</em> will also be released as a short story as part of my <em>Short of Tyme</em> collection.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><span class="book-cover">
<a href="https://books2read.com/b/SheGoesToWar"><img src="../images/Cover-SheGoesToWar.jpg" alt="" title="" /></a> <br />
<a href="https://books2read.com/SheGoesToWar"><button class="buy" style="display: inline-block; width: 100%; max-width: 200px;">Buy This Book</button></a>
</span>
The Hunter never wanted to go to war, but in 1972, she senses the return of her demonic arch-nemesis, Vogerath, to the world. Following his magic like a bloodhound, she finds herself inexplicably drawn to Vietnam, a war zone.</p>

<p>With a pressing need to kill Vogerath, who claims to be the serpent from the Garden of Eden, the half-demon Hunter is joined by her detective partner, Clayton Simmons, and a powerful witch, Verda Bagley.</p>

<p>It was meant to be a simple search and destroy mission, but nothing in the jungles of Vietnam is ever simple and their plans go off the rails the moment the Hunter sets foot on the ground. She’s overcome by the magic of the jungle, which causes her to forget her humanity and transform into a great, black cat with blue eyes!</p>

<p>Her team are forced to subdue her, to bring her back to her senses, but the consequences of her instinct-driven actions leave them troubled, because she killed a demon disguised as an American soldier and his best friend wants revenge! As this fresh, unwanted conflict comes to a close, the Hunter’s hands are reluctantly stained with human blood.</p>

<p>Vogerath’s jungle hideout is surrounded by soldiers and the raid begins, but the Hunter’s plan continues to go wrong. After a unit of tanks is overrun, the US military throws everything they’ve got at the demons, inadvertently playing into Vogerath’s hands! The demon grows stronger with each attack and awaits the power of a nuclear strike, planning to use it to open a portal to Hell, so endless legions of demons can march forth to conquer the Earth!</p>

<p>Will the Hunter and her friends stop Vogerath in time or will the world be conquered by demons? Buy this book today and find out!</p>

<p>Includes a bonus novella: She Goes to Summer Camp, in which the Hunter faces the most unthinkable and horrifying of challenges: teenagers.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_ashen-blades.html'>ashen-blades</a>, <a href='tag_novel.html'>novel</a>, <a href='tag_publishing.html'>publishing</a></p>

<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://owentyme.us/blog/she-goes-to-war-coming-april-5th.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/blog/./she-goes-to-war-coming-april-5th.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Owen Tyme</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 14:22:46 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Character Feature: Otto Vogerath (AKA Pride)
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p><img src="../images/characters/AshenBlades-OttoVogerath.jpg" alt="" title="" /></p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Three AI-generated images of Vogerath.  In all three images, he wears a gray suit and blood-red power tie.</p>

<p>(Left) A shot focused on just the head of the man and he smiles evilly, very pleased with himself.  There's fresh blood on the wall behind him.</p>

<p>(Middle) A wider-framed shot, in which he's still smiling, but the grin isn't quite so wide and the blood on the wall is more smeared than spattered.</p>

<p>(Right) The blood on the wall is long dry and Vogerath has dropped the Illusion of humanity he normally portrays, revealing his true nature as a snake demon.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><span class="book-cover">
<a href="https://books2read.com/b/SheHuntsDemons"><img src="../images/Cover-SheHuntsDemons.jpeg" alt="" title="" /></a> <br />
<a href="https://books2read.com/SheHuntsDemons"><button class="buy" style="display: inline-block; width: 100%; max-width: 200px;">Buy This Book</button></a>
</span>
Otto Vogerath may be many things, including a German man that supposedly came to the states before the Nazis took over Germany, the ring leader of a circus, an abusive husband and father, a criminal, a mob boss, a mass-murderer, a mad genius plotting world domination, but all of that pales in comparison to his true identity: Otto Vogerath is one of the seven Arch-demons that rule Hell, where he's known as Pride.</p>

<p>He's very intelligent and often runs mental circles around his opponents, treating them almost like puppets dangling from strings, continually manipulating them into doing <em>exactly</em> what he wants.  In that regard, he's playing a grand-scale game of chess, while his opponents think they're playing a simple hand of go-fish for no stakes, when in fact, the stakes couldn't be higher.</p>

<p>Even when he appears to be losing, he's usually accomplishing something of lasting value to his long-term goal of galactic domination or just possibly, taking over Hell.  What <em>really</em> motivates him is a mystery to all others, but he'll never give anyone a straight answer.</p>

<p>Vogerath is extremely old, having been born before the dawn of humanity, which makes it <em>almost</em> believable when he claims to be the Serpent from the Garden of Eden.</p>

<p>Whether that's true or not, however, he <em>is</em> the living embodiment of Pride, literally believing himself to be a cut above all others, his greatest flaw.</p>

<p>However, when his plans start falling apart, making him look the fool, he can be extremely dangerous and unpredictable.</p>

<p>When his life is on the line, he becomes a total coward, because in his mind, he's the most important person in the multiverse, bar none.  Therefore, leaving his minions to die while he escapes is perfectly acceptable.</p>

<p>Vogerath is the arch-nemesis of <a href="character-feature-little-miss-secret.html">Little Miss Secret</a>, because he's responsible for murdering her parents.  His mysterious plans revolve around the girl, because he has need of the unique powers of a half-demon. He may even be responsible for arranging for her to be born.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_ashen-blades.html'>ashen-blades</a>, <a href='tag_character-feature.html'>character-feature</a></p>

<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://owentyme.us/blog/character-feature-otto-vogerath-aka-pride.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/blog/./character-feature-otto-vogerath-aka-pride.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Owen Tyme</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 19:31:50 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Special Feature: On Magical Elements
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p><img src="../images/special/AshenBlades-TheElements.jpg" alt="" title="" /></p>

<blockquote>
  <p>A collage of AI generated images representing the various elements, laid out as a cohesive chart of the elements.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>All users of magic in the <a href="../books.html#ashen-blades">Ashen Blades</a> series use a system of metaphors for classifying magic in to manageable categories and these categories are not always the same, varying by culture.</p>

<p>Witches use a system based on four basic material elements, including Air, Fire, Earth and Water, as well as two basic elements representing polar opposite energies: Life and The Void.  Various other elements formed by combining the basic elements together.</p>

<p>During <a href="../books.html#she-hunts-demons">book one</a>, the witches call Life 'Spirit', but Spirit is actually a sub-element of Life magic, a conclusion <a href="character-feature-verda-bagley.html">Verda Bagley</a> arrives at during book two.</p>

<h2>Material Elements</h2>

<p>The four material elements represent all physical materials in the known universe, with the exception of difficult to classify materials, such as dark matter, which science doesn't even understand.</p>

<p>Mastery over any material element allows shaping it and levitating it, with magic that mimics telekinesis.</p>

<h3>Air</h3>

<p>The air, representing not just the breathable gasses, but all gasses, to a certain extent, as well as air currents and weather.</p>

<p>Air is a difficult element to master and witches that bear a natural talent with it can be quite dangerous when they lose control of their emotions, leading to shifts in weather outdoors, or poltergeist-like activity, indoors.</p>

<p>Isabel Grant and <a href="character-feature-verda-bagley.html">Verda Bagley</a> are witches that wield Air magic.</p>

<h3>Fire</h3>

<p>Fire represents the more energetic elements of nature, but isn't considered a destructive influence, because the materials produced by the action of Fire are still useful to living processes.</p>

<p>Fire includes the fourth state of matter, plasma, and nuclear reactions.</p>

<p>Fire is one of the easiest elements to learn and untrained witches with a talent for it are unfairly feared, though in truth, Fire magic is actually quite safe, following guidelines similar to the real thing: it takes effort to start a fire and a large lapse in judgment for a controlled flame to get out of control.</p>

<p>Annmarie Nosset and her daughter, <a href="character-feature-little-miss-secret.html">Little Miss Secret</a>, are witches that wield exceptionally hot Fire magic.</p>

<h3>Earth</h3>

<p>Earth represents the ground we walk on and the processes that take place within it, including tectonic forces and volcanism (though fire is also involved in that).  Hurling rocks with this form of magic is relatively easy, but shaping dirt and stone takes time and dedication to master.</p>

<p>Earth is relatively easy to get started with, because clay can easily be used for training exercises.  However, witches with a natural talent for Earth can sometimes become quite terrifying to deal with, if their emotions get out of control, leading to earthquakes and other upheavals of the earth.</p>

<p>To a lesser extent, Earth also represents all solid matter.</p>

<p>Isabel Grant is a witch that uses Earth magic.  In book two, <a href="character-feature-clayton-simmons.html">Simmons</a> demonstrates some ability to use Earth magic.</p>

<h3>Water</h3>

<p>Water is absolutely essential for all known living processes and users of Water magic can be exceptionally dangerous, because Water can readily be shaped into cutting and impaling attacks.</p>

<p>Water magic is quite difficult to master and rarely goes out of control, because wielding it requires supreme level of control or the water will simply go back to doing what it normally does.</p>

<p><a href="character-feature-verda-bagley.html">Verda Bagley</a> is a witch that uses Water magic.</p>

<h2>Energetic Elements</h2>

<h3>Life</h3>

<p>Life is what binds all the other elements together, allowing them to combine in infinite complexity.  It's also absolutely essential to all living processes.</p>

<p>There are many sub-classes of Life magic and it takes in many things that don't readily fit in other elements, including curses and counter-curses.</p>

<p>Paradoxically (see below, regarding The Void), demons use a sub-class of Life magic to infiltrate the minds and hearts of humans: Spirit magic.  This allows them to arrive on Earth in spiritual form, whispering inside the minds of mankind, until they convince the human to taint their own soul with such a heavy burden of sin, the demon takes possession of both their soul and body.</p>

<p>Life is <a href="character-feature-verda-bagley.html">Verda Bagley's</a> strongest element as a witch, making her an expert on curses, counter-curses and healing magic.  In book two, she also demonstrates knowledge of what's largely considered the dark-side of Life magic: Necromancy, which may be a Void-touched off-shoot of Life magic, though this is debatable, because Necromancy can be used to return a dead thing to life.</p>

<h3>The Void</h3>

<p>The Void represents the forces of death and entropy.  It's ever hungry to consume the multiverse, breaking it all back down until there's nothing left but The Void.  Void magic readily combines with the material elements, transforming them into mocking parodies of themselves.</p>

<p>The only known direct use of Void magic is for spatial manipulation, including teleportation and the formation of a pocket dimension.</p>

<p>For teleportation, it normally has to be paired with another element, to form a doorway.  Form example, <a href="character-feature-little-miss-secret.html">Little Miss Secret</a> uses Void magic combined with Shadow magic to teleport from shadow to shadow, a spell known as shadow-stepping.  How this works is particularly strange: the Void magic user simply steps out of the entire multiverse, and steps into The Void.  From there, they then step back into the multiverse, at the place of their choosing.  Hypothetically, it might be possible to travel through time the same way.</p>

<p>Demons all tap Void magic to one extent or another.</p>

<p><a href="character-feature-little-miss-secret.html">Little Miss Secret</a> uses Void magic, which she got from her demonic ancestry.  Her Top Hat contains a pocket dimension that stores most of the things she owns.</p>

<h2>Secondary Material Elements</h2>

<p>The secondary material elements are formed by combining adjacent material elements.  These can be neatly categorized as scientific and natural elements.</p>

<h3>Smoke</h3>

<p>Smoke is the combination of Air and Fire, usually coming into being when Wood is burned.  While it has its place in the natural world, its considered a scientific element, having been extensively, shaped, controlled and shackled by mankind.</p>

<p><a href="character-feature-little-miss-secret.html">Little Miss Secret</a> makes extensive use of Smoke magic mixed with Shadow magic to conjure the weapons stored in her hat into her hands.</p>

<h3>Metal</h3>

<p>Metal is the strongest of the scientific elements, because most metals aren't found in their pure form in nature, requiring Fire to forge Earth into something different from the two.</p>

<p>In book two, <a href="character-feature-clayton-simmons.html">Simmons</a> is stated to have been studying Metal magic.</p>

<h3>Wood</h3>

<p>Wood magic is difficult to master, but gives power to manipulate plants in myriad ways, accelerating growth or granting power to move to these normally slow forms of life.</p>

<p>Wood is one of <a href="character-feature-verda-bagley.html">Verda Bagley's</a> strongest elements.</p>

<h3>Animal</h3>

<p>Animal magic allows manipulating animal life of all kinds, including humans.</p>

<p>Most demons use some measure of Animal magic, because their first form is almost always that of an animal.</p>

<p><a href="character-feature-mashura.html">Mashu'ra</a> uses this form of magic to transform the body of <a href="character-feature-clayton-simmons.html">Simmons</a>, giving him great strength and durability.</p>

<p>In book two, <a href="character-feature-verda-bagley.html">Verda Bagley</a> demonstrates some very minor Animal magic, allowing herself to see in the dark, much like a cat.</p>

<p>Master Lagrow, the wizard that was Master of the Ashen Blades in <a href="../books.html#she-hunts-demons">book one</a>, uses a very narrow class of Animal magic combined with Life magic to enact curse-like spells on living beings, fooling them into believing he's their friend and ally.</p>

<h2>Void-Touched Elements</h2>

<p>The Void-touched elements are all a combination of another element and The Void, leading that element closer to the end of all things.</p>

<h3>Vacuum</h3>

<p>Vacuum is the absence of Air, which can be quite damaging to unprotected living things.</p>

<h3>Shadow</h3>

<p>Shadow is Smoke that has lost its substance, leaving behind nothing but darkness that blots out the light.</p>

<p><a href="character-feature-little-miss-secret.html">Little Miss Secret</a> makes extensive use of Shadow magic to conjure her weapons into her hands, in combination with her Smoke magic.  She also combines it with Void magic, to teleport from shadow to shadow.</p>

<h3>Ultraviolet</h3>

<p>Ironically, combining Fire magic with the energy of the Void increases the power of the flame until its capable of consuming almost anything, producing a temperature so high, the flame glows in the ultraviolet spectrum.</p>

<p>Effectively, the ultraviolet flame has the endless hunger of the Void, seeking to burn all until there's nothing left.</p>

<p><a href="character-feature-little-miss-secret.html">Little Miss Secret</a> learned to produce a UV flame just after seeing her mother use high-intensity blue flames, effectively combining her witch and demon powers into the most intense spell in her magic arsenal.</p>

<h3>Poison</h3>

<p>Derived from Metal and Void, poison represents anything that's toxic to animals, even including substances that are normally safe or even essential for life, but can be lethal if the dose is high enough, such as salt.  Much of the toxins in the world are metals in one form or another, hence the close relationship with it.</p>

<p>This category of magic also includes any form of corrosive magic.</p>

<h3>Ash</h3>

<p>Ash is Earth that's been scorched so hot it loses all useful qualities, becoming inherently dangerous, choking out life.  It takes time and the application of other elements to revitalize volcanic ash, but it can eventually become fertilizer.</p>

<h3>Bone</h3>

<p>Strangely, bone is the combination of Wood and Void.  When all life leaves wood, the bark falls away and the bleached, dead wood starts to resembles bone.</p>

<p>Bone magic can only manipulate the skeletal structures of formerly living things, leading to such abominations as walking skeletons with no will of their own.</p>

<h3>Ice</h3>

<p>Water that loses most of its energy freezes and loses its life-giving qualities.  Thus, ice is the combination of Water and Void.  Ice magic is easy to master in snowy or arctic environments, but far less common in warmer climates.</p>

<h3>Blood</h3>

<p>Originally considered a form of Necromancy, but later categorized as a corruption of Animal magic by The Void, Blood magic allows the manipulation of living blood.  It's one of the most lethal forms of magic, allowing human bodies to be torn apart from the inside-out, regardless of skill level.</p>

<p>Witches with a natural talent for blood magic are often surrounded by carnage worked by their own, out of control emotions and the more carnage they see, the more out of control their emotions become, until they accept their power or self-destruct as they internalize the realization they're responsible for all the deaths they've seen their power inflict on others.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, those that survive the trauma of such power coming to the surface usually become serial killers, thinking it gives them the right to be judge, jury and executioner.</p>

<p>Blood magic can be used to heal the body, but the malign uses far outweigh its benefits to society.</p>

<p>Whether it's just or not, Blood witches are feared and hunted by nearly all other witches, because they're too powerful to control and it's too easy for them to kill with an errant thought.</p>

<h2>Additional Elements</h2>

<p>This list is hardly exhaustive and there's a myriad of ways to combine the elements that aren't easy to display on a chart.  For example, Steam magic is a combination of Fire and Water.</p>

<h2>Other Elemental Systems</h2>

<p>All of this is simply a useful set of metaphors to aid understanding.  In addition to this system, demons also use their own systems of metaphors:</p>

<p>The most common system demons use relates everything to the various substances in the human body, including blood, bile, urine, bone, muscle, etc.  That system sounds very messy and is very unappealing to non-demons.  Demons, on the other hand, love it, because it suits their sick-minded nature.</p>

<p>The next most common approach relates the whole of creation to the seven deadly sins.  Noble demons tend to favor this system, because it pays homage to the seven arch-demons that rule Hell.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_ashen-blades.html'>ashen-blades</a></p>

<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://owentyme.us/blog/special-feature-on-magical-elements.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/blog/./special-feature-on-magical-elements.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Owen Tyme</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 14:17:28 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Character Feature: Verda Bagley
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p><img src="../images/characters/AshenBlades-VerdaBagley.jpg" alt="" title="" /></p>

<blockquote>
  <p>An AI generated image of Verda Bagley, in 1945.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><span class="book-cover">
<a href="https://books2read.com/b/SheHuntsDemons"><img src="../images/Cover-SheHuntsDemons.jpeg" alt="" title="" /></a> <br />
<a href="https://books2read.com/SheHuntsDemons"><button class="buy" style="display: inline-block; width: 100%; max-width: 200px;">Buy This Book</button></a>
</span>
Verda Bagley is an ally of <a href="character-feature-little-miss-secret.html">Little Miss Secret</a>, <a href="character-feature-clayton-simmons.html">Simmons</a> and <a href="character-feature-mashura.html">Mashu'ra</a>.  She's also a field operative of the Order of Ash and Smoke with a lot of experience.</p>

<p>She's one of the most powerful witches in the world, but ironically doesn't consider herself to be one, instead thinking of herself as simply 'talented'.</p>

<p>She's a mother to her very core and uses nursery rhymes as a concentration aid to focus her mind for spell casting.  She can often be heard singing in combat, to keep her mind from wandering.</p>

<p>She appears to be in her twenties, but is actually in her forties during <a href="../books.html#she-hunts-demons">She Hunts Demons</a>.  It isn't explicitly stated until book two, but her aging process has been unnaturally slowed by her magic.</p>

<p>She hates the common labels that come with her magic and only puts up with being called a witch, because that's the convenient term used by the others in the Order.</p>

<p>She also doesn't believe the creatures the Order fights are actually demons, because according to the beliefs of her religion (The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter Day Saints), demons don't have physical bodies, having been denied that opportunity when they rebelled against God, before the world was.</p>

<p>Instead, she considers them evil monsters that need to die, because their actions are the darkest kind of evil.  Her theories about the demons are not well accepted by the Order, but toward the end of the book, she gains some indirect evidence she was right all along, leading her to conclude the so-called demons are actually Unseelie Fairies.</p>

<p>Like LMS, she absolutely hates demons that prey on children and will go out of her way to put them down.</p>

<p>As a witch, her best elements are Spirit, Water and Wood, but she also has a little mastery of Air and in book two, she starts experimenting with Animal magic.  She's an expert on curses of all varieties and she often works to counter curses planted by demons.</p>

<p>Her favorite spells involve manipulating tree roots and branches to attack enemies or forming water into barriers or weapons.  She also sometimes uses reversed curses, a technique she learned by observing the action of the protective spell surrounding Little Miss Secret.  These are effectively delayed-action curses she places on herself that affect the first person to attack her.</p>

<p>Verda is the expert <a href="character-feature-little-miss-secret.html">Little Miss Secret</a> consulted when she was looking to counter the curse she lives with.</p>

<p>Aside from her magic, she fights with a shotgun and she's almost never without her switchblade, because sometimes magic fails.</p>

<p>Her best attributes are a keen intellect and a creative approach to any situation, both of which she can use in the heat of combat, with a cool and level head.  Like Simmons and Little Miss Secret, Verda isn't one to give up easily and always has a new trick up her sleeve, whether it's magic or not.</p>

<p>She's extremely adverse to the idea of leaving behind or abandoning a friend and she'll go to great lengths to rescue them, almost regardless of the danger.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_ashen-blades.html'>ashen-blades</a>, <a href='tag_character-feature.html'>character-feature</a></p>

<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://owentyme.us/blog/character-feature-verda-bagley.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/blog/./character-feature-verda-bagley.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Owen Tyme</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 20:16:07 -0500</pubDate></item>
</channel></rss>
