<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel><title>Tymely News</title><link>https://owentyme.us/blog/index.html</link>
<description>Straight from Owen Tyme's keyboard</description><language>en</language>
<lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 04:55:55 -0500</lastBuildDate>
<pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 04:55:55 -0500</pubDate>
<atom:link href="https://owentyme.us/blog/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<item><title>
Work In Progress #6: Troll War #6 (July 29-August 2)
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>This is part six of my series on my work in progress novel, <a href="../books.html#troll-war">Troll War</a>, which centers around a kingdom of trolls going to war with a kingdom of dwarves, all because a pair of corrupt nobles from a third kingdom were bored and curious to see which race would come out on top.</p>

<p>You can read <a href="../books.html#troll-war">a short description of Troll War</a> to learn more or you can read <a href="https://mastodon.social/@OwenTyme/112672253855096568">short summaries of each day's writing, on Mastodon</a>.</p>

<p>Here's links to the rest of my blog entries on <a href="../books.html#troll-war">Troll War</a>, in chronological order:</p>

<ol>
<li><a href="work-in-progress-1-troll-war-june-21-28.html">June 21-28</a></li>
<li><a href="work-in-progress-2-troll-war-2-july-1-5.html">July 1-5</a></li>
<li><a href="work-in-progress-3-troll-war-3-july-8-12.html">July 8-12</a></li>
<li><a href="work-in-progress-4-troll-war-4-july-15-19.html">July 15-19</a></li>
<li><a href="work-in-progress-5-troll-war-5-july-22-27.html">July 22-27</a></li>
</ol>

<h2>Part Three: The Drama</h2>

<p>The week began with the start of Part Three, which is the final part.  The intent now is to get my main characters together for one last climactic battle, just in time for the star ship <em>Terror of Vok</em> (the ship of Captain Vendros) and a warship from the machine swarm to show up in orbit, producing a brilliant pyrotechnic display in the night sky, because they'll be pulling no punches.</p>

<p>That should be just enough proof to finally sway the Queen of Utros, Nepita, into finally making peace, but as always, any plans I make are tentative, because my characters often do things I don't expect.</p>

<p>It's ironic, because you'd think I'd know what's going to happen, but once I set a character's personality, I have to honor that or the story would totally lose the suspension of disbelief, for violating a character's internal thought processes.</p>

<p>It's a lot of fun for me, though, because I find out, chapter by chapter.  I may not know the overall plot and climax until I've fully cemented character personalities in my mind, giving me some measure of ability to predict their actions, but they often do the very last thing I would have predicted, once I sit down to write.</p>

<p>There was an example of this in my writing this week, in Chapter 25, that played into some dangling plot threads I setup in chapter 1, which I hadn't known how to make use of until then.  I'll explain more, below.</p>

<h2>Chapter 25: Shout of Ruin</h2>

<p>The recently formed Oswil-Fortune Fields Alliance, which I like to refer to as OFFA, has blockaded the trolls in their own lands on their east and north borders, while they also have other enemies to the south and west, which are currently too frightened of Nepita's ten-for-one vengeance policy to attack.  These would be the gnomes (probably to the south, but won't matter until the next book), goblins (south-west, most likely) and the dark fairies (definitely to the west, which will become important next week).</p>

<p>OFFA has strengthened their defenses around Fort Freybell, which became a point of contention between Fortune Fields and Utros during the recent failed peace talks.</p>

<p>In particular, the local portion of the blockade features dwarves on the front line, because they have more experience with melee combat, including a unit of demon-riders powered by tamed fire elementals.</p>

<p>Behind them, there's Oswil soldiers with rifles, since they're better shots than dwarves.</p>

<p>The third line back is composed of cannons and Gibson-guns (very much like a Gattling-gun; since this is a fantasy world with parallels to our own, I've chosen to replace the names of firearm manufacturers with names that start with the same letter, so things will be somewhat familiar, without every detail needing to be exactly the same) serve as artillery.</p>

<p>The back line is composed of Oswil battle-mages, who happen to be elves.  These are also Oswil Army.</p>

<p>Fort Freybell is somewhat behind the blockade line, set on a hill.  It's more or less an old, medieval-style castle of dwarf construction that the dwarves abandoned when the local mine petered out.  It has some minor strategic value, but only because it's on the trade road between Fortune Fields and Utros.</p>

<p>Illa stands on a hill behind OFFA lines, with Kadrek beside her, wearing heavy armor and carrying a huge tower shield, so he had protect them both from bullets.  Illa's intent is to counter the magic of the trolls, because she has the greatest knowledge of how it works, leaving everyone else free to retaliate.</p>

<p>Hidden among the trees of another hill, some distance away, are Sureshot, Brosla and her men.  She's got her old rifle back (turns out the one Corporal Logan offered her is the very same she used in the 108^th^) and has decided to face her demons head on, now that she knows the root cause of her battle fatigue (an old term for PTSD).  Her orders are to shoot the troll leaders as soon as the battle begins.</p>

<p>Trolls march toward their position with the intent of breaking through, to kill the battle-mages before they really get going.  Prince Yetu (Nepita's son), Anji and several other trolls climb a hill opposite Illa's hill, just as the battle begins.</p>

<p>Sureshot has a brief conversation with Brosla about Anji, because she knows she shot the woman in the temple, a wound that should have killed her.  Brosla looks though a pair of binoculars he obtained form his ship, confirming what she sees.  She concludes the woman is a female troll and so is Illa, who she only knows as Leona Conway, which she now considers an assumed name.  She vows to have a word with Illa, just as soon as she can, because she's angry.</p>

<p>The demon-riders are finally demonstrated in battle, covering themselves and their weapons in jets of flame as they wade into the troll lines, decimating them as they go.  Cannons fire grapeshot (cannon balls linked by chain) into the troll lines, while the Gibson-guns produce a hail of bullets.  Initially, things go badly for the trolls.</p>

<p>Sureshot shoots Anji between the eyes and Yetu freaks out, because the troll woman's presence makes him feel safe.  At his lowest moment, Illa uses her magic to touch his mind, offering him the chance to surrender, with the promise he won't be harmed.</p>

<p>Coming to realize she's become a traitor (he recognizes her voice in his mind), Yetu allows himself to feel a deep-seated rage against troll women for the first time in his life, directing all of it at Illa.</p>

<p>He screams, "Get out of me head!"</p>

<p>His magic rages out of control and latches onto his vocal cords as he subconsciously uses a forbidden spell that female trolls have been murdering male troll wizards over, since the world was seeded with life by the gods.</p>

<p>His raging magic births an invisible, sentient spell known as a Shout of Ruin, which kills with sonic strikes.  It inherits his hatred of Illa and crosses the battlefield, shattering metal objects, just to test its power, destroying weapons on both sides of the battle, though it gets stringer with each group it hits.  It cracks the armor of the demon-riders, ruins troll and OFFA rifles, alike, but when it reaches the Gibson-guns, they explode into shrapnel.  When it passes by Kadrek, his armor and weapons explode, badly injuring him!</p>

<p>It finally comes face to face with Illa, who's studied the Shout of Ruin, because she'd once considered it her best option for revenge on Nepita, though she hadn't been able to produce one, having not realized the spell was effectively alive.</p>

<p>However, having been in telepathic contact with Yetu's mind as he produced it, she learns the technique and counters the deadly spell with one of her own, using her rage against Nepita to produce it.</p>

<p>There's a tremendous clash of sound as the two sentient spells battle for dominance and try to consume each other.  The eardrums of the trolls burst and the beeswax in the ears of OFFA soldiers (a precaution to counter the mental magic the trolls have been using since the beginning of the war), begins to melt, so they clasp their hands over their ears, to keep it in.  The ground begins to quake and a distant mountainside produces an avalanche.</p>

<p>Sureshot is far enough away that she's not in any real danger, though she's in tremendous pain as she aims and fires on Yetu, convinced his scream is somehow the source of the magical sound.</p>

<p>Yetu's Shout of Ruin notices the rifle slug's approach and turns its full attention to vaporizing it, because protecting its master is one of its primary motives.  This gives Illa's Shout the opportunity to consume it.</p>

<p>There's a brief moment in which Illa expects her victorious Shout to kill Yetu, but it doesn't happen.  Instead, it focuses on the goal of killing Nepita, beginning a long journey to the Utros Palace, the results of which are covered in the next chapter.</p>

<p>Illa uses telekinetic magic to turn the broken fragments of Kadrek's armor into high-velocity, spinning blades, launching them at Yetu in a pattern like a shotgun.  One of the fragments punctures a lung and the young troll goes down, totally unable to speak or scream, preventing him from producing another Shout.</p>

<p>Anji sits up and orders her men to retreat, because a second troll army is on the way.  The intent was always to rotate though troll armies, giving them time to regenerate between battle, while the defenders are slowly whittled down.  She has high hopes they'll soon break through the OFFA lines.</p>

<p>She notes the fact that Yetu used forbidden magic without knowing it, but in so doing, he also demonstrated his loyalty.  Anji hopes to appease Nepita and prevent the young wizard's death, though his fate is currently unknown, even to me.</p>

<p>The Shout of Ruin was the element that I totally hadn't been expecting in this chapter, totally catching me by surprise and which neatly tucks into the dangling plot threads established in Chapter 1.  The specific threads I'm referring to are Prince Yetu having magic talent and Yera (who has the mind of Nepita's Grandmother in her head) waiting for an opportunity to strike against Nepita.</p>

<h2>Chapter 26: Weakness</h2>

<p>Nepita arrives at the Abomination Barracks with Yera right on her heels, to have a word with Aketa about her unit's battle readiness.  She watches Aketa eating a fried chicken, briefly amused, because the burn-scarred troll has been made an integral part of the war-rider captured during Part One, with her muscles and tendons attached to the control systems of the war machine, giving her extremely fine control over it.</p>

<p>Aketa and her men are eager for battle, because Aketa claims they desire to prove themselves.  The real truth, however, is that Aketa wishes to throw herself into battle in the hopes of finally dying, because she has no desire to live the life of suffering she's enduring, all because Nepita selfishly refused to allow her to die.</p>

<p>Nepita steps out of Aketa's quarters and senses incredible magic.  She concentrates to be able to see it, observing a ball of magic that's headed right for her, though she's surprised it isn't Yera's spell.</p>

<p>She produces a mental echo-location burst and discovers the attacking spell has a mind of its own, so she immediately mentally attacks it, just barely managing to stop it dead in its tracks, while it claims, <em>Illa sends her regards!</em></p>

<p>Yera laughs and claps, because Nepita is now vulnerable.  Being a villain of the classic, gloating type, she monologues, calling Nepita weak, then reveals who she really is (Grandmother) and how she came to inhabit Yera's body: her personal attendant offered up her body after Grandmother's body was damaged so badly even troll regeneration would likely fail to repair it.  Grandmother wiped the woman's brain and then telepathically moved her mind into the new body, a technique she's been using for a <em>very</em> long time, since she's been around as long as Utros (hundreds of years).</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the other rush to aid Nepita, since Aketa and the abominations are loyal, but Aketa's body obeys the woman's commands and the rest are stopped with a mere snap of Grandmother's fingers, the fire-retardant coating on the abominations turning as hard as steel.  When she enhanced their bodies with magic, as it turns out, she made sure they were open to being influenced by the very smallest of her spells.</p>

<p>Grandmother claims to have allowed Nepita to win their fight, so she could play the long game and steal the throne back during a moment of weakness.  She goes on to make a list of Nepita's personal failings and then finally makes a simple offer: swear eternal fealty and let Grandmother retake the throne or she'll dump even more magic into the Shout of Ruin, so it can kill Nepita.</p>

<p>Nepita suggests that Grandmother procreate with herself and Grandmother follows through on her threat.</p>

<p>As death looms ever nearer, Nepita's life flashes before her eyes, revealing to her the murky details of the first time a woman of the court tried to assassinate her, just after she was taken out of the Play Room.  She'd been pinned to a wall as the older, stronger woman strangled her, but because she wanted to hear Nepita beg for mercy, she let the child breathe, a huge mistake.</p>

<p>In the moment of white-hot rage, Nepita subconsciously tapped into Rage Song, the magic of male trolls.  She screamed with fury and the magic enhanced her vocal cords, producing a sound capable of shattering bone.  It wasn't a Shout of Ruin, which requires years of repressed feelings, but it was still forbidden, male magic.</p>

<p>With the woman's face mere inches from Nepita's mouth, her skull more or less exploded, just as Nepita's eardrums burst, because she'd lacked fine control over her magic, at the time.</p>

<p>The experience had been so traumatic, she suppressed the memory, but with it clear in her mind, she knew she had one chance to save he life, switching from telepathy to a magical scream!</p>

<p>Fortunately for her, Illa's Shout of Ruin was low on power and Grandmother had been too busy savoring her imminent victory, she hadn't quite fed it enough to overcome Nepita's scream!  Her magic cancels out the sound of the Shout, killing it, while the eardrums of everyone but herself burst!</p>

<p>Despite damage to her inner ear, due to the tremendous volume, Nepita is on Granmother before she can recover, her enchanted swords crossed against the old troll's neck.</p>

<p>There's a long, tense moment as Nepita waits for Grandmother to heal and then says this:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>When Nepita was certain Grandmother could hear her, she smiled, “Thank you for your presence making me paranoid.  I’ve been so focused on the threat you pose, I’ve beaten back my rivals and stayed strong, but this wasn’t your day and you won’t get another chance like this.” She crouched without moving her blades, until their faces were six inches apart, speaking so softly only they could have heard, “I am <em>not</em> weak, but neither am I perfect.” She switched back to a more regular volume, “Thank you for your constructive criticism.  I’ll give your words some reflection, <em>Grandmother</em>.” She straightened up, withdrew her swords, sheathed them and then barked an order to Aketa, “You and your men are on standby, until I can have a strategy meeting with the court.  Grandmother has given me much food for thought.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Nepita leaves Granmother's neck scarred by the touch of Nemesis and exits the room in high spirits, because she found the experience invigorating.  She actually whistles as she walks the halls, with Grandmother trailing behind her.</p>

<p>The implication is that Grandmother can come at her as often as she likes, but Nepita will only be made stronger by the constant paranoia, just as it has strengthened her against other court intrigue.</p>

<p>There's a brief scene from the perspective of General Hendrix, who's on the wall of Fort Freybell, watching the movements of the trolls, who have three armies in play, each the size of a regiment.  The first is nearly healed, the second just finished a stint in battle and the third is moving in to attack.  He finally realizes the trolls intend to wear them down over time, using their regenerative abilities to their advantage and calls for reinforcements, because their battle lines are already weak, due to the previous two battles.</p>

<p>In the next scene, Sureshot climbs Illa's hill, because it's too dark for her to work with a rifle at such long range.  She confronts the woman about what she is and Illa comes clean, telling her a short version of her tale.  Sureshot does seem to forgive her for the subterfuge, once she realizes how dangerous knowledge of female trolls can be.</p>

<p>However, she still takes the information to King Windmaker and General Hendrix, because they've been making long-term war plans without vital information.</p>

<p>The discussion eventually reveals that Sureshot has seen Nepita's face, because she describes what the woman's weapons did to her.</p>

<p>The General orders Sureshot to be the core of the team they're planning to send to end the war, by killing Nepita, and she accepts.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Anji arrives in the Utros palace during a strategy meeting, which is being led by both Nepita and Yera (Grandmother, though Anji doesn't know that yet).</p>

<p>Anji gets the Queen alone, telling her Illa has become a traitor and Yetu has used a Shout of Ruin.  If I had to hazard a guess, Nepita has spared Yetu's life, but can't help but imprison him as a result.  He will probably be seen again during the climax.</p>

<h2>Musings on Vokosian Concepts of Time</h2>

<p>Every chapter I write that takes place on the star ship <em>Terror of Vok</em> forces me to consider the implications of an alien culture.  For example, during Cahpter 23, The Broken Priestess, I was forced to flesh out their religion.</p>

<p>Chapter 27 (see below), forced me to take a moment to consider their use of time.  I had previously settled on a 'year-tenth' as the Vokosian equivalent to a month (used in chapter 13) and I settled on 'ten-day' as the equivalent to a week.  There are of course better words for these terms in their own language, but I'm using somewhat literal English translations for the reader, to emphasize the difference in culture.</p>

<p>The invention of the term ten-day got me thinking of time in Vokosian units, which are decimalized, but keep in mind the comparison I'm making in the following table is analogous, not equivalent, so our terms and theirs don't refer to exactly the same amount of time:</p>

<table>
<tr>
    <th>Our Time</th>
    <th>Vokosian Time</th>
    <th>True Vokosian Meaning</th>
</tr>
<tr>
    <td>Second</td>
    <td>Day-Thousandth</td>
    <td>1/1000<sup>th</sup> of a day</td>
</tr>
<tr>
    <td>Minute</td>
    <td>Day-Hundredth</td>
    <td>1/100<sup>th</sup> of a day</td>
</tr>
<tr>
    <td>Hour</td>
    <td>Day-Tenth</td>
    <td>1/10<sup>th</sup> of a day</td>
</tr>
<tr>
    <td>Day</td>
    <td>Day</td>
    <td>1 rotation of their home world*</td>
</tr>
<tr>
    <td>Week</td>
    <td>Ten-Day</td>
    <td>10 days</td>
</tr>
<tr>
    <td>Month</td>
    <td>Year-Tenth or Hundred-Day</td>
    <td>100 days</td>
</tr>
<tr>
    <td>Year</td>
    <td>Year</td>
    <td>1000 days**</td>
</tr>
</table>

<!--
  Our Time        Vokosian Time                   True Vokosian Meaning
------------    -----------------               -------------------------
  Second          Day-Thousandth                  1/1000^th^ of a day
  Minute          Day-Hundredth                   1/100^th^ of a day
  Hour            Day-Tenth                       1/10^th^ of a day
  Day             Day                             1 rotation of their home world*
  Week            Ten-Day                         10 days
  Month           Year-Tenth or Hundred-Day       100 days       
  Year            Year                            1000 days**
-->

<div id="prose" class="prose">

<p>* The Vokosian homeworld has shorter days than Earth and Alethis (name of the world in this novel), which are about 16 hours long, leading to far more days in a year.</p>

<p>** This is roughly equivalent to the time required for the Vokosian homeworld to complete one orbit, but it's not quite perfect.  Nonetheless, they still accepted the decimalization of time, to simplify their lives, while the seasons continued on their usual course.  The Vokosian year is approximately 16000 hours long, while an Earth year is 8760 hours, so the Vokosian year is almost two Earth years.</p>

</div>

<p>This approach to accounting for the passage of time should make the Vokosians feel alien, without making it hard to relate to their perspective, while allowing some simple math to work out the details, because one hour is 1.6 day-tenths.</p>

<p>Now that I've set the Vokosian calendar in my mind, I was forced to go back to chapters 13 and 16, to fix some time figures, so instead of <em>Terror of Vok</em> arriving in three year-tenths, it has become one and a half, to keep my three month timetable accurate, but that's what editing is for.  I'm always going back to add small details to match the clearer picture of the plot that I get in later stages of writing a novel.</p>

<h2>Chapter 27: The Living Bone</h2>

<p>The scene begins with the High Priestess of Vok (named Et'aell, by the way) alone in her quarters aboard <em>Terror of Vok</em>.  She's unable to get alcohol of any kind, after the public spectacle she made of herself and when people pass her in the halls, they either make signs to ward off evil or tell her to repent.</p>

<p>She's spend the majority of a ten-day alone, aside from going out to get food from the galley.</p>

<p>She's still unable to cope with the shattering of her faith, because she's come to believe that Vok is dead, based on the way most of their species has been wiped out.</p>

<p>The doorbell rings and she shouts for them to go away, but it just keeps ringing.  Eventually, it becomes knocks and finally, the door is opened by a security override.</p>

<p>Captain Vendros and his first officer step in, leading to this exchange:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“What do you want?” Et’aell demanded, half angry and half despairing.
The Captain surveyed the untidy room, which reflected Et’aell’s internal state quite well, then settled on her unkempt hair and rumpled clothes, because she hadn’t done anything to groom herself in days.  He sniffed the air and it was obvious her unwashed odor offended him.</p>

<p>Captain Vendros spoke with determination, despite what he’d just seen and smelled, “You have two choices, High Priestess.  First, you can continue to wallow in misery over your broken faith or you can do something good, because the crew needs you.”</p>

<p>“No one needs me.” Et’aell gave the Captain a defiant look and then started to cry again.</p>

<p>The first officer shook his head, “You have no idea how wrong you are.”</p>

<p>“Have you forgotten what day it is?” Vendros asked.</p>

<p>“It doesn’t matter what day it is, because Vok is dead!” Et’aell despaired, “No day is more holy than another, because there is no more holiness and all we have left is just a matter of staving off our eternal punishment for just one more day!  We’re doomed to burn in Xercil’s crematory and there’s nothing I can do about that!”</p>

<p>Captain Vendros spoke softly, “That may be what you believe, but there’s a whole crew of people on this ship that believe otherwise, who’ve gathered for a Ten-day Service that only you can lead.  <em>They</em> still have their faith.  <em>They</em> still believe.  <em>They</em> still need you.  Will you abandon <em>them</em>, just as you seem to believe you’ve been abandoned by Vok?”</p>

<p>His words were like a slap to the face.  Vok may have abandoned his people by dying, but a sense of duty welled up within her as tears poured more freely from her eyes than ever before, because she was ashamed by her own, selfish actions.</p>

<p>“I don’t believe anymore,” she admitted, “but you have a point: I don’t matter.  My calling was never about me and whether my faith is living or dead, the least I can do is go through the motions in our last days, to give the people of Vok what comfort I can, before their souls are given to Xercil.</p>

<p>“I’ll serve as this ship’s priestess and say the words they need to hear, but I don’t think I’ll ever find my faith again.”</p>

<p>“I’m sorry.  I should never have told you the truth.” Vendros bowed his head with grief.</p>

<p>“You did nothing wrong and if Vok were still among the living, he would agree.  Give me a little time to prepare, then I’ll lead the crew in a Ten-day Service.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Roused from her depression by duty, the Priestess cleans herself up, cleans and dons her vestment, then applies her ceremonial makeup, going off to lead the service, only to discover that in her absence, the crew have cleaned the chapel, top to bottom, and they've filled the pews, with more standing at the back.</p>

<p>She doesn't know it, but Captain Vendros took a personal hand in all of this, ordering the crew to clean the room and then show up.</p>

<p>While she believes herself to merely be going through the motions, she delivers a sermon and leads the service, leaving not one eye in the room dry.</p>

<p>With the morning service complete, she attends to hearing the crew speak their minds to her, in private, again doing what's expected of her, but not for her own sake.</p>

<p>When evening comes, she leads a second service for those that were on duty during the morning shift, again without a single dry eye.</p>

<p>With a day spent in service to others, fulfilling her calling, she heads back to her quarters, questioning her own lack of faith, because she could see that Vok still lives on in the hearts and minds of her flock.</p>

<p>She isn't over the blow to her faith, but she has perhaps started to heal.</p>

<p>I'm enjoying this character and the internal conflict in her heart.  I plan to use her as the leader of the survivors of the Vokosians in the second book, though I think her story will also make the sacrifice of Vendros and his crew during the climax more poignant.</p>

<h2>Chapter 28: Pushing Back</h2>

<p>Two and a half months after the near continuous battle for Freybell began, King Windmaker and General Hendrix stand on the wall of the fort, observing the battlefield as good men die to hold the line, more or less by the skin of their teeth.</p>

<p>Hendrix looks north, while Windmaker looks east, each hoping to see reinforcements, because King Joshua has pulled all but the minimum of soldiers from the borders of Oswil, promising thirteen whole regiments, while Windmaker hopes to see more of his war machines, because they've done without for far too long.</p>

<p>Hendix didn't expect to see anything, thinking he's too early, but he's happy to see cavalry approaching at a gallop, having moved faster than the rest of the army!</p>

<p>Windmaker is happy to announce a unit of war machines are on the way and they're truly relieved for just one moment, but as they look at the battlefield, they're still upset to see good men dying.</p>

<p>Later on, as ten regiments from Oswil arrive at the battlefield (the other three went out to strengthen the blockade), causing the trolls to flee, Sureshot is more than happy.</p>

<p>However, it won't be easy to assault Utros, because the narrow canyon leading to Whitewall and the Utros palace is small enough a dedicated force of a hundred trolls could easily hold it, for as long as food holds out.</p>

<p>Sureshot begins a discussion with her team about their upcoming mission to assassinate Nepita and General Hendrix presents her with three enchanted bullets, Troll-Slayer rounds that are sized for her rifle, ordering her to make each one count, because the Scott and Walcott Firearms Company refuse to make any more, for fear of what the trolls might do to them.  Officially, those rounds don't exist and S&amp;W will deny all knowledge of the fact they made them.</p>

<p>Sureshot discusses her plan to approach the Utros palace from behind (from the west), followed by climbing a sheer cliff wall, so she can summit the mountain and then drop down on the other side, to enter.</p>

<p>Illa suggests an alternative, using a secret passage the dwarves don't know about that leads to her old quarters, which used to belong to her Grandmother, then insists she has to go with, because the valley the secret door opens on is a graveyard for fallen troll royals, who never died peacefully and are therefore restless.  She claims they won't harm troll royalty or anyone under their protection.  Kadrek insists on going if his wife is going.</p>

<p>Sureshot initially refuses to bring the couple, because they died in her vision of the future, but Brosla manages to convince her that he'll keep all three of them safe.</p>

<p>King Windmaker challenges his ability to do so, but Sureshot informs the King Brosla is a null and therefore able to defy fate.  Hearing this, King Windmaker volunteers to join them for their suicide mission, because he wouldn't miss seeing a null in action for all the gold in the world.</p>

<p>He promises to bring his personal war-rider and a company of his royal guardsmen, because the secret door is large enough to get such large war machines through.  The plan becomes causing as much chaos as possible in the palace with the war machines, while Sureshot works to locate and kill Nepita.</p>

<p>There's also some discussion of the threat Weapon Master Anji poses to the team, based on her previous marksmanship, so Sureshot essentially vows one of her Troll-Slayer rounds will be used to put the Weapon Master down for good.</p>

<p>Sureshot's team get horses from the stable, while the war-riders are prepared for a long journey by bolting cylinders of enchanted coal to the area of their buttocks, making them look like giant dwarves with bedrolls strapped to their behinds.  This is something adapted from my time studying the Vietnam War for another novel; the U.S. soldiers that fought the war kept what little they needed in the field in a small butt-pack that hung from their belt.</p>

<p>They head north, where they'll turn west on the main road, until they reach the territory of the dark fairies.  Once there, they'll cross into fey land with the intention of making contact with the fey lords.  They plan to tell the truth, that they intend to kill the ruler of the trolls, and hope this fact will assure their safe passage.</p>

<h2>Future Plans</h2>

<p>I'll likely write Sureshot's encounter with the fey on Monday.</p>

<p>I need to write at least two more chapters from the perspective of the High Priestess, as well, so I may write one of those on Monday, to further her character growth and the revitalization of her faith.</p>

<p>Regardless, the last bit of her story will be in the midst of the climax, when all non-essential personnel will be ordered off the ship, just as the battle begins. </p>

<p>Down on the ground, all heck will break loose as Sureshot's team and Anji's best soldiers meet in Memorial Vale (the haunted valley).  That's when the sniper vs. sniper contest I've been foreshadowing will finally happen, with each of them gunning for the other, while Illa and King Windmaker go on without her.  That battle will probably start with the death of several of Corporal Logan's men, who have always been intended to serve as a plot device to demonstrate when the crap has hit the fan.</p>

<p>I hope to complete the rough draft next week, but all plans are tentative, especially considering the fact I also need to get the editing on <a href="../books.html#dark-moon">Dark Moon</a> (Book 4 of <a href="../books.html#wizards-scion">The Wizard's Scion</a>) finished, since my artist just finished the cover art.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_writing.html'>writing</a>, <a href='tag_work-in-progress.html'>work-in-progress</a>, <a href='tag_rumors-of-war.html'>rumors-of-war</a></p>

<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://owentyme.us/blog/work-in-progress-6-troll-war-6-july-29-august-2.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/blog/./work-in-progress-6-troll-war-6-july-29-august-2.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Owen Tyme</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 12:37:47 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Work In Progress #5: Troll War #5 (July 22-27)
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>This is part five of my series on my work in progress novel, <a href="../books.html#troll-war">Troll War</a>, which centers around a kingdom of trolls going to war with a kingdom of dwarves, all because a pair of corrupt nobles from a third kingdom were bored and curious to see which race would come out on top.</p>

<p>You can read <a href="../books.html#troll-war">a short description of Troll War</a> to learn more or you can read <a href="https://mastodon.social/@OwenTyme/112672253855096568">short summaries of each day's writing, on Mastodon</a>.  This series can be read <a href="tag_rumors-of-war.html">via this link</a>, though it will be in reverse chronological order, from newest to oldest.</p>

<h2>Chapter 19: Diplomatic Impunity</h2>

<p>I started the week's work by finishing this chapter.</p>

<p>After Illa's bombshell revelation about the trolls having used nothing but cloned shock troops for three years, just to soften the dwarves up (covered in the previous installment of this series), King Windmaker requests aid from Oswil.</p>

<p>Sureshot uses a telegraph crystal she brought with her to contact King Joshua.  While they wait for a reply, they chat idly about Lady Gunn and it's revealed that she and her family have been under investigation for years, due to their underhanded business practices.</p>

<p>King Windmaker is just about to reveal that Lady Gunn was the one to tell him trolls invaded his land at the start of the war, when the reply comes through, requiring Sureshot's attention.  It was funny to me, dangling the truth so close to Sureshot, only to whip it away, without her knowledge.</p>

<p>King Joshus immediately sends an entire regiment, with two more promised for the future.  He also orders Sureshot to make an alliance with Fortune Fields.</p>

<p>Windmaker and Sureshot start making plans for future battles with the trolls, in case they don't accept peace.</p>

<p>Brosla contacts Captain Vendros, who shares his message again, giving the dwarves extra incentive to make peace and King Windmaker shows a lot of curiosity about the alien machines.</p>

<h2>Chapter 20: Ceasefire</h2>

<p>Prince Yetu (son of Nepita, pronounced as 'ee-too') brings a message from the front lines to Queen Nepita, in her throne room.  He's so excited, he forgets his place and speaks out of turn, endangering his life.  Nepita publicly chastises him to appease the court, then winks at him while they're all looking at him, because in the past three years, she's grown even more fond of him.</p>

<p>In an internal monologue from Nepita, we learn that Yetu was born under circumstances similar to Illa, slightly early, with his mind open to magic, though not to the same degree.  As it turned out, he took to magic like a frog to water, soon learning to use physical magic the way Illa did, though without her around to teach him, he's had to pick that up through book learning.  He was also given Illa's quarters, since he's the only one available that can use the same magical techniques she could.</p>

<p>However, he still lacks the respect a female troll commands and his duties mostly involve all the worst tasks the women of the court can think of to dump on him, because they hate him.</p>

<p>Nepita has been visiting him in the evenings, to help with his magical training, but also just to talk, because she loves him in a way a troll woman normally wouldn't feel for a male child.</p>

<p>Still, she's planning to soon send him into battle, because his magical talents will be useful when the invasion of Fortune Fields begins.</p>

<p>Yetu reports that Oswil soldiers have taken position between Utros and Fortune Fields, putting a stop to the war.</p>

<p>Nepita is so angry, she clenches her teeth hard enough to crack one of them.  The sound snaps her out of her anger and it begins to heal.</p>

<p>Yetu tells her the reason the Oswil soldiers gave Angi: a battle was fought between dwarves and trolls on Oswil soil.</p>

<p>She turns to the court and demands, “Which of you <em>stupid fools</em> authorized that?”</p>

<p>The women of the court take a few steps back, leaving one of their own at the center of an open circle.  Nepita murders the woman on the spot for her costly mistake.</p>

<p>Yetu tells her the dwarves have committed to peace and are now requesting a ceasefire, as relayed via the Oswil army.</p>

<p>Nepita strongly believes it's all a trick.  Based on the fact that she fell back to give the dwarves the impression they were winning, she believes an outpost they recently captured, Fort Freybell, contained some hidden artifact the dwarfs were after.  Having obtained what they were after on her lands, all along, she believes they're using Oswil as an excuse to get away with it.  She's being needlessly paranoid and is totally wrong, but paranoia is a survival trait for trolls.</p>

<p>Nepita reluctantly decides to allow the attempt at diplomacy, because Oswil has forced her hand.</p>

<h2>Chapter 21: The Olive Branch</h2>

<p>Sureshot, Brosla and Prince Gorgo Windmaker, the 11th (Kadrek's brother), arrive at the Utros palace for peace talks.  At Gorgo's insistence, they're unarmed, aside from Sureshot, who brought a pair of hidden knives and a derringer, because she's not fool enough to walk into troll lands without weapons.</p>

<p>Before they set out, Illa placed a protective spell on Sureshot, mysteriously commenting, "That should keep your thoughts safe."</p>

<p>Shengis stares them down for a few minutes, which is standard procedure.  Outsiders think it's designed to make visitors uncomfortable, but the real truth is that he's waiting for Nepita to enter his mind, to take over for the negotiations.</p>

<p>Without her sword or pistols, Sureshot is extremely on edge, heightening her senses to the point she picks up on Nepita's magic as it enters the mind of Shengis.  She has no idea what it means, however.</p>

<p>The peace talks begin with introductions and statements of intent, but things soon go south: Nepita is obsessed with Fort Freybell and its meaning to the dwarves, insisting Gorog tell her what they wanted with the little outpost.  Naturally, he has no idea what she's talking about, but she doesn't believe him, threatening to make an example of him, to demonstrate what happens to those that lie.</p>

<p>Sureshot confirms their story that they came to make peace and takes the opportunity to share her king's perspective, handing over a letter of introduction to lend weight to her words.</p>

<p>Nepita more or less ends the peace talks by telling Sureshot, "You may be telling the truth, but I don’t have any reason to trust the dwarves and if your countries are allies, then Oswil is also my enemy."</p>

<p>Brosla makes one final attempt at peace by calling Captain Vendros, who tells his tale.  Nepita listens with amusement, but ultimately calls Brosla a charlatan and illusionist.</p>

<p>Brosla is angry at her words, but Nepita demands proof of his claims.  He admits he has none other than what he's given.</p>

<p>Sureshot hisses to the others, “Get ready to run!”</p>

<p>Nepita orders Gorgo shaved and stripped, then orders the others thrown in the dungeon, saying they'll be guests of the palace for the remainder of their short lives.  Nepita's magic releases Shengis, leaving him to his own devices.</p>

<p>The guards in the room approach the trio with hostile intent, so Sureshot whips out her derringer, pointing it right at Shengis, insisting the gun is loaded with a Troll-slayer bullet.  Slayer bullets are expensive, enchanted rounds designed to kill a particular species on impact,</p>

<p>She's bluffing, but Shengis orders the guards to stop.  However, they don't listen, because they know their orders came from Nepita, not Shengis.</p>

<p>Sureshot decides not to waste her only round and shouts, "Run!"</p>

<h2>Chapter 22: Escape</h2>

<p>I had a lot of fun writing this chapter, because it involved some good character development, fun action and a very unique scene with natural humor mixed in.</p>

<p>Gorgo is out the door right off the bat, but Brosla hesitates, because no one has ever pointed a gun at him!  Sureshot slaps him, shoves him toward the door and then follows him out, while bullets zip past.  Fortunately, the trolls are new to firearms and they're terrible shots (aside from Angi, but that will come much later on).</p>

<p>Out in the hall, Gorgo tackles and punches out a troll, tossing a captured rifle to Sureshot.  She whirls around and fires on one of the chasing trolls, putting a bullet between his eyes!  That action triggers her PTSD (she calls it battle fatigue), causing her vision to restrict so badly, she feels like she's looking down the scope of her old rifle!</p>

<p>She's nearly blind, so Gorgo grabs her elbow and drags her along, taking several turns, until he ditches their pursuers and then opens a secret door.  Once they're hidden inside, two groups of guards, coming from opposite directions, meet by the hidden door.</p>

<p>There's a short argument about who lost the fugitives and the troll in charge decides the other team are traitors, sending them off to the dungeon for interrogation, which is the result of troll paranoia at work.</p>

<p>When they're gone, Gorgo demands to know what happened and Sureshot explains she can't use a rifle without getting tunnel vision, a result of battle fatigue (an old west/civil war term for PTSD).</p>

<p>Sureshot asks how Gorgo knows so much about the Utros palace and he explains that the dwarves were the ones to carve it from the bedrock in exchange for gold.  In doing so, they added many secret passages to the design, just in case they ever went to war with Utros.</p>

<p>They discuss their available weapons and Sureshot offers Gorgo a knife.  He refuses, deciding to stick with his fists, which he's named 'Nasty' (right) and 'Tricksy' (left).</p>

<p>She offers the knife to Brosla, who still looks shell-shocked.  There's a short discussion of making a plan in his mind, ahead of time, to deal with the stress of combat and Brosla takes the knife.</p>

<p>Gorgo leads the way, but informs them getting out of the palace will involve going through the front doors (the only exit he's aware of).</p>

<p>Switching to Nepita's perspective, she shouts at Anji for losing the prisoners.  Ultimately, she decides to add the women of the court to the search parties, so they can use telepathic magic to echo-locate minds and she personally joins the search, enthusiastic about the task, because she hasn't had time to go hunting since the war started.</p>

<p>Back in the secret tunnels, the fugitives hear singing, so Gorgo produces a small bottle of beeswax, insisting they plug their ears, so the song magic the <em>Sanguine Sisterhood</em> uses won't affect them (he has no idea that organization of assassins are the troll women from Utros).</p>

<p>Brosla refuses, because he's immune to magic, a fact that makes Gorgo a little jealous.  Sureshot also refuses, believing Illa's spell will protect her, but Gorgo plugs his ears.</p>

<p>The troll women pass by them without noticing the minds of the fugitives, sweeping through the halls until they head outside.</p>

<p>The fugitives eventually reach the last secret door before the exit and make a plan to silently take down the pair of guards they saw stationed there on the way in.  The plan is for Sureshot to handle one, while the other two focus on the other, with Gorgo tackling and Brosla cutting the troll's throat.</p>

<p>The door is opened and Sureshot uses her rifle to choke one guard, then snaps his neck.  Gorgo tackles the other, according to plan, but Brosla hesitates and then chokes the guard out with his shin, instead of cutting his throat, because he just can't do it.  When they're done, Sureshot snaps the second guard's neck, because such severe injuries take a lot of time for a troll to heal.</p>

<p>Gorgo is disappointed with Brosla, who hands the knife back to Sureshot.</p>

<p>Knowing the doors lead to a small, one room fort, Sureshot makes the next plan, asking the men to open the door, while she prepares to shoot every troll beyond them, from the cover of a corner.</p>

<p>The doors are opened and she sees Anji, holding a rifle very much like the one she used to favor, plus six troll men.  She puts a bullet through the woman's temple, putting her down, then proceeds to wipe out the others, systematically.  Again, the poor marksmanship of the trolls is their advantage.</p>

<p>Nearly blind again, Brosla takes Sureshot's hand, while Gorgo leads the way.  They weave their way through the city, past many a witness, ending up at an alley with no obvious exit.  The dwarf pops open another secret hatch and they squeeze through.</p>

<p>Nepita arrives at the alley on short order (citizens of the city pointed the way), but not in time to catch them.  She investigates for a time, even going so far as to climb a building, but concludes there was no way they could have escaped without a secret door.</p>

<p>She kicks the ground for a time, looking for a different sound, but finds nothing.  She draws her sword, All-biter (said to be able to cut anything), and taps the wall with the hilt, listening for something unusual.  She finds nothing and slashes the wall in frustration, cutting right through the hidden hatch, which pops open as a result.</p>

<p>She scrambles inside, finding a natural cave that the dwarves modified, to make a trough down the center as it goes downhill.  There's water dripping into the trough, which is wet enough to serve as a water slide.</p>

<p>She lays down and slides away as a scream echoing up the tunnel soon confirms her suspicions.</p>

<p>The fugitives are sliding down the tunnel, Gorgo at the lead, Brosla center and Sureshot last.  She's scared by their speed.</p>

<p>I found the resulting exchange rather fun:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Sureshot: "Are you sure this is safe?"</p>

<p>Gorgo: "No, me’s sure it isn’t!"</p>

<p>Brosla (panicking): "What?"</p>

<p>Gorgo: "We should eventually end up in the underground river, but the trouble is, me don’t think there’s enough water in it to cushion our fall!"</p>

<p>Sureshot (angry and screaming): "What, pray tell, are you planning to do about that?"</p>

<p>Gorgo: "Me hadn’t really thought it through, but uncertain death is better than certain death!"</p>

<p>Brosla: "Can we slow down, before we hit the bottom?"</p>

<p>Gorgo: "Aye, that’s a good idea!"</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Gorgo uses his knees to slow them down (he's wearing plate armor) and they end up in an amusing pile-up, sitting on each other's shoulders.</p>

<p>Nepita arrives on the scene, screaming, "I've got you now, you little-" she finishes the sentence by referring to them as fatherless children.</p>

<p>Sureshot calls for more speed, while she starts trying to shoot Nepita from her awkward, laying-down position.  At the same time, Nepita tries to sing, but the ride is so bumpy, she can't stay on tune.</p>

<p>Sureshot wastes two rounds, but hits Nepita in the eye with the third, which only ticks her off (crazy sometimes just doesn't know when to quit)!</p>

<p>Nepita responds by swinging her second sword, Nemesis, which has the power to hit each individual with their own, personal weaknesses.  She isn't close enough to physically strike Sureshot, but the sword produces an incredibly powerful wave of mental magic, which blows right past Illa's protective spell.</p>

<h2>Chapter 23: The Broken Priestess</h2>

<p>This was originally chapter 24, but after writing the two chapters, I switched their order to let the tension stew.</p>

<p>Captain Vendros has been lying to his crew for weeks, just to keep their morale high.  Most of them have no idea that their ship holds the last of the Vokosian race, aside from Brosla, and that lie has been eating him up inside.</p>

<p>He decides to visit the High Priestess of Vok, that he might unburden himself in the appropriate way.  She just happened to be among the group of refugees that ran toward his ship when the machines attacked.</p>

<p>I enjoyed detailing the religion of the Vokosians, which was necessary to properly describe the Priestess.  They believe their god, Vok, is a skeleton and actually believe their own skeletons, inside their bodies, are extensions of him.  Literally, they believe they carry their god inside their bodies, everywhere they go.</p>

<p>Xercil is another mythological figure from their religion and he's very analogous to the Devil.  Xercil runs a crematorium, where he burns all the bones he can, specifically to spit in the eye of Vok.  Vokosians that sin enough believe their souls will belong to Xercil when thy die, who will punish them by using them as fuel to burn bones, for eternity.</p>

<p>An interesting point is that the ultimate punishment for criminals in Vokosian culture involves execution followed by cremation, which supposedly ensures Xercil will obtain their soul.</p>

<p>Captain Vendros realizes he's interrupted the High Priestess' evening meal, but she doesn't mind.  She asks him to wait a moment, so she can dress properly for the ritual he seeks to use.</p>

<p>When she returns, she's dressed all in white, with her face painted like a skull, so she can more reasonably serve as a stand-in for Vok.  That is the true purpose of the priests of their religion, who are there to listen to whatever is on the mind of whoever sought them out.  The duty of the priest is to listen and then take the secrets to the grave, because people sometimes need to unburden themselves.  They listen to confessions of sin, difficult life experiences, good life experiences and more or less anything that might be on a person's mind.  When they're done, the priests offer spiritual advice based on scripture and life experience, if appropriate.</p>

<p>Captain Vendros tells all, sparing no details, and she tells him he acted appropriately, with proper concern for his crew, because if they break down, because they're depressed, they many not fight as hard when the machines catch up to them.</p>

<p>He leaves feeling much better, but the Priestess starts to cry, wipes her makeup off on her sleeve, gulps down the alcohol she had with her meal and then heads off to find the ship's bar.</p>

<p>The next evening, Vendros arrives at the bar, finding the High Priestess drunk as can be.  He confronts her about her public drunkenness (priests are allowed to drink, but never to the point of intoxication, because they might let secrets slip if they get inebriated) and she says, "Thank you for showing me the truth." To the whole room, she shouts, "Vok has abandoned us!  We’re all going straight to the blazes of Xercil’s crematory!"</p>

<p>That deeply offends the entire room and most everyone steps out.  The bartender cuts her off and tells her she's not welcome in his bar anymore.</p>

<p>She leaves, but collapses just outside.</p>

<p>The Captain picks her up with the help of his first officer and she pukes on their shoes.  They take her back to her quarters, clean her up and put her to bed.</p>

<p>Captain Vendros heads for his quarters, feeling just as bad, if not worse, than he had before he spoke with her, because he never intended to destroy her faith.</p>

<p>I'm planning to add scenes between Captain Vendros and the Priestess from time to time, to keep the people in space relevant, since they're paramount to the climax and events of the next book.  These will center mostly around the slow journey of the Priestess back to her faith, prodded there by Vendros.  She will become the leader of the survivors that get off the ship at the start of the climactic battle that will overshadow events on the ground.</p>

<h2>Chapter 24: Trauma</h2>

<p>The opening scene of the chapter shows Sureshot on a mountainside, aiming her old rifle at the door of a log cabin a mile and a half away.</p>

<p>The door opens and a provocatively dressed woman steps to the threshold.  She pauses to blow a kiss inside, then steps out.  She's not Sureshot's target.</p>

<p>A man steps into the doorway and Sureshot smiles, because she has her target in her sights.  She aims for the heart and pulls the trigger.  She's at such extreme range, her shot is slightly off, but the man goes down, bleeding heavily, because she hit an artery, not his heart.  She reloads and considers putting a second bullet in the man to finish him off, a little mercy.</p>

<p>She thinks on the man's crimes and decides letting him die a little slower is appropriate, because on top of his crimes against the crown, he also raped and murdered close to fifty women.</p>

<p>She's unbothered by his last-minute struggles, until a little girl runs to his side and takes his hand, soon followed by the woman.  They give what comfort they can in his final moments and then the woman picks up the girl, leaving.</p>

<p>As it turned out, the monster had a daughter and Sureshot had killed him right in front of her.  None of the preliminary work on the mission had turned up that all-important detail (she was sick and in bed, where she wasn't visible from outside the cabin), which would have entirely changed her team's plans.</p>

<p>The after-action inquiry finds no fault with Sureshot, but instead lays what little blame there is on the rest of her team.  Nonetheless, Sureshot can't forget and can't forgive herself for her actions.</p>

<p>That's the event that broke the Army's best sharpshooter and forced her into early retirement, just over a year earlier.</p>

<p>Switching to the perspective of Brosla, Sureshot drops her rifle and starts crying about how sorry she is.</p>

<p>Gorgo complains, "Ye picked a fine time for a bout of battle fatigue!"</p>

<p>Nepita slashes Nemesis in the air again, but it has no effect on Brosla and leads her to adopt an expression of confusion.</p>

<p>Brosla is more or less left as the one to deal with Nepita, because Gorgo is focused on how soon they'll be landing in the chamber they're hurtling toward, asking Brosla to stop the assassin in the tunnel.</p>

<p>Brosla considers for a time and then orders his journal to form a network link with <em>Terror of Vok</em>, the ship of Captain Vendros.  He orders it to use the ship's computer to calculate a new form as an 'area-suppression tangle-pistol', leading to another humorous exchange:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Journal (sing-song voice): "Working…"</p>

<p>Journal (chirping): "Please wait!"</p>

<p>Gorgo (worried): "Is that gonna work?"</p>

<p>Brosla: (testy tone): "I don't know!"</p>

<p>Journal (chirping): "Please wait!"</p>

<p>Gorgo (screaming): "Here’s comes the drop!"</p>

<p>Journal (chirping): "Task complete."</p>
</blockquote>

<p>They fall free as the journal changes shape into a metallic pistol.  Brosla raises it and fires, shooting a web-like blast of gooey stands that blocks the tunnel opening they fell from.  He's just in time to catch Nepita, who's snared so badly, she can't move and the strands start constricting, preventing her from singing, due to the pressure.</p>

<p>They hit the floor pretty hard and Gorgo dislocates a shoulder.  Brosla pops it back in place with the help of his journal's scanners and some holographic instructions on treatment.</p>

<p>Their rifles are wrecked, since they landed on them.</p>

<p>Sureshot is physically fine, but unconscious, twitching as if she's having a nightmare.</p>

<p>Gorgo wishes he had a rifle so he can put Nepita out of their misery, to which she responds in a wheeze:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Trust me, <em>Prince Gorgo</em>, I won’t soon forget what you’ve done to me.  I <em>will</em> find you on the battlefield, <em>all three of you!</em>  I'll catch you and then cut little bits off, an inch at a time, with the dullest, rustiest knife I can find.  Then, once you’re nothing but a pathetic torso, I'll have a healer regrow your limbs and start all over again!  I'll spent the next thirty years killing you, but you’ll die of old age before I'll ever let you-</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Brosla adjusts his new journal-pistol to fine a more confined shot and then shoots Nepita in the mouth, webbing it shut.</p>

<p>They joke about how nice it is that she can't speak and then look down at Sureshot with concern.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Sureshot is having an emotionally difficult nightmare, in which she's on trial for mass murder, with King Joshua as judge, the gallery filled with all of her victims and their families.  Even worse, she has no lawyer, because no one in the land would defend her and there's five prosecutors, who intend to take turns interviewing witnesses, because they have a list that's hundreds long.</p>

<p>The first witness in Callie Blackwell, the daughter of the last man she shot during her army career.  The prosecutor asks a leading question designed to paint Sureshot as a vile serial killer, so she objects, but is overruled and ordered to remain silent, on pain of being sent straight to the noose, ore or less setting the impression in the reader's mind that she's being railroaded.</p>

<p>With no choice, Sureshot is forced to listen as Callie says, "She killed my daddy!  <em>She killed my daddy!</em>  She shot him right in front of me!"</p>

<p>As the girl leaves the witness stand, she passes by the defense table and leans over to whisper, "You’re going down-" and finishes with a word so foul, no little girl should have known it.</p>

<p>Hours pass as the prosecutors question every single one of Sureshot's victims, who start sharing their opinions on just about everything related to Sureshot, especially her lack of a love life.  They're out of line, but she dare not object.</p>

<p>Last of all, the prosecutors call a final witness: <em>Staff Sergeant Jane Stanton</em>.  It's totally wrong in every way for the prosecutor to call the defendant to the stand, but no one argues, not even Sureshot, who's will has mostly been broken by the events in court.</p>

<p>Her short stay on the witness stand went as follows:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Prosecutor: "How did killing all of those people make you feel?"</p>

<p>[Long silence as Sureshot thinks]</p>

<p>King Joshua (angry): <em>Answer the question, Sergeant!</em></p>

<p>Sureshot: "I-I enjoyed it.  I was killing enemies of the crown and I took great satisfaction from seeing each fall, for the sake of my king."</p>

<p>King Joshua (growling): <em>Are you actually trying to shift the blame to me?</em></p>

<p>Sureshot (crying): "No.  I take full responsibility.  I lost sight of why I was taking those shots and I started to enjoy it.  I didn't realize I’d lost my way, until I saw Callie hold her dying father’s hand.  I didn't realize I’d become a mass murderer in my heart, until I’d killed a man in front of his own child."</p>

<p>Prosecutor: "Are you guilty of the crimes you’ve been accused of?"</p>

<p>Sureshot: "I am and any punishment would be just."</p>

<p>[Sureshot returns to her seat]</p>

<p>King Joshua (raps gavel): <em>I find the defendant guilty of all charges and I’m so disgusted by her mere existence, I order her execution to take place, immediately.  Take her to the firing squad.</em></p>
</blockquote>

<p>She's taken outside, chained to a fence and a line of women with rifles just like the one she once favored step out.  They remove their executioner's hoods, revealing their faces are the same as Sureshot's.</p>

<p>"Ready!"</p>

<p>Sureshot decides her death would be justice and hopes it will relieve her of the burden of guilt she carries.</p>

<p>"Aim!"</p>

<p>She relaxes and an eerie calm takes her, because she's going to die and she can't do a thing about it.  Even worse, she doesn't want to.</p>

<p>She accepts her fate and stares down the barrel of the very rifle she took so many lives with.</p>

<p>"Fire!"</p>

<p>Sureshot wakes to Gorgo slapping her with all of his strength, because he and Brosla have tried just about everything else.  He just about dislocates her jaw in the process, but she does wake.</p>

<p>She looks up, seeing a peculiar mixture of hallucination, sleep and death magic, which she's almost certain was perfectly customized to her own psyche, designed to destroy her from the inside.  She only survived because Illa's magic and Gorgo's fist worked together to haul her out of the deadly dream.</p>

<p>Oddly, she now knows the root cause of her battle fatigue: she enjoyed her job a little more than she should have, something she vows to reflect upon, once she has the time.</p>

<p>Gorgo leads the way and they follow the path of the underground river, which flows through the cave they're in.  Eventually, they reach the point where the river flows into the canyon that leads to the Utros capitol.  They're above the canyon, so they stay out of sight of the patrols, down below, and eventually climb down, near the bottom.  From there, they make their way to the safety of the line held by the Oswil army.</p>

<h2>Part Three: The Drama</h2>

<p>The end of chapter 24 marks the end of Part Two, because peace will not be made in the near future and the real war will soon begin, with Oswil and Fortune Fields working together.</p>

<p>The first chapter of Part Three will likely involve the new alliance holding the line against the trolls, who will finally get serious, pulling out all of the stops.  They'll start rotating their troops in and out of battle, so the alliance will continuously face fresh troops, while the trolls relax and heal between stints at the front lines.</p>

<p>Yetu will make his first appearance in battle, supporting his side with magic.  Illa is likely to counter him and a magical duel will happen against the background of the battle.  The duel will probably end in a draw; Yetu hasn't got Illa's talent, but he does have physical endurance she lacks, allowing him to cast spells longer, so they're more or less an even match.</p>

<p>Months will pass between chapters as similar events take place, over and over, with the line moving very little, if at all.  The dwarves and humans will slowly be worn down and just when they're about to fail, fresh soldiers from Oswil will arrive to save the day.</p>

<p>From that point on, the war will turn against the trolls and a team of experts will be formed with the mission of deposing the ruler of the trolls.  That's the point at which Illa will finally come clean to Sureshot and redirect their focus from Shengis to Nepita, because Illa believes that so long as her sister lives, there will never be peace.</p>

<p>The rest of part three will follow that team's cavalry charge behind enemy lines, on a search and destroy mission that has only one target: Nepita, the Queen of the Trolls.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_writing.html'>writing</a>, <a href='tag_work-in-progress.html'>work-in-progress</a>, <a href='tag_rumors-of-war.html'>rumors-of-war</a></p>

<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://owentyme.us/blog/work-in-progress-5-troll-war-5-july-22-27.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/blog/./work-in-progress-5-troll-war-5-july-22-27.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Owen Tyme</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 17:26:33 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Work In Progress #4: Troll War #4 (July 15-19)
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>This is part four of my series on my work in progress novel, <a href="../books.html#troll-war">Troll War</a>, which centers around a kingdom of trolls going to war with a kingdom of dwarves, all because a pair of corrupt nobles from a third kingdom were bored and curious to see which race would come out on top.</p>

<p>You can read <a href="../books.html#troll-war">a short description of Troll War</a> to learn more or you can read <a href="https://mastodon.social/@OwenTyme/112672253855096568">short summaries of each day's writing, on Mastodon</a>.  This series can be read <a href="tag_rumors-of-war.html">via this link</a>, though it will be in reverse chronological order, from newest to oldest.</p>

<h2>Rewrites of Chapters 13 through 15</h2>

<p>Inspiration struck me on Monday and I more or less started the week's work by rewriting Chapters 13 and 14.</p>

<p>Chapter 13 more or less got gutted and was renamed 'Dire Warning', removing the content of the message Brosla received from space, to make use of that info later on (Chapter 16), when he meets the king.  Additionally, I added a little scene in which Brosla looks up at the stars and weeps, because he knows his race is nearly extinct.  He vows to defend his new home world, even if it costs him his life.</p>

<p>Chapter 14 was lengthened by adding a scene in which Sureshot visits the telegraph office in Ruby Canyon, that she might send a message to the royal palace of Oswil.  There's some argument about her authority to do so, but she reveals to the people in the office she used to be a Staff Sergeant in the 108th Phantom Recon, a unit that's notorious for being the King's personal problem solvers.  Most everyone thinks of them as assassins and they're not wrong.  This is the first major hint at Sureshot's troubled past, with more to come in later chapters.</p>

<p>T/he description of telegraph crystals was moved into Chapter 14 to match this new arrangement.</p>

<p>The reply is an order to return to the palace at a gallop and fresh horses are arranged at every city along her chosen route.</p>

<h2>Chapter 15: Royal Decree</h2>

<p>Sureshot arrives at the palace sore as can be from riding for about twenty hours straight, at a gallop.  Fortunately, General Hendrix, the King's right hand man, arranged a hot bath in an enchanted, healing bathtub, to take care of that.  She dozes for a short time as the magic does its work and is woken by a palace maid, that she might dress and tell her tale in detail.</p>

<p>She's led to the throne room, where she meets with King Joshua Wood, who's a ghost that's been dead for about four-hundred years.  As the last of his bloodline, when he died, he was unable to pass on, because his death would have resulted in a civil war, due to the power vacuum.  Oswil accepted a ghost for king and as a result, the kingdom is extremely stable compared to all others.</p>

<p>It's also very progressive, with a level of unparalleled freedom.  For example, King Joshua gave women equal rights about a hundred years into his rule, because he felt it would improve the kingdom.  His actions resulted in neighboring kingdoms doing the same, just to prevent their women from running off to live in Oswil.</p>

<p>Sureshot doesn't like being in her King's presence, due to his supernatural aura, but that had always been a part of her duties, before she retired from the Army.</p>

<p>She gives him a full report on the battle fought in Ruby Canyon and the King reactivates her in the Army, that she might lead a peace mission to confront both the dwarves and trolls about what they've done.  He worries the war may turn into a three-way brawl between nations, but accepts the notion that may be unavoidable.</p>

<p>Sureshot is angry at being forced back into the Army, but has no choice, because the King invokes wartime rules that allow retired soldiers to be reactivated.  She protests that they're not at war, but he explains that with a battle being fought on Oswil soil, the nation is at war, though one final attempt at diplomacy is called for.</p>

<p>To calm her, the King acknowledges Sureshot's mercenary existence as a gunfighter and offers her ten-thousand crowns for completion of the mission.  Instead, she asks for regular Army pay, five-hundred crowns for completion and an unspecified favor from the King, regardless of the outcome.  He reluctantly agrees, because he needs her.</p>

<p>Brosla was next in line to see the King and was watching the scene from the background.  Seeing Sureshot heading off and believing his best chance to fulfill his orders lies with assisting her, he blurts out, "I have information pertinent to this discussion!"</p>

<h2>Chapter 16: One Last Miracle</h2>

<p>Brosla tells the King he's from the stars and as an aid to understanding, he reluctantly says he's from the heavens.</p>

<p>The King asks, "Are you an angel or a god?"</p>

<p>He explains how he's a mortal from another world that revolves around a distant star, further explaining that the stars are distant suns, very much like the local one.  He makes sure to tell them he's just as mortal as they are.</p>

<p>He tells them dangerous creatures are on the way to their world, with the intent of consuming every natural resource, comparing them to an infectious disease.</p>

<p>Ultimately, the King doesn't believe him, even calling him a charlatan.  Sureshot also refuses to believe his words.</p>

<p>To convince them, Brosla uses his mimetic journal like a communications device, initiating a holographic call to the star ship captain that sent him the message in the night, who agrees to help.</p>

<p>It's noted at this point that Sureshot has some minimal magical training and she could have become a weak wizard, but she got little further than learning to sense magic.  She uses that ability, sensing no magic at all from Brosla or his shape-shifting journal.</p>

<p>The captain introduces himself as Turloth Vendros and the tale that was originally placed in chapter 13 is related, albeit in heavily modified form, with technological terms dumbed down for his primitive audience.  In particular, there's an interruption to explain what a galaxy is and he refers to the computer virus as "a disease-like mental contagion that only affects machines".</p>

<p>Vendros ends his tale with a plea for assistance, begging that the people of the world do their best to make peace and then turn their minds to preparing for war with the machines.  He also begs the King to teach his people about magic.</p>

<p>When he's finally done, the King believes the tale, because it's far too crazy to not be true.  He promises to make an attempt at peace, because that was already his goal.  He also promises to pass the request to learn magic to the wizards, but says it will be up to them.  Failing that, if the dwarves can be convinced to stop fighting, he'll ask them to teach Vendros and his people about runic enchantments.</p>

<p>The call is ended and Sureshot asks, "Okay, but how does all of this relate to my mission?  Either way, I’m going to make peace between the dwarves and trolls."</p>

<p>Brosla offers to go with her, because peace is now his mission.  He thinks he has little to contribute, but still offers to do all he can to aid her.</p>

<p>She reluctantly accepts him ad they head off to speak with General Hendrix about the details, before getting a night's rest.</p>

<h2>Chapter 17: Heroism</h2>

<p>In the morning, they have a brief conversation about the "spark of magic", which is a trait necessary for someone to become a wizard or witch.  Sureshot explains the spark as follows:</p>

<p>Life itself <em>is</em> magic.  Some have a bit more of it in them, allowing them to exert their will to produce miraculous results.  Those that have that ability are said to have the spark of magic.</p>

<p>Feeling the need for guidance, Sureshot takes Brosla to see her mother, who happens to be a fortune-telling witch.</p>

<p>They enter a pitch-dark room.  There's a sudden, pink light from the inside of a crystal ball, which illuminates a small, round table and the hands of an old woman.</p>

<p>Sureshot takes offense at her mother's pointless showmanship, since they both know there is no need for theatrics to use magic.  </p>

<p>Her mother sourly lights some candles with a snap of her fingers and there's a short argument about Sureshot's cynicism and the fact that her mother was wearing a long, pointed false nose with a wart on it.</p>

<p>The old witch (Vera) offers Sureshot the only other seat in the room and Brosla requests a chair for himself.</p>

<p>Vera turns her head in surprise, because she normally uses foresight magic to see just moments into the future, since her eyes are in such bad shape, she's nearly blind.</p>

<p>She's absolutely shocked, because she hadn't seen him coming and he's totally invisible to her magic!</p>

<p>She concludes that Brosla is a "Null-Magic Receptacle", or a "null", for short.  She explains that nulls are living beings born with zero magic.  No one knows how that can be, since life itself <em>is</em> magic, but it does happen about once in every generation.  She further explains that nulls are invisible to fate and therefore have the power to defy fate.  They normally die at a time of their own choosing and those that realize what they are tend to become the greatest of heroes, because they're such difficult forces to stop.</p>

<p>This will become important to the plot in later chapters and books.  Most likely, Brosla will slowly become the primary protagonist of the series.</p>

<p>With that surprise out of the way, Vera asks Sureshot to take her hand and uses that connection to send her daughter's mind flitting to the future.</p>

<p>Sureshot experiences a flash of one possible future, minus Brosla, of course.  She's surrounded by corpses of military men, a dwarf named Kadrek and a woman with snow-white hair, all shot in the right eye, specifically.</p>

<p>She unknowingly led them into a trap set by the troll sharpshooter (probably Anji), getting them all killed.  She blames herself, because she refused to touch a rifle.</p>

<p>Sureshot draws her sword (named Shaffurukattā, which roughly translates as Shuffle Cutter) and whispers to it for a moment, then concentrates magic in her hands.  Shaffurukattā drinks deeply of her magic and she slashes the air, producing a wormhole-like tear in space.  The tear leads her behind the sharpshooter and she slashes right through the woman, producing another spatial tear, neatly cutting them in half, right down the middle.  Her opponent was a troll, but not even a troll can regenerate from that, at least not without help.</p>

<p>She steps back through the tear to her dead friends and despairs, only to be surprised by the white-haired woman waking up, despite having a hole clean though her skull!  The woman complains about the pain.</p>

<p>Sureshot asks, "What are you?"</p>

<p>The woman smiles and answers, "A housewife."</p>

<p>Then she looks around, sees Kadrek's dead and then bursts into tears.</p>

<p>The vision ends, but the details fade away like a dream, leaving Sureshot with a few impressions: the name Kadrek sticks in her mind (she knows a dwarf named Kadrek), there was lots of blood and she felt regret at not having a rifle, which bothers her, because she's sworn to never use one again.</p>

<p>Before they leave, Vera asks Brosla to protect Sureshot, because with a null standing between her daughter and fate, she hopes her daughter will survive their dangerous mission.</p>

<h2>Chapter 18: Reluctance</h2>

<p>Sureshot, Brosla and a unit of soldiers are riding through a forest, while she's deep in thought about the way she met Corporal Logan, the man in charge of the men assigned to her.</p>

<p>Logan offered her a rifle kitted out the way she always preferred, back when she'd been in the army, but the mere sight of it brought back hundreds of deaths that she'd seen through the scope of her rifle, because she'd been among the best sharpshooters in the kingdom.</p>

<p>The memories are painful and the very personal way in which she looked just about every one of those she killed in the eye before shooting them was troubling.  She'd only killed enemies of the crown, but in the process, human life had become cheap and unimportant.</p>

<p>That realization had led directly to her retirement a little over a year before and her work as a gunfighter.  She specifically been seeking jobs with a very human element, in which she helps people with their troubles, as the means to get her soul back.</p>

<p>She refused the rifle and Logan kept it for himself.  Logan is hated by the men under his command, because he always shouts and insults them, never letting up.  Sureshot is concerned for the men, but chooses to do nothing, because she won't be their Sergeant for long, knowing that if she intervenes, Logan is likely to take it out on the men, just as soon as she's out of their lives.</p>

<p>I'm setting up Logan to be a point of contentions later on, but he isn't all bad.  He's a good soldier that happens to have some faults.</p>

<p>He had many reasons for offering Sureshot the rifle, including a little bit of desire to suck-up, a genuine understanding of Sureshot's reputation and some knowledge of the emotional trauma a good sharpshooter endures.  In his own small way, he's trying to force her to confront her own demons, knowing that their best chance of success in battle will be with a rifle cradled in Sureshot's arms.</p>

<p>Knowing her own, vague regrets from the vision, she didn't argue with Logan bringing the customized rifle.  She more or less hates herself for admitting it, but she may need it.</p>

<p>They arrive at the home of Kadrek and Illa.  Sureshot tries to convince Kadrek to get her an audience with King Windmaker.  As a result of the work she did for the dwarf, she knows there's royal guardsmen from Fortune Fields watching the dwarf's every move, though she doesn't understand why.</p>

<p>Kadrek initially refuses, but Sureshot doesn't back down, so he tell her who she is and then takes her to the guards.  They refuse to help, because they can't leave their post.</p>

<p>Kadrek decides accompany Sureshot and Illa offers her assistance with the trolls, claiming she once lived among them.  That leads to a bit of disbelief that Illa could know anything at all about trolls, causing Illa to reveal her magic powers, as a show of strength.</p>

<p>Sureshot agrees.</p>

<h2>Chapter 19: Diplomatic Impunity</h2>

<p>Kadrek, Illa, Sureshot, Logan and the men are hauled in front of King Windmaker, in chains, because they crossed the border with Kadrek, who is well known for having been banished.</p>

<p>King Windmaker is conflicted, outwardly angry, but despairing on the inside, because Kadrek's presence forces his hand.  He shouts for his son and his wife to be taken to the dungeon.</p>

<p>Sureshot screams, "Diplomatic immunity!" and then demands that the chains be removed from her entire team, including Kadrek and Illa.  She only allowed her team to be shackled, because it was the fastest way to get to King Windmaker.</p>

<p>Her letter of introduction is inspected and the King orders the chains removed.  He's relieved to have a way out of jailing his own son.</p>

<p>However, while the chains are being removed, he starts a bit of a staring contest with Sureshot, as the means to judge her tenacity.  She meets his gaze for ten minutes straight and the King blinks, with his eyes burning.  When he opens his eyes, she's still staring.</p>

<p>She says, "Never try to out-stare a sharpshooter from the 108th."</p>

<p>The King recognizes the unit number and gets the implied threat.  King Joshua sent an assassin to make peace, implying that if he doesn't agree to her reasonable demands, then she's was quite likely authorized to kill him.</p>

<p>Despite this fact, he quite likes her, because she's more tenacious than a dwarf and audacious enough to order him around in his own throne room.  This is a little nod to the chapter title, <em>Diplomatic Impunity</em>.</p>

<p>Sureshot explains the events that brought her there and the King apologizes for the actions of his men.  Sureshot explains that she's on a mission of peace.</p>

<p>The King promises to remain at peace with Oswil, promising his men will never cross the border without permission, ever again.</p>

<p>Sureshot counters that she didn't come for peace between Fortune Fields and Oswil.  She came to make peace between the dwarves and the trolls.  If he doesn't agree, then the consequence will be making an enemy of Oswil and fighting a war on two fronts.</p>

<p>The King explains how the war began and his inability to make peace, despite trying.  He eventually mentions having captured many trolls, but they act as though they were born yesterday, knowing little to nothing.</p>

<p>Illa counters, "That’s because they <em>were</em> born yesterday, metaphorically speaking."</p>

<p>She explains that the trolls have largely been fighting the war with cloned shock troops, a strategy designed to soften Fortune Fields up for a real invasion.</p>

<p>The King is frustrated to learn this, because he's lost ninety-percent of his soldiers in the past three years.</p>

<p>Ill informs him, "That was the point.  The real invasion will be starting any day now."</p>

<p>He laments not hearing her out three years before and that's as far as I got on Friday, before I had to head off to work.</p>

<p>I'll probably finish the chapter (on Monday) with an emotional plea for peace from Captain Vendros, via Brosla's mimetic journal.</p>

<h2>Future Plans</h2>

<p>The overall plot-line has started coming into focus for me, but as always, everything is tentative until the final draft.</p>

<h3>Finishing Part Two</h3>

<p>I"ll likely wrap up part two next week, the rest of which should revolve around attempts to force a cease-fire, for the sake of peace talks.  With Fortune Fields so worn down, but willing to commit to peace, Oswil will get involved, sending an army to occupy the land between the two nations.</p>

<p>Nepita isn't stupid enough to start a war with Oswil while she's already in a war with Fortune Fields, so the cease-fire will briefly happen.  The dwarves will send another envoy (Kadrek's brother), but Nepita will treat him the same as Kadrek, shaving and stripping him as her response, because she wants to continue fighting the dwarves (she's having fun).</p>

<p>Part two should conclude with the King of Oswil committing to aiding the dwarves, since they can't stand on their own after all they've endured.</p>

<h3>Part Three</h3>

<p>Part three will focus on the invasion of Utros and Sureshot's team will lead the charge, accompanied by King Windmaker.  Their intent is to force the trolls to accept peace as they look down the barrel of a loaded gun, but it won't be so easy and Nepita will pull out all the stops to fight back.</p>

<p>I want to keep the situation in space relevant to the story, so Brosla will get occasional updates from Captain Vendros.  During the climax, his ship will arrive in geosynchronous orbit with an enemy warship right on his heels.</p>

<p>As the battle on the ground rages (probably at night), there will be incredible pyrotechnics in the sky, leading to debris falling into the atmosphere like a meteor shower, because the two ships won't be pulling any punches, literally blasting each other to bits.</p>

<p>I want the battle in space to become the reason Nepita finally backs down and sees reason, but it's nearly impossible to stop a battle once started and the two rulers will have to work together to end it.</p>

<p>The novel should end with everyone from all over the region watching debris fall form the sky, including major and minor characters introduced throughout the book.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_writing.html'>writing</a>, <a href='tag_work-in-progress.html'>work-in-progress</a>, <a href='tag_rumors-of-war.html'>rumors-of-war</a></p>

<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://owentyme.us/blog/work-in-progress-4-troll-war-4-july-15-19.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/blog/./work-in-progress-4-troll-war-4-july-15-19.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Owen Tyme</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 11:23:42 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Work In Progress #3: Troll War #3 (July 8-12)
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>This is part three of my series on my work in progress novel, <a href="../books.html#troll-war">Troll War</a>, which centers around a kingdom of trolls going to war with a kingdom of dwarves, all because a pair of corrupt nobles from a third kingdom were bored and curious to see which race would come out on top.</p>

<p>You can read <a href="../books.html#troll-war">a short description of Troll War</a> to learn more or you can read <a href="https://mastodon.social/@OwenTyme/112672253855096568">short summaries of each day's writing, on Mastodon</a>.  This series can be read <a href="tag_rumors-of-war.html">via this link</a>, though it will be in reverse chronological order, from newest to oldest.</p>

<p>Writing this week revolved around completion of Part One, 'Setting the Stage', and the start of Part Two, 'The Players'.</p>

<h2>Chapter 10: Discovery</h2>

<p>I renamed this chapter and the old title, 'Exile' was used for chapter 10.</p>

<p>As Illa and Kadrek spend the day out on the town for the first time since their stay in the hospital, King Windmaker marches his personal guards and a full regiment of soldiers back into the city of Wind Hammer, with the recently captured trolls as prisoners of war.  The intent is to house them in a prison inside the city.</p>

<p>The King and his personal guard break off and march their war-riders back into the palace, leaving one of the great doors to the palace open, symbolizing the fact the King is in, but the kingdom is still at war.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the captured trolls are marched through the city, right past Illa and Kadrek.  They see Illa and call out to her, begging her to save them, but their guards mistake their cries for prayers to a troll god.  Kadrek, on the other hand, takes note of where they were all looking, right at Illa.</p>

<p>She comes clean and even fights past the instinct to keep the ancient secret of the trolls, telling him she's a troll woman.  She apologizes for lying to him, having kept it going so long only because she feared for her life.  He forgives her on the spot. Next, he asks her to promise she'll never lie to him again and in exchange, he promises to always stand beside her.</p>

<h2>Chapter 11: Exile</h2>

<p>Illa agrees to Kadrek's reasonable demand and gives him her word.</p>

<p>Kadrek does what he feels is right, taking her straight to the King, that she might offer information of value in exchange for her life.</p>

<p>The throne room is cleared of even the King's personal guard and Illa starts by prostrating herself before the King, saying she's a female troll, once more struggling with instinct just to speak.  The King doesn't believe her, so he orders her to look him in the eye as she speaks.</p>

<p>He doesn't believe her, because everyone on their world knows the troll race was literally last in line when looks were handed out.</p>

<p>Getting angry, Illa introduces herself properly and a hint of her old pride rises to the surface, that she might speak with the tone of royalty.  She explains her lineage and relationship to the current Queen of the trolls, her sister, Nepita.</p>

<p>Next, she tells the secret tale of Segawa, the Goddess of Beauty, who's always depicted veiled, because she's said to be so beautiful that any who looked upon her would instantly die, even other gods.  Unknown to mortals, Segawa was married to the blind troll god, Benni.  Unable to see his wife, he was safe to spend extended periods in her company, unaffected by her power.</p>

<p>Coming upon the scene of the newly-made trolls and seeing their ugliness, a result of the other gods selfishly giving all of their beauty to their own mortal creations, on top of noting the terrible curse the gods had placed on the trolls because their mere appearance offended them (trolls burn as easily as dry wood), she took pity on the first female troll, gifting the ugly creature with her own, divine beauty.  In turn, she took the troll's ugliness for her own.</p>

<p>Angry with the other gods, Segawa threw off her veil and showed them her face for the first time, using it to shame them for their selfish actions.  Ashamed at what they'd done, they kept the secret to themselves.  Bothered by her own appearance, Segawa put her veil back on and told only the high priests of her church, though the trolls also knew everything.</p>

<p>King Windmaker asks for proof and Illa cuts her own finger off, allowing the King to watch her grow a replacement.</p>

<p>Convinced, the King asks where her loyalties lie and she says her loyalty is to Kadrek, promising to tell all, if the King will spare her life and allow her to stay by Kadrek's side.</p>

<p>The King is silent for a long time, deep in thought, so Illa begins totll more, but the King silences her, because he realizes her secrets will do the opposite of what she intends.  Instead of giving the dwarves an advantage, if word got back to the trolls that they knew the deepest secrets of troll-kind, the war will become a holy war.</p>

<p>He wants the information, but not at the price of upsetting the trolls so badly that they'll never stop fighting until one kingdom or the other is destroyed.  After all, the standing policy of the trolls was to kill anyone that learned the facts about their women, which had been the case so long it was actually instinct.</p>

<p>The rest of the court is brought back in and the three of them portray a bit of theater.  The King pretends to believe nothing Illa has said and also pretends he's infuriated to have caught her in a lie.  The guards try to seize her, but Kadrek stands in their way, shouting that he'll spit in his father's eye and fight the royal guard, armed with only a pocket knife.</p>

<p>The King gives Kadrek the choice to stay in the kingdom or be banished with Illa.  Kadrek decides to go with her, so the King offers to marry them first, because it's the only way he might witness the event.  They agree, so he has his dead wife's ring resized for Illa and does the same with the old wedding band from his own finger, for Kadrek.  He marries them on the spot, then gives Kadrek a pouch of gold and two hours to purchase supplies for the road, suggesting they travel north, to Oswil, because they'll be welcome there.</p>

<p>When they're gone, the King orders the room cleared again, so he can be alone with his grief.</p>

<h2>Chapter 12: Upping the Ante</h2>

<p>Queen Nepita receives a message from King Windmaker, delivered by a captured troll he released to carry it.</p>

<p>The message is simple: for every dwarf that dies by a troll's hand, one-hundred trolls will burn to death.</p>

<p>Nepita is amused by his bravado and vows to show her counterpart what happens to brave men in her kingdom.</p>

<p>She walks to the work room of the biomancers, where abominations are being surgically assembled from parts obtained from troll men.  The current subject is a bloated, three armed troll, who's in the process of having a fourth arm grafted onto his body, a difficult process that requires four surgeons working in unison.  He's not bloated with fat, but with transplanted muscle.</p>

<p>Nepita demands a status report and they tell her fifty-seven abominations are ready.</p>

<p>This was done in editing an earlier chapter, but I went back and added a scene were Kina and Aketa reported to Nepita.  For Aketa's failures, she was assigned to become an abomination.</p>

<p>The biomancers inform Nepita that Aketa has requested to have her body implanted inside the captured war-rider, that she might become an abomination of steel, rather than flesh.  Nepita agrees and they inform her that Yera (The attendant of Nepita's Grandmother) has offered to enchant the war-rider to be self-heating, so it will never need fuel, claiming she's unlocked the secrets of dwarf runes.</p>

<p>Nepita is surprised, because Yera hasn't spoken in more than a decade, but she sees the utility of such work and agrees.</p>

<p>A new scene begins with King Windmaker standing on the wall of an abandoned castle far to the south of his kingdom, where a prosperous human farming kingdom once was.  The land was abandoned, due to a volcanic eruption, which has steadily continued from time to time for more than a hundred years.</p>

<p>Opposite him, on the other side of the castle's gate, the lieutenant of a squad of fresh soldiers stands.  Both of them hold enchanted lassos woven from mythril wire.</p>

<p>Down in the castle courtyard, most of the squad waits, mounted on fire-dogs.  Fire-dogs are four-legged, steam powered machines that serve Fortune Fields much like firetrucks in modern times.  Each has a big water tank on its back, while the soldiers sit on the neck, controlling the movements of the dogs with stirrup-like controls, while the ears of the dogs are handles to control the direction their heads point.  There's an elbow-activated button on the water tank, behind the driver, which activated the water pump, allowing the dog to spray water from its mouth.</p>

<p>Another soldier on fire-dog comes into view over the horizon, screaming and cursing, because an angry fire elemental is hot on his heels!  It's shaped like a stag, with blue flames for head and body and orange flame for legs and antlers.</p>

<p>The fleeing soldier passes through the ruined castle walls and out the back, while the King and Lietenant whirl their lassos, each getting a good hold of an antler!  The elemental is held in place, while the fire-dogs spray it, shrinking it until it's only six inches tall!</p>

<p>The fleeing soldier comes around to face its backside and all of the fire-dogs are used to effectively pen the beast in with walls of splattering water.</p>

<p>The dwarf that lured the creature hops down and pulls an enchanted, mythril jar from his coat, complete with a screw-top lid.  The lassos are released and the stag frees itself, while the dwarf sets the jar on it's side, saying, “Me brought ye some coal to eat!”</p>

<p>The elemental, desperate for any fuel it might use to regain its former size, enters the jar and the lid is screwed on, capturing it.</p>

<p>The King accepts the jar and looks through the air holes in the top, pleased the crazy plan worked.</p>

<p>The elemental will be handed off to dwarves with good animal skills, for taming, and will eventually be used as the power source for a new type of war-rider, a fire-breathing demon-rider.</p>

<p>One weapon isn't enough, however, so there's many more elementals to capture...</p>

<h2>Part Two: The Players</h2>

<p>Chapter 12 marks the end of Part One, which was all about setting the war in motion.</p>

<p>Part Two is about setting the rest of the story's plot in motion, starting with introducing some new characters (adventurers) and giving the human/elf kingdom of Oswil a reason to involve itself in the war.</p>

<p>The idea is to introduce a group of adventurers and then send them to both sides of the war, to make peace.  This will consist of an alien anthropologist that has his own reasons to make peace (odd-ball with unusual abilities), a gunfighter/retired army sergeant (leader), Illa (glass-cannon/witch), Kadrek (fighter and negotiator) and an Oswil Army corporal.</p>

<p>There will also be a squad of soldiers, but their purpose in the story will be to die and demonstrate when the crap has hit the fan.</p>

<p>Three years pass between parts, giving the simmering war time to reach a full boil...</p>

<h2>Chapter 13: One Last Miracle</h2>

<p>This chapter introduces Brosla Ghinead, an alien anthropologist living on the planet, who's been studying magic for thirty years.  He looks at least vaguely human, but a little on the tall side, with skin just a little too red (like a sunburn) and overly-sharp teeth, which he hides with something akin to dentures.  He's a Vokosian, a technologically advanced, space-faring race with a a large empire.</p>

<p>He's woken in the night by a message from space that came marked with government codes at the highest level of authority.  The source of the message is the captain of the last remaining ship, coming from a man that claims to have been the commander of Vokosian Empire's military.</p>

<p>The message details a war that happened in Brosla's absence, in which a machine intelligence became a self-replicating scourge on the galaxy.  The galaxy fought back and managed to press the machines back to their own system, at which point the captain tried to make peace.</p>

<p>He laments the fact the galaxy needed a butcher and he chose to be a peacemaker.</p>

<p>The machines backed down and they eventually made trade agreements, to share scientific progress, but that was just a ploy.  The machines got the Vokosians to replace all of their reactors with safer models that included safety features.  No sign of trickery was found and the new design got used everywhere.</p>

<p>They only discovered the trick when a radiation pulse from the machines shut down every reactor in the empire, aside from more antiquated designs, resulting in more than a thousand worlds falling in a single day!</p>

<p>The lone captain escaped in his antique, personal ship and ran.  Eventually he found records of Brosla's research on the strange planet and set a course, thinking magic might be the miracle his people desperately need.</p>

<p>The captain urges Brosla to get the locals organized to defend their world, because the machines will come, sooner or later.  He also claims he will arrive at the planet in a little over three months time.</p>

<p>Brosla gathers his things and heads out, intent on speaking with the King of Oswil as soon as possible.</p>

<p>The intent of this character is that he'll become a part of the adventuring party </p>

<h2>Chapter 14: Rock and a Hard Place</h2>

<p>Jane "Sureshot" Stanton is a retired Oswil Army Sergeant and sharpshooter.  She has a very old west, gunfighter look to her, since that's the theme I'm associating with Oswil.</p>

<p>She wears a long, leather coat, cowboy hat and cowboy boots.</p>

<p>She wears an enchanted katana on her back (she's the world's equivalent to half-Japanese), which is an old family heirloom.</p>

<p>On her hips are a pair of Scott and Walcott copies of the Cobb Single Action Army revolver.  Even better, S&amp;W employ a dwarf smith, who enhances some of their work with dwarf runes, so her pistols are enchanted.</p>

<p>I'm intentionally drawing parallels to Smith and Wesson, plus Colt, since named firearm manufacturers are very much a part of the old west.  I don't want to use the real world names, because the world I'm writing isn't our world, at all, though it does have many similarities, especially among humans.</p>

<p>Sureshot is at a remote town on the frontier, near Utros, named Ruby Canyon.  The town is half in and half out of the canyon mouth.</p>

<p>As she walks the town and talks with the mayor about the job she came to do, involving shooting a bunch of goblins, she notices an excess of dwarves around the place, counting seventeen at a glance.</p>

<p>She raises her concern with the mayor, who also finds it odd.</p>

<p>Getting a nasty suspicion, she asks when they last saw a goblin.  He tells her four days.</p>

<p>She tells him her honest opinion: Ruby Canyon is caught between dwarf and troll armies, but she's interrupted by the sound of gunfire.</p>

<p>Hours pass and the battle ends with a town full of dead dwarves and a handful of dwarves burning trolls, to make sure they won't regenerate.  Many of the dwarves were killed with extremely precise shots to the right eye, because the trolls had a sharpshooter with them that was showing off.  This is a little foreshadowing for later chapters, in which I intend to pit Sureshot against the troll responsible, in a contest of sniper vs. sniper.  The troll sniper is probably Anji, but I haven't made up my mind yet.</p>

<p>Sureshot demands to speak with the commanding officer of the dwarf soldiers, but he's dead and so are the rest of their leaders.</p>

<h2>Chapter 15: Royal Decree</h2>

<p>Sureshot sends word to the King of Oswil via telegraph crystal, a one-inch, flat, square variation of a crystal ball coated in a magical, moss-derived chemical that glows when tapped or when hit by the same frequency of light it emits.  Such devices come in linked pairs that glow at both ends when tapped.  They're used for long-range communication in Oswil, using Moss Code, which is their name for their equivalent to Morse Code.</p>

<p>The King responds with a request for her immediate presence, so she rides as fast as she can for the capitol.</p>

<p>Sadly, that's as far as I got, but my plan for the rest of the chapter is for Surshot to report to the King, while Brosla waits for his turn to speak.  Hearing the King's decree that men will be sent to seek peace between the dwarves and trolls, Brosla will probably reveal himself as an alien, telll his tale and volunteer to go on the peace mission.  The king will assign a squad of soldiers and temporarily reactivate Sureshot's rank as Sergeant (likely against her will), so she can take command.</p>

<p>There might be a visit to a fortune-telling witch on the way out of town, who will cryptically prod them to go visit Kadrek and Illa, because they're essential to the success of the mission, on top of being main characters.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_writing.html'>writing</a>, <a href='tag_work-in-progress.html'>work-in-progress</a>, <a href='tag_rumors-of-war.html'>rumors-of-war</a></p>

<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://owentyme.us/blog/work-in-progress-3-troll-war-3-july-8-12.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/blog/./work-in-progress-3-troll-war-3-july-8-12.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Owen Tyme</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 11:35:09 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
On the Nature of Magic
</title><description><![CDATA[

<blockquote>
  <p>"Any sufficiently advanced technology is indistinguishable from magic."</p>

<p>― Arthur C. Clarke, Profiles of the Future: An Inquiry into the Limits of the Possible </p>
</blockquote>

<p>We gaze with wonder at the stars of the night sky and most everyone has no idea the effect they're having, just by looking.</p>

<p>Quantum physics includes some peculiar concepts that most people never manage to wrap their brains around: Heisenburg's Uncertainty Principle and the Observer Effect.</p>

<p>The following summary is probably a little off, but should serve to help me make my point.  To the physicists reading my words: sorry, but I'm not one of you and my understanding is certainly flawed.  Please forgive my errors.</p>

<p>To summarize, the state of any given particle is undefined until measured and the only conclusions that can be drawn without measurement are all a matter of what the particle is most likely to be doing, but until that measurement is made, the particle is actually doing all of the things it could possibly be doing, at the same time.  When the particle is measured, it stops doing all that freaky, simultaneous stuff and suddenly pretends it was following one path all along, but only so long as it's being measured.</p>

<p>I take it on faith that the mathematics say it's true and I've seen some tricky little experiments that prove it.  Look up a Youtube video on the double-slit experiment if you want your mind blown.</p>

<p>That's the Observer Effect at work: as far as I'm aware, in quantum physics, any form of intelligence (seems to require life, as well) simply looking at the environment around it causes the universe to change, setting itself down a particular path and all things are in flux until we look at them.</p>

<p>Nothing is concrete until we make it so, just by using our senses.  I once read that astronomers observing the stars with ever finer instruments have hypothetically shortened their lifespans, simply by forcing them to take on a particular state. That's why I say people have no idea what they're doing to the stars.</p>

<p>However, please don't feel bad about it.  That's just the nature of life and the universe.</p>

<h2>What About the Magic?</h2>

<p>Ah, the question has finally arisen in your mind, yes?  Why did I bring this up and what does it have to do with magic?</p>

<p>I've never gotten a clear explanation of the Observer Effect and its cause.  As far as I know, no one understands why it happens, only knowing that it does.</p>

<p>So, deep down, at a fundamental level, the universe does this mysterious, dare I say it, <strong>magical</strong> thing, which has no explanation.  The very foundation of reality and everything in it stands on this strange thing that happens, just because an observer shapes the universe merely by existing.</p>

<p>Arthur C. Clark spoke well when he said this: "Any sufficiently advanced technology is indistinguishable from magic."</p>

<p>I daresay that reality itself is magic and science may be an illusion the universe made up on the fly, just because we were looking too close.</p>

<p>The trouble in all of this is that we can't even arrive at a concrete, definitive explanation of what intelligence actually is, except in self-referential terms.  So it also is with life.  These concepts go round in circles, referring only to themselves and each other. At the end of the day, all we can really and truly say is that we know them when we see them.</p>

<p>Please trust me when I say this, because I studied both subjects in college, discovering a deep, philosophical hole in our knowledge that has no concrete answer.</p>

<p>To my mind, anything that cannot be defined or explained is magic.  Period.  Plain and simple.  Perhaps this is not your definition, but it is mine.</p>

<p>To summarize, here's the magical things we've covered so far: quantum physics, observers, intelligence and perhaps even the spark of life itself.</p>

<p>All of science stands on these inexplicable, magical things, so in a way, science is also magic.</p>

<h2>Science Fiction</h2>

<p>No matter how obsessed the writer may be with scientific accuracy, sooner or later, every science fiction story comes down to the same issue, right at the level of the story's bones: the tale can't be told without relying on magic.</p>

<p>Ah, but in my mind I can hear a thousand sci-fi fans screaming the same thing at me: the defining quality of sci-fi that sets it apart from fantasy is that <em>there is no magic!</em></p>

<p>Unpopular though my opinion may be, I've got to break it to you: rubber science, no matter how concrete and well-researched, is based on the same leap of faith that magic is, because it is fundamentally the same thing.</p>

<p>Again, science <em>is</em> magic.</p>

<h2>Fantasy</h2>

<p>Fantasy, on the other hand, embraces that bendy, wobbly concept and thrusts it to the forefront.  Some writers use it a lot and some use it a little, but at the end of the day, you can't have fantasy without at least a pinch of magic.</p>

<h2>A Writer's Definition of Magic</h2>

<p>So, let's look at the two sides of this coin in terms of definitions, like a dictionary, but let's do so from the perspective of a writer.</p>

<ul>
<li>Rubber Science: A plot device</li>
<li>Magic: A plot device</li>
</ul>

<p>So, if both come out to equal the same thing, it implies they really are the same thing, does it not?  Everything else is just window dressing and descriptive detail.</p>

<h2>Science Fantasy</h2>

<p>In the end, I've chosen to boldly go where few choose to tread: I freely mix science fiction and fantasy in what I call 'science fantasy'.  I like to pit the usual elements of the two against each other, because it makes for a striking and new take on the older genres.  I find the combination fresh with endless possibilities.</p>

<p>To me, this is extremely freeing and my imagination runs where it chooses, resulting in wizards and witches with magic blaster guns, flying around in star ships that have the usual kind of rubber-science bells and whistles like force fields and teleporters, but instead of hand-waving the science, a wizard did it by integrating his love of magic and technology into one convenient package.</p>

<p>I just don't comprehend the purpose of putting some rigid, unbending line down the center of my brain, arbitrarily deciding that fantasy and science fiction are separate, never the twain shall meet.  I balk at the limitation, because they're the same, dang thing!</p>

<p>However, I'm not alone in this.  Other writers have done it, but most of the time, they insist their work is science fiction.</p>

<p>The most prominent example I can think of is <em>Star Wars</em>.  George Lucas used a sci-fi theme to tell fantasy stories and successfully sold that little, white lie to millions (maybe billions?) under the heading of science-fiction.  The science in Star Wars is heavily hand-waved and rubber as can be.  The Force is just magic with a sci-fi themed wrapper (psychic powers!) and just like fantasy, there's a lot of sword fighting, even though perfectly reasonable laser-like guns exist.  Robots replace golems, aliens replace monsters and crystal balls become computers to make something that would normally be called fantasy, if there weren't space ships in it.  Heck, even laser guns are analogous to a wizard's magic wand.  </p>

<p>Why is space travel almost exclusively pigeonholed as sci-fi?  Hasn't anyone heard of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spelljammer">Spelljammer</a>?</p>

<h2>What Changed Me?</h2>

<p>I used to play Dungeons and Dragons a lot and as a Dungeon Master, I was always drawn to unique settings and adventures to run.  The unusual is what I craved.</p>

<p>Two particular publications caught my eye: <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Expedition_to_the_Barrier_Peaks">Expedition to the Barrier Peaks</a> and <a href="https://dungeonsdragons.fandom.com/wiki/Tale_of_the_Comet">Tale of the Comet</a>.</p>

<p>I never had a chance to run the first in a serious fashion, just because it was too old and my access to it at the time was limited, since my brother owned and somewhat jealously guarded it.  The second was my own discovery, just sitting on the shelf of a party supplies store that I entered in search of unnaturally large balloons for a college class (3 footers).</p>

<p><a href="https://dungeonsdragons.fandom.com/wiki/Tale_of_the_Comet">Tale of the Comet</a> captured my attention in a way that nothing in Dungeons and Dragons ever had before.  Magic vs. technology, wizards fighting robots, an AI scourge on the galaxy that needed to be put down and an opportunity for magic to save the day where technology had failed.  It also captured the imagination of my players and every time I used it, the gaming table was electrified with excitement.</p>

<p>In short, it was a magical experience for us, especially me.  Everyone saw how unique the setting was and wanted to see more.</p>

<p>It didn't happen consciously, but that's when I finally realized science fiction and fantasy were the same, a pair of twins separated at birth and raised without knowledge of each other, though they got along famously when they finally met.</p>

<p><a href="https://dungeonsdragons.fandom.com/wiki/Tale_of_the_Comet">Tale of the Comet</a> changed me forever and is responsible for the writer I am today.  Without it, I would probably never have had the audacity to unchain my imagination.  Without that setting showing me the possibilities, I might never have written about <a href="../books.html#sky-children">an electrical engineer crash-landing on a planet that gave him magic powers</a>, nor would I have written about <a href="../books.html#wizards-scion">his son, Levi Jacobs</a>.</p>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>Magic is real.</p>

<p>It's found in the heart of the laws of physics, the very core of the human brain and inside every living thing.  Seeing anything is magic, because the mere act of observing changes <em>everything</em>.</p>

<p>I'm in awe of the grand design of the universe and our place in it as the observers and shapers of all we touch, taste, smell, hear and see.</p>

<p>I'm grateful my eyes are open to this fact, glad to know science and magic are so much alike.  It fills my mind with ever-changing possibilities.</p>

<p>Who knows if the magic underpinning the universe will ever be understood?  I, for one, hope that mystery is never revealed by science, because if it is, it will destroy that last bit of wonder and leave people thinking our own existence is nothing but a cheap trick.  It would be like pulling the curtain back, only to reveal everything was based on a bunch of squirrels running on a hamster wheel; novel and amusing perhaps, but mundane.</p>

<p>Without a little magic, there is no imagination.  Without something we can't understand, there would be no striving for something new.  Without the touch of mystery pervading the entire universe, it would be a cheap, boring existence, gray and lifeless to the core.</p>

<p>I <em>need</em> to stare at the stars in awe.  I <em>need</em> the mysteries to excite my mind with their possibilities.  I <em>need</em> the magic of existence.</p>

<p>Magic is all around us and the best magic of all is the human mind.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_writing.html'>writing</a></p>

<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://owentyme.us/blog/on-the-nature-of-magic.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/blog/./on-the-nature-of-magic.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Owen Tyme</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 14:28:20 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Work in Progress #2: Troll War #2 (July 1-5)
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>This is part two of my series on my work in progress novel, <a href="../books.html#troll-war">Troll War</a>, which centers around a kingdom of trolls going to war with a kingdom of dwarves, all because a pair of corrupt nobles from a third kingdom were bored and curious to see which race would come out on top.</p>

<p>You can read <a href="../books.html#troll-war">a short description of Troll War</a> to learn more or you can read <a href="https://mastodon.social/@OwenTyme/112672253855096568">short summaries of each day's writing, on Mastodon</a>.  This series can be read <a href="tag_rumors-of-war.html">via this link</a>, though it will be in reverse chronological order, from newest to oldest.</p>

<p>Writing was fun this week, with a fair amount of action as the fighting between the dwarves and trolls heated up, followed by the start of a little romantic subplot that will be rather important to later chapters.  I also planted some important seeds for later plot points.</p>

<h2>Chapter 5: The Bleeding Mother</h2>

<p>I renamed Chapter 5 based on what I wrote on Monday (July 1).</p>

<p>Anji, the troll Weapon Master, and Nepita's sister, Illa, a powerful witch, lurk in the forest on the other side of Razorpoint Ridge, while Illa practices an ancient troll song, titled <em>Flowing Stone</em>.  The song is extremely complex, but holds the power to wake the earth itself.  She completes the work and masters the difficult pronunciation.</p>

<p>As dawn comes, the trolls prepare to attack and Illa starts the magical song.  It normally requires a soprano, an alto and a tenor, all working together, taking turns to sing the song, but Illa is able to sing all of it, except the deepest notes at the very beginning.  Anji, as a natural tenor, helps her sing that portion and then leads the army to attack Razorpoint Refuge.</p>

<p>The song describes the earth as a pregnant mother, giving birth to her child (ash and smoke), effectively comparing lava to blood.  The song-based spell causes lava to pour into the deep coal mines of the dwarf fort, effectively filling it up from the inside, while frightened dwarves flee, most of them killed by the catastrophe!</p>

<p>King Windmaker, of the dwarves, is horrified to see his fears come to fruition as the seemingly impregnable fortress falls to magic, just as a screaming army of trolls comes around the ridge to attack!</p>

<p>At the same time, Illa passes out, because she misjudged the energy requirements of the spell, having gone far beyond her personal limits.  Fortunately, that means that instead of turning the whole mountain into an active volcano, it stops at just producing a large pool of lava spilling out of the fort's front gates.</p>

<h2>Chapter 6: Withermine</h2>

<p>Chapter 7 was actually written first, because inspiration struck me regarding the conclusion of the conflict at Razorpoint Refuge, but I often switch back and forth to different locations in my writing and I'll try to keep things simple on this blog by going in story order, here.</p>

<p>Most of the chapter follows Captain Shatterhand, the female dwarf officer in charge of the war-riders headed for Withermine.</p>

<p>Her unit is lost in fog that's settled in around the remote mining village and she's convinced they've been going in circles for hours on end.</p>

<p>There's a brief internal monologue about the swamp, which is filled with mythril deposits.  This section is designed to aid the reader's understanding of dwarven enchantment techniques and why mythril is so important to them.</p>

<p>Mythril acts as a natural magical purifier/concentrator, taking in the raw magic of the air, only to release it in a more pure and reactive form.  Magic effectively pools around it, building up over time until someone comes near, at which point the magic responds to their thoughts, producing randomized, chaotic spell-like bursts the dwarves call 'mythril surges'.</p>

<p>Dwarven enchantments normally consist of a small amount of mythril (an ounce or two) to serve as a power source for the magic, combined with dwarven runes, which act like an analog to an electrical circuit, transforming the raw magic the mythril produces into a more controlled, useful form.  Dwarven runes are effectively another form of natural magic, but they require the skill of an exceptional smith to do anything on their own.  An exceptional smith working with mythril can produce very powerful results, that var in direct proportion to how much mythril is used.</p>

<p>Shatterhand wishes their compasses would work, but one of the natural side effects of uncontrolled mythril makes compass needles spin.</p>

<p>She stops at some trees to determine north from the moss on the trunks, but there's moss on all sides.  However, she does see a wither-like blight in the leaves of the tree, marking their proximity to Withermine, because the trees are sick with toxic mythril poisoning.</p>

<p>One of her men, who has an excellent sense of direction, volunteers his opinion they should take a sharp turn left.  For lack of any better idea, she puts the dwarf in the lead.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the trolls waiting to ambush Withermine have been camping on a large island near their target.  Their leader, Aketa, hears the dwarven war-riders approaching, because the legs of them splash rather loudly.</p>

<p>She wakes her sister, Kina, ordering the woman to mask their presence with an illusion, while the trolls all press themselves into the rocks of the island.  Aketa takes position on a high rock, to give herself a good view, while Kina sings, causing them to visually meld into the rocks, masked with mental trickery.  Her singing comes to resemble a natural wind blowing through rocks, but since there's no wind, it sounds eerie and ghost-like.</p>

<p>Hearing the song and mistaking it for something caused by a mythril surge, Shatterhand advises her men to keep their thoughts focused on the mundane, to avoid danger, because the form of a surge is only limited by the imagination.</p>

<p>Shatterhand spots the island and cautiously marches her men and their war-riders onto it, finding some half-rotted bedding scattered about (the bedding of just the troll leaders, because most of the men have been doing without).  After a brief discussion, the dwarves conclude some adventurers likely got lost in the swamp and used the island as a temporary refuge, before dying off to the dangers of the place.</p>

<p>Shatterhand orders her men to inspect their war-riders for damage, while she spends her time tying to use the island to figure out which way north is, because though the island is on her map, she still isn't sure which way to go.</p>

<p>Kina turns her song into a lullaby, putting the dwarves to sleep, while Aketa stalks Shatterhand.  There's a brief fight in which Shatterhand refuses to back down and Aketa cuts the dwarf's throat.  While Shatterhand struggles to breathe in her dying moments, Aketa telepathically enters her mind, stealing knowledge of both Shatterhand's orders and how to drive a war-rider.</p>

<p>Withermine is wiped out with ease (off-screen, so to speak, since it doesn't really matter) and the trolls decide to use the war-riders to fool King Windmaker into trusting them. They head off to Flintbrook, where the dwarves are planning to rendezvous before heading into troll lands, to assault the Utros palace.</p>

<h2>Chapter 7: Hired Assassin</h2>

<p>The battle at Razorpoint Ridge is short, but intense.</p>

<p>King Windmaker initially struggles against the trolls, because there's thousands of them that swarm him en-masse, trying to climb all over his war-rider!  He spins in place, flinging them off, just in time for Anji to land on top of his war machine.  He tries to swat her with his war-rider's ax, but she's too fast, using her sickles to hook the sides of the rear hatch.</p>

<p>She uses her weapons to cut through the latch holding it closed and then flips her way onto the hatch like a ninja!  At the same time, King Windmaker snatches an ax off the wall of the cockpit and whirls around, aiming to cut her down!  Her wickedly-sharp sickles cut the head of the ax free, followed by cutting the handle from the shaft, leaving the king effectively unarmed.</p>

<p>She places her weapons to his throat and the king feigns surrender.  He knows what she doesn't, however: her sickles are dwarf made and in fact, his very own creations, which he gave to the troll king as a gesture of peace.  Dwarf made enchanted weapons normally will not harm the smith that made them, nor will they harm the king of the dwarves, so he punches Anji as hard as he can, shattering her nose!</p>

<p>She reacts by trying to cut his throat, but the sickles lose their sharpness, unable to do more than merely bruise him!  Anji starts to fall back, but the King refuses to let her escape, grabbing both of her wrists, using them to haul her in close, for a devastating head-butt that cracks her skull!</p>

<p>The King thinks Anji is a hired assassin, based on her attire and figure.  She wears blood-red clothing and armor, which marks her as a member of the <em>Sanguine Sisterhood</em>, a notorious band of supposedly human women that work as expensive hired killers.  However, he doesn't know the full truth; the <em>Sanguine Sisterhood</em> have always been troll women.</p>

<p>He decides to offer her payment, putting a bounty on the head of the troll king, Shengis, literally offering both a hefty sum of gold and enchanted weaponry to the assassin that produces the troll's head.</p>

<p>Anji agrees and King Windmaker tosses her broken body to the ground, with little expectation she'll survive her wounds, because he thinks she's human.</p>

<p>The battle is finished, with the troll army wiped out, but the victory is pyrrhic, since no one from the fort survived the melee.</p>

<p>Anji drags herself home, discovering along the way that the dwarves have found and captured Illa, though they actually think she was a prisoner of the trolls that were guarding her in her sleep.</p>

<h2>Chapter 8: False Riders</h2>

<p>King Windmaker and his men lurk in the ruins of Flinrbrook, horrified by the message the trolls left him, spelled out with dwarf corpses: <em>THE PRICE IS TEN-FOLD!</em></p>

<p>He knows the troll policy of responding with ten-fold force to any offense and even has no issue with it, knowing the enemies of Utros to the west, consisting of goblins and dark fairies, need a harsh hand, just to bring them to the negotiating table.</p>

<p>However, he doesn't understand the message, because he knows of no offense deserving of troll retribution, convinced the war began as a misunderstanding, though he knows it's already too late to stop the fighting.</p>

<p>As he's puzzled about the message, Aketa's troll-driven war-riders arrive, marching as if on parade in a city, rather than a more natural marching gait useful for crossing the wilderness, which makes no sense.  In addition, their leader is singing a dwarven song of triumph, leaving him wondering if they're drunk.</p>

<p>Putting the pieces together in his mind, he screams for his men to plug their ears and attack, leading to a desperate melee between war machines!</p>

<p>King Windomaker seeks the enemy leader in the midst of the brawl, eventually spotting the silver decorations of Captain Shatterhand's personal war-rider.</p>

<p>He shield-rushes her from behind, damaging her escape hatch and they both go down.  Getting a war-rider on its feet after a fall isn't easy and King Windmaker is the only one to have mastered performing an acrobatic stand in one, getting his war machine back on its feet nearly instantly, while Aketa is forced to move more slowly.</p>

<p>Halfway through raising her war-rider's torso, the king's ax smashes through her window, while she dodges, inside her cockpit!  The ax smashes through the cockpit and into the steam chamber, below, releasing super-heated steam that burns every inch of Aketa's body!</p>

<p>Knowing she'll never heal properly, due to the weakness of trolls to being burned, she goes all-in on a suicide attack, using the King's backward yank of his ax to free it as the means to launch herself at his cockpit window, aiming her sword for his eye!</p>

<p>She smashes through the glass, but her weapon betrays her, pulling to one side of its own accord!  She lands on the King, who head-butts her, cracking her skull, before he grabs her sword and beheads her!</p>

<p>He kicks her body out the window and then sets his war-rider to slowly turn in place, holding Aketa's head up for all to see as he shows the trolls he's taken their leader's head and demands their surrender.</p>

<p>They back down and the battle is won.</p>

<p>Kina watches the battle via a telescope while she hides with the remainder of the troll forces (there weren't enough war-riders for all of them).</p>

<p>While the dwarves are distracted with their prisoners, Kina retrieves her sister and holds the head in place, so Aketa doesn't actually die.  In wasn't sisterly love that motivated her, but rather duty to the Queen.</p>

<p>Aketa is carried back by the men and Kina drives their only remaining war-rider back to the Utros mountains, so they can report on the unexpected capabilities of the dwarves and give her the captured war machine, for study.</p>

<h2>Chapter 9: The Icy Maiden</h2>

<p>Illa wakes in a dwarf hospital in the palace of their capital city, Wind Hammer.  Kadrek is in the bed beside her own and is totally infatuated with her, because she's very attractive.</p>

<p>Knowing she's too weak to get home on her own, she plays the femme fatale and leans into his attraction, pretending to be the daughter of a human gunsmith, who was killed by the trolls.  She hopes to recover her strength and then magically brainwash Kadrek, that he might carry supplies for her on the way home, ultimately planning to give him to Nepita as a hostage.</p>

<p>The dwarf reminds Illa of her first love, who was murdered by Nepita for being a rather out-spoken male (at great risk to his life, he pursued Illa, rather than the other way around).</p>

<p>Over the course of days, they speak at length, the friendship between them grows and Illa starts to lose herself to the role she's taken on, because Kadrek really has grown to love her and she's begun to feel the same.</p>

<p>Kadrek has the healers take them to the surface in wheelchairs and there, he gets on his feet.  It's obvious that standing on his injured feet is like walking on daggers for him.  He flexes his muscles in the sun and Illa's heart beats faster!</p>

<p>Illa mentally reminds herself in a somewhat shaky fashion, <em>He’s a means to an end.  He’s a means to an end!  My gosh, he’s an</em> attractive <em>means to an end!</em></p>

<p>Seeing her expression, he winks and flexes his bicep, showing off.  She finds her will weakening, but dredges up some pride in her trollish heritage to fight back with, reminding herself that she's of royal blood, sister to the Queen and the greatest witch Utros has seen in five-hundred years.</p>

<p>Kadrek asks her if she wants to dance and Illa is overcome by the romance of it: he's in serious pain, but still wants to dance with her!</p>

<p>In one final attempt to cling to her cold, icy heart, she (truthfully) tells him she's too weak to stand.</p>

<p>He offers to support both their weight and the last of the ice in Illa's heart melts, allowing a metaphorical avalanche of released ice and water to bury her trollish pride, once and for all, falling head over heels for the charming dwarf.</p>

<p>She agrees and Kadrek picks her up, supporting her weight, despite his injured feet, seemingly oblivious to the pain, because he's holding the woman he loves as he slowly bobs from foot to foot.</p>

<p>Illa makes up her mind to tell him the truth, but knows the time isn't right.  She fears it's too soon and she'll be killed for who she really is.  She leans into her feelings and pushes their relationship forward by kissing Kadrek as passionately as she knows how, because she needs him to fall head over heels for her.</p>

<h2>Chapter 10: Exile</h2>

<p>Finally well enough to leave the hospital, Illa is put in a cottage on the palace grounds set aside for elf visitors.  The interior is decorated with wood furniture carved with leafy patterns.  The bed has green sheets and pillows.  Light streams in through a colorful, stained-glass window.</p>

<p>She sits on the edge of the bed, wearing a blue, silk dress the same shade as her eyes, which was originally made for a dwarf, though it was expertly cut down to fit her very slender frame by the palace seamstress.  Her legs are a little long for it, leaving it hanging at mid-calf height, but that's just fine, because that's the current fashion among human women.  Her hair is tied back with a matching scarf.</p>

<p>Kadrek arrives, dressed in a red tunic and matching felt hat, with a shiny, mythril belt buckle that emanates heavy magic.</p>

<p>The plan is for the two of them to spend a day walking around town, because they're both finally well enough for it.</p>

<p>That's as far as I got for the week, but I know how the chapter will end. The King has returned to the city with troll prisoners, who will recognize Illa and try to get her to help them, blowing her cover.</p>

<p>Kadrek will defend Illa with his life, taking up arms against the King's men.  The two of them will be captured and hauled before the King, who will hear their stories.  Illa will finally come clean and Kadrek will continue to stand with her.</p>

<p>Unable to bring himself to kill his son's beloved, the King will instead disown Kadrek, marry them on the spot, then exile them from the kingdom, likely giving Kadrek the parting gift of a fat purse filled with gold, that they might make their way to Oswil, where they're sure to be accepted.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_writing.html'>writing</a>, <a href='tag_work-in-progress.html'>work-in-progress</a>, <a href='tag_rumors-of-war.html'>rumors-of-war</a></p>

<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://owentyme.us/blog/work-in-progress-2-troll-war-2-july-1-5.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/blog/./work-in-progress-2-troll-war-2-july-1-5.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Owen Tyme</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 10:30:08 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Work in Progress #1: Troll War #1 (June 21-28)
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>Eight days ago, I started work on one of my many planned novels, <a href="../books.html#troll-war">Troll War</a></p>

<p>For a while now, I've been thinking it might be fun to write a little something about each day's writing, as a sort of journal of my work in progress.</p>

<p>I'll be doing this on Mastodon for daily posts and on this blog for more in-depth information every weekend.</p>

<p>To start the ball rolling, I've been posting my daily updates on Mastodon all week: <a href="https://mastodon.social/@OwenTyme/112672253855096568">https://mastodon.social/@OwenTyme/112672253855096568</a></p>

<p>These are each short, normally detailing one chapter, because that's roughly my minimum average output.  From time to time I may post twice in a day, if I've done things that need to be broken up.</p>

<p>The rest of this post will be my first weekly update.</p>

<h2>Basics of the Setting</h2>

<p>Troll War takes place in a galaxy not unlike our own, on a world similar to Earth, though with the addition of magic.  It won't play too big a part in the novel, but there's a whole galaxy of sci-fi wonders out there, including an AI species that's consuming the resources of the galaxy to spread like a plague, but that won't become a big part of the story until book 2, <a href="../books.html#ai-war">AI War</a>.</p>

<p>The series is titled <a href="../books.html#rumors-of-war">Rumors of War</a>.</p>

<p>This as yet unnamed world (the inhabitants probably call their planet some uncreative translation of the word 'dirt', just like we do) includes a variety of fantasy races.  So far, I've only mentioned humans, elves, dwarves, trolls, gnomes, goblins and dark fairies (but this implies the inclusion of light fairies).  The other races will likely play a part in book 3, <a href="../books.html#magic-war">Magic War</a>.</p>

<p>As for technological level, I'm intentionally breaking with tradition and not using a medieval setting, placing the people of the various races collectively somewhat beyond the Victorian-era of technology, with a fantastic flare, but only when considered as a homogeneous people, which they most certainly are not.</p>

<h3>Dwarves</h3>

<p>The dwarves have advanced steam technology and metallurgy, including vehicles and trains of all kind, but have stuck by their old melee weapons, shields and armor, because the best firearms they've managed on their own are muskets, though they don't know the secret to making black powder or gunpowder, getting that from humans.  Their axes do include one-shot muskets, however, in place of the ax handle.</p>

<p>Dwarves don't use magic directly, but their best craftsmen are somewhat mysteriously able to craft magic items and their magic is always of the best quality.  They do this by starting with magical materials they've dug from the ground, such as mythril.</p>

<h3>Humans</h3>

<p>The humans are most advanced in firearms and the family of Lady Gunn (see below) are the principle inventors of guns.  In particular, repeating pistols and rifles will play a part in battle later in the book, once things really get going.</p>

<h3>Elves</h3>

<p>Elves mostly eschew technology in favor of magic, but they have nothing against purchasing technological items from other races, if they find them useful.  This may change over time or it may not.  I'm undecided, but the local elves in the book are very much linked to the humans, since they're governed by the same king.</p>

<h3>Trolls</h3>

<p>Trolls are surprisingly advanced in medicine, because they have the advantage of being able to experiment with bodies that rapidly regenerate and the real truth is that their doctors (if you could call them that!) are able to produce frightening abominations of biology that would terrify even modern men, shaping the bodies of trolls until they become something new and horrifying.</p>

<p>It isn't uncommon for a troll to reattach severed limbs and with the assistance of another, they can reattach a severed head.</p>

<p>It isn't obvious to an outsider, but troll women look just like human women, aside from being exceptionally attractive, with starkly-white hair.</p>

<p>Troll women are all effectively witches, with a style of music-based magic unique to them.  They prefer, but are not limited to mental magic, with a heavy emphasis on telepathy.  Illusions come almost as easy to them.</p>

<p>Trolls strongly believe that might makes right.  They're secretly ruled by their women, because their magic makes them believe they're superior to men and the men have never been strong enough to resist.</p>

<h3>Notable Kingdoms</h3>

<p>Oswil is the human/elf kingdom, to the north of the main trade road.  The southern end of the kingdom is human land and the north end is elf land, though they all live under the rule of a human king.</p>

<p>To the southwest of Oswil is Utros, the troll kingdom, which is outwardly ruled by King Shengis, though he's actually a puppet of the troll Queen, Nepita.  Utros is mostly in the mountains and the land is rich with iron.</p>

<p>To the southeast of Oswil is Fortune Fields, the dwarf kingdom, which is mostly a large, open plain, though there are swamps and mountains on the western edge.  The land is rich with copper, iron, silver and gold.</p>

<p>The three kingdoms form the primary setting of <a href="../books.html#troll-war">Troll War</a>.</p>

<h2>Prologue</h2>

<p>The majority of the prologue was written as a result of some inspiration about five months ago and on Friday of last week (the 21st), I did some clean-up work and then finished it.</p>

<p>This initial scene takes place in a tavern on the southern outskirts of the human kingdom of Oswil, which hosts bare knuckle matches with very few rules.</p>

<p>On this particular day, a human noblewoman, Lady Gunn, has been invited to join another noble, an elf wizard named Lord Rolar.  Lady Gunn isn't pleased by how dirty the tavern is, but she's pleased by the fine wine her companion offers her and a match between a dwarf and a troll begins.</p>

<p>Dwarves are well-known for how sturdy they are, on top of being incredibly stubborn.  Their fighting spirit is second to none and getting a dwarf to back down is next to impossible.  This particular dwarf is used to slowly wearing his opponents down by having far greater endurance, on top of being able to punch like a fully-loaded mine cart.</p>

<p>Trolls, on the other hand, have the wondrous power to regenerate from most any wound, a power they use to out-last most any opponent they might face in battle.  This particular troll is used to taking hits and growing back, outlasting his opponents though masochism and an incredible tolerance for pain.</p>

<p>Lady Gunn is soon drawn into the fight, selecting the dwarf as her choice of champion to cheer for.</p>

<p>The one-on-one fight rages for six hours, until the dwarf is exhausted, but still standing and the troll is on his feet, but he's begun to exhaust his body's resources useful for regeneration, starting to lose his edge though hunger.</p>

<p>The tiny thought I had in the back of my mind for this is that each time a troll heals, they become slightly more hungry.  While they're able to recycle damaged cells and restore their bodies, there's a lasting cost in the form of a metabolic price that must be paid to activate the magic used for this.</p>

<p>Both combatants are at the end of their rope, breathing heavily and the troll isn't regenerating anymore, because he's too hungry.  They nod to each other with mutual respect.</p>

<p>The dwarf asks, "Shall we end this by putting everything we've got into one last exchange?"</p>

<p>The troll agrees and they both abandon defense, charging each other for one, final strike!  The troll dies as a result and the dwarf is briefly praised as the winner, but just as he starts a speech about his victory, he falls dead, min-sentence.</p>

<p>Seeing the results, Lord Rolar asks, "To the south of Oswil, we have two nations, Fortune Fields and Utros, ruled by dwarves and trolls, respectively.  After this evening's spectacle, can you imagine what might happen if circumstances conspired to send them to war?"</p>

<p>Lady Gunn proposes they settle the question with their usual bet at stake: thirty silver pieces.</p>

<h2>Chapter 1: Don't Kill the Messenger!</h2>

<p>Nepita, Queen of the Trolls sits upon her throne in the great hall of Utros, surrounded by the women of her court, feeling bored.</p>

<p>He thoughts are interrupted by a nervous boy entering the room, carrying a message from the troll king, Shengis, claiming an elf has been captured entering the kingdom.</p>

<p>Nepita invited the boy to come closer and realizes she's looking at her own son, who she handed off to her mate to raise, once he was weaned.  She feels a strangely sudden sense of attachment to the fourteen year old boy and grants him the title of 'Prince', similar to the way she granted her mate the title of 'King'.  She orders her right-hand woman, Anji, the Weapon Master, to take the boy away for training, then orders her sister, Illa, to test the boy for magic potential, which flies in the face of tradition.</p>

<p>Nepita silences the resulting argument with a thunderous shout and then orders the room cleared.  She may have a sentimental side, but Nepita is also unpredictable and beyond deadly.  She respected by the entire court due to the way she broke every bone in her grandmother's body, to gain the throne.  She's also well-known for revisiting any offense ten-fold, which is her standing international policy.</p>

<p>Raising her voice in song, Nepita touches the mind of her mate, Shengis, that she might use him like a puppet.</p>

<p>Through his eyes, she observes the elf prisoner, who explains his presence by offering up a journal taken from an ill-fated party of dwarves that had been on a spying mission inside troll lands.</p>

<p>It is hinted, but not spelled out that this elf is Lord Rolar, last seenin the prologue.</p>

<p>Nepita speed-reads the journal and is both furious with the dwarves and eager for war, because it will interrupt her boredom.</p>

<p>Disconnecting her mind from Shengis, she calls Anji back into the room, giving orders for the coming conflict.</p>

<h2>Chapter 2: Disturbing the Peace</h2>

<p>King Gorgo Windmaker, the Tenth, King of the kingdom of Fortune Fields, receives a guest.</p>

<p>Lady Gunn hands over a journal she claims was captured from trolls, which details their spying operation and observations of the dwarf kingdom.</p>

<p>King Windmaker values his profitable business relationship and even friendship with the trolls, despite their obvious differences, but he can't ignore the journal, so he sends his son, Prince Kadrek, as an envoy to Utros, to seek a peaceful conclusion to the conflict.</p>

<p>The price has an eerie journey up the canyon leading to the palace of Utros, until he hears singing that absolutely entrances him, drawing him every forward, until he lays eyes on four troll women.  He stares at them in a trace as his men are slaughtered, but just as he's about to be killed, their leader, Anji, recognizes him, having sen the Prince though her mate's eyes.</p>

<p>She orders the prince stripped, shaved and his memory of troll women wiped, then sends him on ahead, for interrogation.  The Prince is put to sleep by a magic lullaby.</p>

<h2>Chapter 3: Declaration of War</h2>

<p>When Kadrek wakes, he faces Shengis and Nepita looks on him through her mate's eyes.</p>

<p>He explains his presence and begs for peace, but neither of the troll rulers believes him, thinking his father sent him under false pretenses.</p>

<p>They hear him out, then give him an ultimatum to deliver, before giving him the night to rest, because eh it's a long, naked, barefoot run back to the palace of Fortune Fields, which he should make sure he hurries to complete, because he has limited time to warn his father before two more villages are destroyed (he's informed of the plan to destroy Flintbrook; see next paragraph).</p>

<p>While the prince sleeps, Anji and her army arrive at the smallest dwarf village along the border to Utros, Flintbrook.  They slaughter every dwarf they find, not even sparing the children, and arrange the bodies to spell out a horrifying message: <em>THE PRICE IS TEN-FOLD!</em>  They leave no stone of the village standing on another, using bursts of magic to level every structure they find.</p>

<p>At dawn, the prince is released and he runs the entire way, leaving his feet a bleeding mess.  He collapses in the throne room and tells his father he must immediately respond with his acceptance of the destruction of Flintbrook or be prepared to lose Withermine and Razorpoint Refuge, followed by all-out war.</p>

<p>Last of all, he warns his father the soldiers should plug their ears and not listen to the singing, before he passes out.</p>

<h2>Chapter 4: War Machine</h2>

<p>Furious, King Windmaker shouts, "By Nobris, <em>ye don't shave a dwarf's beard!</em>"</p>

<p>Here's a helpful quote from what I've written, to explain:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Nobris was the god of dwarves, industry and beards, who was widely believed to have gifted the dwarf race with their talent for mining and crafting.  According to legend, he’d also given them their beards, which grew thicker and longer than the hair of women.  To a dwarf, their very beard was a sacred, god-given gift and shaving it off was said to be an affront to Nobris, whom they praised more than any other god.  In short, the trolls hadn’t just shamed the prince, but they’d also insulted Nobris.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Kadrek is carried off by the healers, while the King erupts in orders to prepare his kingdom for war.  In particular, he orders his war-riders gathered at the west gate, then makes his way to the back of a statue set behind his throne, climbing a ladder to the platform, which allows access to the interior of the statue, which is filled with buttons, levers and other controls.  He opens the shutters covering the windshield of the definitely-not-a-statue, allowing more light in, then shuts the back hatch.</p>

<p>He activates the steam engine in the belly of his war-rider, which is actually a huge, steam-powered mech shaped like a giant dwarf armed with an ax and shield.  Likewise, the war-riders occupied by his royal guardsmen come to life and they march down the hall, though a huge pair of brass-shod doors.</p>

<p>They emerge on the main street of the royal city and every dwarf witnesses the huge machines in motion, coming to the same conclusion: the kingdom is at war.  The workers on their way home from work turn around to volunteer for another shift, while the busy streets are soon cleared, as every man, woman and child among the dwarves sets out to contribute to the war effort, as one lone street vendor, who used to be a royal guardsman sheds a tear for the looming future and the loss of peace, likely with the only joy being the joy of fighting.</p>

<h2>Chapter 5: Bloody Razor</h2>

<p>I didn't get very far on this chapter, doing little more than writing descriptions as King Windmaker's war-riders gather, then set out, one two companies off to Withermine, while he takes another two off to Razorpoint Refuge.</p>

<p>Razonpoint Refuge is a fort built at the deepest portion of a crescent-shaped mountain named Razorpoint Ridge.  The interior of Razorpoint Ridge faces into Fortune Fields and is topped with razor-sharp obsidian, while the prevailing wind blows right into it.  The top is high enough that it touches and shaves the bottom off of clouds, causing the land beneath to often fill with fog, incidentally watering the crops for the dwarves living there.</p>

<p>Not only is it fruitful land, but also extremely defensible, so the King's father built a fort there, using the excuse of defending the nearby trade road, to the north, to justify putting a fort so close to troll lands.</p>

<p>King Windmaker splits his force in two, placing them near each tip of the crescent, that they might use a pincer attack when the trolls inevitably come.</p>

<p>Depite the fact backup is on the way, the King worries: Razorpoint Refuge is an impenetrable fortress, impossible to take by force, and yet, the trolls openly declared it as one of their first targets in the war, as if it were a place of weakness.  He can't help but wonder what they know that he doesn't.</p>

<p>The answer will become clear on Monday, when I resume writing, but I'm leaning toward it being a matter of troll women and their magic.  On the other hand, the trolls have no idea the dwarven war-riders even exist, so it should be a really fun opening battle for the war, with unexpected outcomes on both sides.  However, unless I change the chapter title, the battle is going to be bloody.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_writing.html'>writing</a>, <a href='tag_work-in-progress.html'>work-in-progress</a>, <a href='tag_rumors-of-war.html'>rumors-of-war</a></p>

<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://owentyme.us/blog/work-in-progress-1-troll-war-june-21-28.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/blog/./work-in-progress-1-troll-war-june-21-28.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Owen Tyme</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 16:57:34 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
More Short Stories
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>After spending an inordinate amount of time fiddling with the details, including small adjustments to CSS files to allow for the posting of properly-formatted prose on my website, I've posted a pair of my old short stories from the days when I put my work up on Wattpad.</p>

<p>The first of these is Community Service Fairy Godmother and the second is Sweet Surrender, which will become the next two entries in my <a href="../short_stories.html#shorts">Short of Tyme</a> series.  You can find links to their pages there or click on the titles, below.</p>

<p>Neither has cover art at the moment, because I don't wish to re-use their old AI-generated cover art.  They'll get another pass of editing sometime before they get new covers illustrated by Ryan Johnson, the artist I work with.  As soon as both tasks are done, they'll be published in the usual fashion.</p>

<p>I should soon be posting more stories, because I have more to share, but for now, I hope you'll enjoy these little gems.</p>

<h2><a href="../shorts/short-of-tyme/community-service-fairy-godmother.html">Community Service Fairy Godmother</a></h2>

<blockquote>
  <p>Seeing systemic injustice in the laws established by the Queen of the Fairies, <em>may she reign forever</em>, Sophorica breaks them to draw attention to their absurdity, literally painting New York City red.  After all, if the only crime is to be caught and any offense can be forgiven simply by being sneaky, then the law itself can only be considered a cruel joke.</p>

<p>Her crime is expunged from history and the human race is none the wiser, but the Queen, <em>may she reign forever</em>, sentences Sophorica to perform one act of community service in the human realm for each human witness.  This service takes the form of granting wishes to human children as their fairy godmother, until they're happy.</p>

<p>However, the awful truth is that granting wishes rarely brings happiness, forcing Sophorica to learn as much as she can about her charges, that she might get them to wish for what they really need, rather than what they want.</p>

<p>Will Sophorica find a way to free herself from the twisted, unjust punishment wrought by the Queen, <em>may she reign forever</em>, successfully demonstrating the flaws in fairy law or will she be forever banished to the human world as a Fairy Godmother?</p>
</blockquote>

<h2><a href="../shorts/short-of-tyme/sweet-surrender.html">Sweet Surrender</a></h2>

<blockquote>
  <p>In this trio of linked tales, learn what happens when the unstoppable force meets the immovable object.</p>

<p>In the first tale, a priestess to the god of empathy never wanted to involve herself in politics, but when her king seeks riches from the kingdom at the expense of the common man, she's forced to put herself directly in the path of the King's armies, who are under strict orders to turn her away, even if it means killing her.  Unfortunately for them, they didn't count on the pain they inflict on her reflecting back!</p>

<p>In the second tale, nobles discuss Aaron Kozinski, an amazing guard that never fails in his duty, no matter how bleak the situation, all in exchange for a little money, that he might eat and pay rent.  He stands guard in horrendous weather and even repels assassins, preventing them from coming anywhere near his employer, all without complaint.</p>

<p>In the concluding tale, the two are manipulated into conflict by a mysterious man that hopes they'll destroy each other.</p>

<p>Will the priestess learn enough about Aaron to ease his pain or will she be overwhelmed by his hopelessly broken heart?</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_short-story.html'>short-story</a>, <a href='tag_writing.html'>writing</a>, <a href='tag_publishing.html'>publishing</a></p>

<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://owentyme.us/blog/more-short-stories.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/blog/./more-short-stories.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Owen Tyme</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 13:26:59 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Shame On Me, I Guess, Part III
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>Despite my earlier posts regarding how much I dislike the social-media-platform-that-shall-remain-nameless, I got used to using it as an additional platform on which to toot my horn and gain some fans.</p>

<p>I had hoped to reach a larger audience, but now regret my choice to use that website for more than just an experiment.</p>

<h2>What Happened?</h2>

<p>I released <a href="../books/ashen-blades/demon-for-president.html">Demon for President!</a>, which is a political satire piece, in which a demon runs for President of the United States.</p>

<p>I posted about it a few times via a science-fiction and fantasy group that I'd taken a liking to, which requires <strong>manual approval</strong> for all posts before they're shown publicly.  The group admin had no issue with what I was doing and approved.  He often hit like on my posts in the past, as well.  Not that one, but political satire isn't everyone's cup of tea, so fair enough.</p>

<p>Then yesterday, the social-media-platform-that-shall-remain-nameless pulled every last one of my posts to the group over a supposed rule violation for "fraud and deceptive practices".  The group admin was absolutely mystified by this, because he knew as well as I that I wasn't deceiving anyone.  Any human being that read my posts would have come to the same conclusion.</p>

<p>The software (probably AI) that the social-media-platform-that-shall-remain-nameless uses to moderate literally cannot tell the difference between language related to selling a political satire book and an attempt to get people to vote for a non-existent demon that's running for president.</p>

<p>The absurdity of this is actually quite astonishing to me.</p>

<p>Based on the message that was shoved in my face over this unjust enforcement of their rules, they literally claim the rules for their website are not just enforced by software, but that no human being was even involved in checking the software's work.  I have no option to appeal and no opportunity to seek for this to be made right.</p>

<p>In short, they must have fired their human moderators and replaced them with software as a result of their worship of the almighty dollar and desire to cut costs all the way to the bone.</p>

<p>Yes, companies exist to make a profit, but long-term profits have never been found by tying up the end-user, so they can't resist (monopolistic practices), dropping drawers and squatting down on the end user's face (disrespecting the user), followed by defecating into their screaming, open mouth (expecting them to take whatever is dished out, no matter how vile).</p>

<p>That is a disgusting state of affairs, which can only lead to further injustice and it's simply bad business.  Period.</p>

<p>It's also a matter of squashing people's right to voice themselves.  Yeah, I know, the first amendment doesn't apply, because they own the website, not the government, but squashing people's rights has never been a good business decision in the long run, because the users will leave like rats bailing from a sinking ship, sooner or later.</p>

<h2>What Now?</h2>

<p>I will never use the social-media-platform-that-shall-remain-nameless again, not even for an experiment.  My page there will remain up for another month or two, just to give the people I'm leaving behind a chance to see what happened and point the way to greener pastures.</p>

<p>I doubt they'll follow, but I'll at least have the satisfaction of knowing I've done the right thing by trying to raise the warning flag.</p>

<h2>Alternatives?</h2>

<p><a href="https://joinmastodon.org/">Mastodon</a> is a wonderful social media platform that I can't praise enough, which mimics the interface of the social-media-platform-formerly-known-as-twitter.  I've been welcomed by the people that use it, the platform itself treats me with respect and the rules for the server I use are really quite short and straight to the point.  I've been using it about the same amount of time as the social-media-platform-that-shall-remain-nameless, but I've had far more success there.</p>

<p><a href="https://mastodon.social/@OwenTyme">Here's my Mastodon profile, in case you're interested.</a></p>

<p>I've also recently discovered <a href="https://join-lemmy.org/">Lemmy</a>, which is a decentralized forum system that operates similar to Mastodon, based on the same underlying technology (<a href="https://activitypub.rocks/">ActivityPub</a>).  I'll probably be using this in the future, but I've also been considering using <a href="https://www.reddit.com/">Reddit</a>, because it has a larger user-base.</p>

<h2>Pulling Back the Curtain...</h2>

<p>The social-media-platform-that-shall-remain-nameless is Facebook, by the way.  It's been said before and I'm sure it will be said many times more, but the company isn't worth trusting.  Their business practices are atrocious and the only reason they haven't failed is because they're so huge, with so many users, no one can stand the idea of leaving their family and friends behind, even though they'd like to stop using that website.</p>

<p>My suggestion: it's time to walk away.  Sometimes, you just have to cross the bridge and then burn it down before the vicious wolves nipping at your heels can reach you.</p>

<p>I should have stuck to my original opinion and never bothered with Facebook, but that's where the people are and I was just trying to promote my novels.</p>

<p>From now on, I'll remember this lesson and hopefully this article series won't get a fourth entry, because that really would be embarrassing for me.  "Shame on me", indeed.</p>

<h2>What I'll be Doing</h2>

<p>Facebook effectively tried to censor one of my books, so would anyone be interested in reading <a href="../books/ashen-blades/demon-for-president.html">"The Novel Facebook Tried to Silence!"</a>  Somehow, I suspect that's a line that will sell books...</p>

<h2>Evidence and What I Left Behind</h2>

<p>I wish I had screenshots of the posts Facebook removed, but I've got nothing left of most of them due to Facebook wiping them out.</p>

<p>Facebook wiped out at least three promotional group posts (once again, I remind you that these <strong>required</strong> admin approval to be shown) related to <a href="../books/ashen-blades/demon-for-president.html">Demon for President!</a>.  First was a short post with just the cover and a description of the book, mostly word for word copied from the back cover text, along with the book's cover</p>

<p>Second, I used my ad flyer, which shows off the Republican and Democrat personas of the villain of the book, along with I believe more or less the same text as the previous post.  I may have added a little blurb to describe the series, but I'm not sure.</p>

<p>Last of all was a post offering free Ebooks in exchange for honest reviews.  It was only tangentially related to <a href="../books/ashen-blades/demon-for-president.html">Demon for President!</a>, in that it displayed the cover of it.</p>

<p>There was no act of fraud and no intent to deceive anyone in any of this, despite Facebook's unjust claims of such.  I was just trying to promote my most recently published novel and get some much-needed reviews, as any self-published author would.</p>

<h3>Post #1: Reconstructed Book Announcement</h3>

<p>This is as close as I can get to the original text of the post I made announcing the publishing of <a href="../books/ashen-blades/demon-for-president.html">Demon for President!</a>.  I can't guarantee the text is 100% as it was, but this should be quite close, because most of it was a copy+paste from the same sources and it was just a re-arranged and expanded version of one of my Mastodon posts:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Book #3 of Ashen Blades, Demon for President! is now available for pre-order, coming to online bookstores June 10, 2024: <a href="https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/demon-for-president.html">https://owentyme.us/books/ashen-blades/demon-for-president.html</a></p>

<p>When a snake demon in an expensive, tailored suit takes an irreverent stab at American Presidential politics, the Hunter is literally forced to take a stab at him, to save the USA from getting a Demon for President!</p>

<p>The Hunter’s demonic arch-nemesis, Vogerath, returns to Earth once more, but this time, he’s running for President of the United States, on the 2024 ballot! Worse yet, the demon’s unique power to be in multiple places at once allows him to convincingly pretend to be identical twins, running as both a Republican and Democrat!</p>

<p>The other candidates all drop out of the race under mysterious circumstances and with his best competition being himself, he’s practically assured a win!</p>

<p>Soon, the American people are lapping up the snake-in-a-suit’s every word as if it were ambrosia, calling out his name at every turn, magically charmed to believe he’s the best thing since sliced bread, despite the checkered, criminal history of his “family.”</p>

<p>Hard pressed to get rid of him, the half-demon Hunter and her allies kill him repeatedly, but he pops back up like a bad weed, making all of his appointments on time, photogenically kissing babies, cutting the ribbons of stores and donating laundered blood-money to charitable causes.</p>

<p>Will the hunter manage to end the demon’s presidential campaign before election day? If she doesn’t, the USA may just get a Demon for President! Buy this book today and find out for yourself!</p>

<p><img src="../images/Cover-Full-DemonForPresident.jpg" alt="" title="" /></p>
</blockquote>

<h3>Post #2: The Flyer</h3>

<p>Days later, I finally came up with a proper flyer for the book, along with some ad text I was happy with.  I can't recall the text for this one, but I think it was nearly identical to the previous post, because I was rather tired at the time and in a lazy mood.  I think it was posted on June 8th, but it might have been the 9th.  I'm not sure.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><img src="../images/Flyer-DemonForPresident.jpg" alt="" title="" /></p>
</blockquote>

<h3>Post #3: The Review Request</h3>

<p>I'm lucky I saved the text of the last of my censored posts, because I intended to use it elsewhere (and yes, that giveaway code is still good):</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>FREE Ebooks!  Use the code 'P6YFQ' via this link to get free Ebooks of my novels: https://www.smashwords.com/profile/view/OwenTyme</p>

<p>If you use this code, then please write an honest review as soon as you've read each book.  The truth is I really do need the reviews, just to prime the pump a bit.  After all, almost no one will take a chance on a book with no reviews.</p>

<p>Please post reviews to the sites you usually buy from, because most online book sellers, including Amazon and Barnes and Noble, will allow you to post a review without making a purchase.</p>

<p>All of my currently published novels are available to you, including Troll Song, Forgotten Legends, The Third Wish, She Hunts Demons, She Goes to War and Demon for President!  My always free short stories are also available, including Emergent Consequences and She Goes to Summer Camp.  So, yes, my entire catalog of works are free to you through June 30th, after which the code expires.</p>

<p>Here are some examples of sites on which you can write reviews (each link should point to a list of my published works):</p>

<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s?i=digital-text&amp;rh=p_27%3AOwen+Tyme&amp;s=relevancerank&amp;text=Owen+Tyme">https://www.amazon.com/s?i=digital-text&amp;rh=p_27%3AOwen+Tyme&amp;s=relevancerank&amp;text=Owen+Tyme</a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/45452178.Owen_Tyme">https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/45452178.Owen_Tyme</a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.barnesandnoble.com/s/%22Owen%20Tyme%22">https://www.barnesandnoble.com/s/%22Owen%20Tyme%22</a></p>

<p><a href="https://fable.co/author/owen-tyme">https://fable.co/author/owen-tyme</a></p>

<p><img src="../images/special/review-request-june-2024.jpg" alt="" title="" /></p>
</blockquote>

<h3>What the Admin Posted</h3>

<p>You can find the post from the admin of the group here: <a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/scififan/permalink/8044035455647552/">https://www.facebook.com/groups/scififan/permalink/8044035455647552/</a></p>

<p>And because I want as much of the evidence out of Facebook's hands as possible, here's a screenshot of the message, including the screenshot he posted and was confused over, along with my comment:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><img src="../images/special/what-the-admin-said.jpg" alt="" title="" /></p>
</blockquote>

<p>Note the other comment: another witness of the awful over-reaching of the rules, along with willful ignorance of other infractions.</p>

<p>To summarize: no one asked for this unjust enforcement of rules, no one is happy about it and even the admin of the group is mystified about why it happened!</p>

<h3>What the Admin Asked Me</h3>

<p>The admin also reached out to me.  Here's a screenshot of our brief conversation on the matter:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><img src="../images/special/what-the-admin-asked-me.jpg" alt="" title="" /></p>
</blockquote>

<p>At the time he reached out, I was only aware my review request post had been taken down (I suspected it was because of the use of "we" in the image), but after answering him I dug a little deeper, finding three or possibly four of my posts were gone, all related to the political satire piece, so I think that was the real cause.</p>

<h3>Post #4: The Goodbye Post From My Facebook Page</h3>

<p>Finally, here's a quote from my last post on Facebook, for the sake of preservation, in case it gets censored just like my group posts about my novel:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I'm done with this social media platform.  I don't like the way they enforce their rules (all done with software, with no human to review what the software does, plus no one can appeal to a human over unjust rule enforcement by that software).</p>

<p>They've unjustly applied their rules to me on multiple occasions, sometimes due to over-zealous software that can't grasp the subtleties of human communication and other times because of a literal bug in their software that got me slapped with rule violations for an ad I didn't even run, the form for which was auto-populated by their own software.</p>

<p>Yes, I'm serious: the software filled the form and then punished me for the content of it, before I could even change it.
I'm tired of how broken this website is.  Period.
So, I won't be posting here anymore.  I'll leave the page up for now, to get the word out, but when I'm ready (probably in a month or two), it will come down.</p>

<p>If you still want to follow my work on a social media platform, try my Mastodon profile, which is where I'm most active: <a href="https://mastodon.social/@OwenTyme">https://mastodon.social/@OwenTyme</a></p>

<p>Alternatively, you can bookmark my website and visit from time to time, because I update it often: <a href="https://owentyme.us">https://owentyme.us</a>
My website includes a blog you can subscribe to with an RSS reader: <a href="https://owentyme.us/blog/">https://owentyme.us/blog/</a></p>

<p>Finally, if you just want to chat with me, my E-mail address has always been public: <a href="&#109;&#x61;&#105;&#x6C;&#x74;&#x6F;:o&#119;&#x65;&#x6E;&#116;&#x79;&#x6D;&#x65;&#64;&#111;&#x77;&#101;&#110;&#x74;&#x79;&#109;&#101;&#46;&#117;&#x73;">o&#119;&#x65;&#x6E;&#116;&#x79;&#x6D;&#x65;&#64;&#111;&#x77;&#101;&#110;&#x74;&#x79;&#109;&#101;&#46;&#117;&#x73;</a></p>

<p>Good luck to all of you that are staying behind.  I'm sure the rule-enforcement bots are coming for you next, since we apparently live in a dystopian future ruled by robots.</p>
</blockquote>

<h2>Final Thoughts</h2>

<p>Sorry this post is far longer than my typical blog entry, but I wanted to both express my feelings and set aside some evidence of Facebook's shameful behavior for the sake of warning others.</p>

<p>I hope you learned something of value from my experience, because perhaps that would make it all worth it.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_social-media.html'>social-media</a>, <a href='tag_social-media-platform-that-shall-remain-nameless.html'>social-media-platform-that-shall-remain-nameless</a></p>

<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://owentyme.us/blog/shame-on-me-i-guess-part-iii.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/blog/./shame-on-me-i-guess-part-iii.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Owen Tyme</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 15:42:03 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
New Release: Demon for President!
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>I'm delighted to announce the release of a new book!  The third volume of <a href="../books.html#ashen-blades">Ashen Blades</a>, <em>Demon for President!</em> is now available as an Ebook!</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><span class="book-cover">
<a href="https://books2read.com/DemonForPresident"><img src="../images/Cover-DemonForPresident.jpg" alt="" title="" /></a> <br />
<a href="https://books2read.com/DemonForPresident"><button class="buy" style="display: inline-block; width: 100%; max-width: 200px;">Buy This Book</button></a>
</span>
The Hunter's demonic arch-nemesis, Vogerath, returns to Earth once more, but this time, he's running for President of the United States, on the 2024 ballot! Worse yet, the demon’s unique power to be in multiple places at once allows him to convincingly pretend to be identical twins, running as both a Republican and Democrat!</p>

<p>The other candidates all drop out of the race under mysterious circumstances and with his best competition being himself, he's practically assured a win!</p>

<p>Soon, the American people are lapping up the snake-in-a-suit’s every word as if it were ambrosia, calling out his name at every turn, magically charmed to believe he’s the best thing since sliced bread, despite the checkered, criminal history of his “family.”</p>

<p>Hard pressed to get rid of him, the half-demon Hunter and her allies kill him repeatedly, but he pops back up like a bad weed, making all of his appointments on time, photogenically kissing babies, cutting the ribbons of stores and donating laundered blood-money to charitable causes.</p>

<p>Will the hunter manage to end the demon's presidential campaign before election day? If she doesn’t, the USA may just get a Demon for President! Buy this book today and find out for yourself!</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="../books/ashen-blades/demon-for-president.html">There's also a promotional page for this book, which includes links to political pins you can buy.</a></p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_ashen-blades.html'>ashen-blades</a>, <a href='tag_novel.html'>novel</a>, <a href='tag_publishing.html'>publishing</a></p>

<!-- text end -->
]]></description><link>https://owentyme.us/blog/new-release-demon-for-president.html</link>
<guid>https://owentyme.us/blog/./new-release-demon-for-president.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Owen Tyme</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 08:05:12 -0500</pubDate></item>
</channel></rss>
